I'm about to take you from a complete
beginner to a pro AI builder with
Codeex. And you don't have to have a
technical background at all. My name is
Nate. I have no technical background.
And I started using AI about two years
ago. And in that time, I had an AI
consultancy that we scaled to over
$100,000 a month. And then I exited that
business. And now across my different
business units, we generate an average
of over $400,000 per month because we
all use AI so well. And none of us are
actually like coders or anything like
that. So in this course, I'm going to
show you guys how to install Codex. I'm
going to talk about the core concepts.
I'm going to talk about how you turn it
into your AI operating system and your
second brain. We're going to go over
things like skills. We're going to build
some together. We're going to go over
how you create deliverables that are
branded and feel like it's coming from
you and feel like it's coming from your
company. We'll go over images. We'll go
over design websites using the browser
using Codex to edit videos, using codeex
to build automations. We'll even address
the whole codeex versus cloud code
debate. And by the end, not only will
you be a pro AI builder, but you'll also
know exactly how you could go off and
sell this kind of stuff to clients. So,
there are going to be timestamps down
below. Feel free to skip around to what
interests you. Save this video so you
can come back to it for later. And now,
let's not waste any time and just get
straight into this one. All right, so
we're going to go ahead and get started
with installation. You're going to open
up Google and you're going to type in
cloud code. Wait a minute. That was so 3
months ago. No, I'm just kidding. But it
is funny how Chad GBT also pops up right
here. So, you're going to type in Chadbt
or Codeex. I'll show you what that looks
like. I will just type in codeex
install. And then you see right here,
ChadBt Codeex because Codex is a product
of OpenAI and Chad GBT. So, this is what
it looks like. What you're going to want
to do is just download this for your
operating system. So right here I would
click on download for Windows and then I
would go through the installer to get
the codeex desktop app. Now this
actually will be called the chatbt
desktop app but we're going to be using
codec. Now if you do use VS code already
or you use cursor or something like that
and you'd rather run codec through the
IDE extension or through the CLI then
you certainly can do that. But I love
the desktop app. I think that they're
bringing it in really really nicely with
their browser use and their sites and
routines and everything like that. And
the rest of this course we're going to
be using the Codeex desktop app. So, if
you want it to all look the same, then
just go ahead and download the app real
quick. Now, once you're inside here,
it's going to look like this. You're
going to have two different tabs up top
right away. You'll see chat and work,
but then on the lefth hand side, you
will switch over here from chatbt, which
is chat and work to codeex. And if you
do have a chatbt subscription already,
like you're paying 20 bucks a month or
100 or 200, that's the same exact
subscription. So, you won't have to make
a new account, but if you are currently
on a completely free account for OpenAI
or for Chatbt, then I would at least get
on the $20 a month plan right now. And
if you start to blow through your usage,
then just go ahead and upgrade. Because
the way that this works is you can see
in the bottom left, you can see that I
have 94% left and I'm currently on the
$200 a month plan for Codex. And so if I
use this up within the week, then I
would just basically have to wait till
it resets. Or I could pay per usage API
billing, which is just a little bit more
expensive than being on the
subscription. The subscription of Codeex
actually gets you about $14,000 of
inference if you use the entire
subscription. So, it's it's really
really cheap for being on the
subscription, paying $200 a month, and
I'm getting about $14,000 of usage out
of it. And I know that 200 bucks a month
or 100 bucks a month may seem expensive
relative to subscriptions, but we're not
paying for Netflix here. We're not
paying for entertainment. We're paying
for productivity. We're essentially
treating this as the cheapest hire you
will ever make. $200 a month for the
output that multiple hires would give
you if you start to use it right, which
is why you're investing time in this
course right here. Anyways, before we
get into this, I wanted to address one
question, which is okay, why would I use
codeex over something like work? Because
work is kind of marketed as like for
knowledge work for nontechnical people,
blah blah blah. I think it's good that
they're doing that, but ultimately it's
one of those things where codecs can do
everything that work can do and it can
do more. So, why would you not just
invest the time learning codecs because
it's basically the same, but then one
day you might need some of the extended
functionality that Codeex has and you
can just do it right there because
you've already learned Codex. I'm not
technical at all. I don't know how to
write code, but I've been able to do
some very, very incredible things with
codecs and with cloud code and tools
like that, all with my natural language.
And this entire course, you're going to
see it's literally just natural
language. There's just a few things that
you need to understand in order to get
the most out of it. So, if you're just
starting or if you've been using work
for a while, just trust me, go ahead and
switch over to Codeex. You're going to
thank yourself one day. And trust me,
it's not anything more difficult or
intimidating at all compared to work.
You're just getting more power. Awesome.
So, now that that's out of the way,
there's a lot of things that we're going
to be looking at in this app. And I
don't want to just run you through in a
really boring way and click on every
single thing and explain what it means.
I'm going to basically be doing that
throughout this entire course as we get
familiar with everything. So the first
thing that I actually want to do is kind
of start with like a 30,000 foot view of
everything that's possible in Codeex and
how simple it all is when we really
bring it together. So we're going to
start with me explaining to you all of
the core concepts that you actually need
to know in order to use Codex and in
order to understand what it can do. And
I'm going to explain the stuff extremely
simply with some examples. So let's hop
into this next segment. Today I'm going
over the 18 core Codeex concepts that
you actually need to know in order to
start using it right away and getting
value from it. It doesn't matter if
you're not technical at all or you've
never used Codex before. By the end of
this video you'll understand exactly how
this thing actually works so that you
can start using it right away. So let's
not waste any time and just get straight
into this one. All right, so I've split
these 18 core concepts into four
different parts and they get cooler as
we continue to go on. So part one we're
going to start off here is foundations.
So we're going to kick off with concept
number one which is projects. Now, a lot
of you guys, I'm assuming, have used
chat GBT or cloud in the web before
where you can talk to an LLM and it can,
you know, give you an answer. But the
problem you face is that every time
you're talking to it or you start a new
chat, you have to kind of familiarize it
with you and your business and what
you're working on that week or that
quarter. So, with projects, you can
basically keep everything organized into
one project so that as you keep working
inside of it, it only gets smarter about
knowing who you are. So, right here on
the lefth hand side, you can see that
I've got a few projects going on. I've
got Herk 2, I've got Hyperframes, I've
got Trading Challenge, I've got AIS
demo, and I typically am always just
working inside of my Herk 2 project. My
Herk 2 project is basically what I call
my AI operating system. And what a
project is is actually very simple. It
is just a collection of folders and
files. So right here, this is inside of
my file explorer on my computer and it's
called Herk 2. And this is exactly the
project that I have open in Codeex. When
I say right here, I'm inside of Codex,
right? This is the file path that I'm
working in, which is if I open this up,
my Herk 2 project. So what that means is
this project has rules about me. It has,
you know, credentials. It has all my
projects. It has all my YouTube videos.
This thing has so much knowledge about
me. So now when I come into the chat and
I say, "Hey, can you just give me a
rundown of what we've been working on
this past month?" This thing basically
gets familiarized with my project. And
then it looks at everything that we've
been working on together. It even looks
through all of my previous chats that
I've had with Codeex. So here you can
see that it looked back from the past
month and it said, "Here's what we've
worked on. We've been improving your
Herk 2 and your AISOs. We've been
working on YouTube content and strategy,
AI model testing and demos, apps and
product experiments, websites, branding,
business operations. So, this is no
longer just an AI chatbot. This is now a
co-founder. This is a personal
assistant. Which brings us on really
nicely into concept number two, which is
something called an agents.md.
And don't let that MD intimidate you
here. If I go over to the right hand
side and I open up my files, you'll
notice if I scroll down, I have
something right here called an
agents.mmd. And when I open this up,
it's literally just a markdown file.
That's what the MD means. And it's just
rules. Like this is a very simple thing
that you all can read and it's not
technical at all. So this is basically
like the rules for your project. So you
remember inside of my Herk 2 project, I
have this agent on MD. Well, if I was
inside of my hyperframes editor project,
there would be a different agents.md. So
this thing basically just sets the
ground rules for the project that you're
working in. So right here you can see
that this one says, "Hey, you are Nate
Herk's AI operating system. Your job is
to help him spend less time on
operations so he can focus on making
YouTube videos." And then I give it
things like core operating rules for how
to work with me. I give it some stuff
about how to be safe on my desktop. And
then the real bulk of my agent MD is
what I call routing. So this is a
routing map. It basically means Okay, so
yeah, Nate's project is huge. There are
hundreds, probably thousands of files
and folders inside of this project. So
let me just explain to you how this
actually works. If you need business
stuff, you go to the wiki. If you need
corporate structure, you go to the
corporate structure section inside the
wiki. If you need his voice, you go
here. If you need course knowledge, you
go here. If you want active projects,
you go here. So everything that I'm
doing, we're routing it back somewhere
so that my agents.mmd file tells this
project where everything is so that
every time I open up a new chat, like I
said, I don't have to reexlain things.
And basically the way that this works,
if we picture this being a chat thread,
you know, you come over here and you
say, "Hey, you say, "Hey, Codex, I need
you to help me do this." And before
Codex actually even like reads this
message, what it does is it first reads
the agents.mmd. So I'm just going to put
a here and that stands for agents.mmd.
But codeex will basically read this and
then it will read your message and then
it will respond with something like, you
know, hey, how can I help you today? So
the kind of stuff that you want to put
inside your agents.mmd is the type of
stuff that you want codeex to know about
you every single time you're talking to
it in that project. And now moving on to
concept number three, we have something
called the agent loop. So you'll hear
about something like codecs or claude
code or Hermes agent. These are all
called agent harnesses. And these
harnesses have their own agent loops.
And real quick, if you're wondering
about codecs versus like work chatbt
work, I always use codecs. The majority
of my work is not building products or
building software, but I only use codecs
because it's just the most powerful. And
once you get through this video, you'll
realize how easy it is to use. But
anyways, the reason why this is called a
harness is because they have this thing
called the agentic loop, which at the
highest level basically just means when
you ask the agent a question, it has a
bunch of tools at its disposal and it
basically thinks and it reasons and it
uses tools and then it responds to you
and then it thinks and then it reasons
and it takes action. It uses tools,
responds to you and that's basically the
agent loop. And what's really awesome
about that is you can see it in action.
So right here you can see that this said
worked for 25 seconds. And if I open
this up, we can basically see what it
did, right? Right? So like it hid this
response and it gave us our output, but
it had a reasoning loop inside. It first
said, "Okay, I'll check our recent tasks
and project nodes, then I'll pull
together the main themes from the past
month." And when it did that, it ran all
these commands. It ran this, which you
don't have to know what this means, but
basically what this did is it looked
inside something right here called a
memory.md. So very similar to the
agents.md, but this is about memories
rather than just like rules. It then
looked at other chats. And so we can
basically watch it do things. So, to
show you guys a real example of this,
hey, could you just check my most recent
YouTube video that I uploaded and give
me three comments that you thought were
funny from that video.
Now, as I shoot this off, what I want
you guys to pay attention to is what
we're watching. So, first it said
thinking. Now, it says, "I'll find your
latest upload, read through the
comments, and pick three that made me
laugh." And now we can see what it's
doing. So, it's looking through the
memory. It's looking at these things.
It's running these commands. And these
commands are basically right here. It's
reading, you know, files to get
established and to get oriented with
what it needs to do. And so, you can
actually learn a lot about how codeex
works and how to best work with it by
when you ask it a question, you just
kind of watch what it does. So, you can
see what it had to do was it had to run
a command in order to actually go talk
to YouTube, look at the data, and pull
it back. And now we can see three
comments. We have this one, never seen
anyone so excited to lose money. Trading
with AI is very easy. I just prompt
Claude only take profitable trades. And
if I want to lose money, I can do it
myself faster and better. And what
you'll notice is how quick that all
happened. Now, I do have my Astra on
fast mode, but I will talk about that
later because that is a core concept
that's coming up. By the way, guys, I've
got this completely free SOP for you
about getting your first Am. It's going
to go over the exact steps that has been
proven for hundreds of our AIS Plus
members to get their first paid gigs. It
goes over the one sentence service pitch
that can get you started today. Why your
first client should cost you money. The
five-minute video that answers, can this
person actually deliver before you've
actually received any money, what to do
when you have zero case studies. There's
so many good things in here that are
going to help you out. Even if you
already do have clients, I would
recommend grabbing this because like I
said, it's yours completely free. So, if
you want to grab this, there's a link
for it down in the description. Let's
get back to the video. All right, and
moving on to the last concept of part
one. It's a slash goal. And this is
honestly one of my favorite things about
AI ever. It's the ability to do
something called a slashgoal. And right
here you can see that that says set a
goal to keep pursuing. Now AI agents are
super goal oriented which is super cool.
So let's say you have Mr. AI agent right
here. And you basically say hey here is
your goal. You know this is what you
need to do and you give it this
objective goal. What happens is it will
basically just keep working and keep
working and keep working until it
actually hits that goal. And it's cool
because even if you kind of like give
them a roadblock, they are going to be
so goal-oriented that they're going to
keep retrying different things and
they're going to just basically keep
going until they're able to succeed and
hit that goal for you. Now, obviously
the more objective a goal, the easier it
is to prove that. So, if you say, "Hey,
can you, you know, work on this until
you've pulled in 257 sources and then
write the report, that's an objective
goal, right? 257 sources and written
report." But you can also set goals that
are a little bit more emotional. Like
your goal could maybe be more like, you
know, until you're fully satisfied or
until you've, you know, verified this
over and over and you feel good about
it. And in that case, you're still going
to, you know, get there and it will
still decide when it's done. But as you
get more objective with your goal, the
goal prompts are just more effective.
But let me show you one goal that I
actually did that you guys have already
been witnessing in this specific example
is I went to my Hyperframes project. And
hyperframes basically lets your coding
agents build HTML and then render it as
video. So essentially it creates video.
But what I did here is I shot it off
a/goal prompt. You can see this one says
sent as goal. So basically what I did is
I said I need you to help me create some
motion graphics for a YouTube video. So
all the motion graphics you've seen so
far were from this exact prompt right
here. I'm going over 18 different Codex
concepts. I want, you know, an intro. I
want transition cards. I want all this.
So I basically defined that I wanted one
intro scene and that I wanted 18 cards.
And then you can see that it said I
finished and I visually checked. meaning
it actually took screenshots to make
sure everything looked good before it
decided to be done. And now we have all
these animations. But what's cool about
the goal prompts is that models nowadays
are getting so good, the AI models are
getting so good that it's actually
better to give them a goal and then step
out of their way. If you really just try
to like micromanage them, you're kind of
just like muzzling their capabilities.
So if the situation isn't super super
risky, give them a goal and you can get
out of the way. Now, there's one quick
thing that I felt the need to address,
which is basically the question, "But
Nate, what if we've been using cloud
code for a long time?" Well, I'm really
glad that you asked. It's actually
really simple. Really, the main
difference is the agents.mmd, thecodex,
and the aagents. Because in cloud code,
you basically have like your cloud. MD,
and you have your cloud. So, when I
first started switching over from claude
code to codex, all I did was I said,
"Hey, codeex, take a look at this herku
project. I've been building this up
using cloud code for the past couple
months. I need you to help me get this
codeex ready." And basically what that
means is I made a copy of my cloud.mmd
and called it agents.mmd. So I have two
of those now. One one aent.mmd one
claude but they're basically the same
file. And then I made a copy of all my
cloud skills and put them in the agents
folder and I made a copy of all of my
like claude settings files and I put
them in my agents. And the cool thing is
you don't have to do any of that
manually. You literally just say hey
codeex look at the documentation analyze
my project and make this codeex
accessible. Make it codeex ready. So
anyways, if you were feeling a little
bit of doubt about all that kind of
stuff, that's the way I did it. And now
you have a bunch of local files and
folders that you can use on any agent
harness whenever. It's very flexible.
It's very tool agnostic, and that's what
you want to be building at the end of
the day. So anyways, had to address that
real quick. Let's get back to the video.
All right, awesome. So let's move on to
part two of these core concepts, which
is environments. So the first piece of
environments is number five, which is
local versus cloud. So there's a couple
things to talk about here. The first
thing is if someone says, "Oh, is this
running locally or are these local
files?" All that means is does that
exist only on the machine that you're
currently using? Whether you're on a
MacBook right now or you're on a desktop
PC like I am right now. When you say
local, it just means it's only
accessible by you. So right here, if I
open up my files, these are basically
local files. Now, they're syncing with
one drive when I want them to. So that
would kind of push them into the cloud,
but otherwise it's completely local. So
like if you're working on a word doc on
your computer and you forgot to save it
and then email it to yourself on so you
could work on it on a different laptop
that was a problem because it was
locally on that other machine. But
something like Google Drive is always in
the cloud obviously. But this also goes
beyond just files. This goes to like
things that are produced. So right here
you can see that it actually created me
this little site for all these motion
graphics. So if I open up this site you
can see that I can view all of these
videos. I can click into the different
ones and it threw this together for me
really nice and it served this to me on
a local host. So right here you can see
that this URL is 127.0.0.1
and the port of this local host is 8008.
Now realistically that's not super
important. You don't really need to
understand what exactly this means. But
this is just a local host. But this is a
little confusing because it looks like
this is a web address that if I, you
know, emailed to you, you could open
this up and have the site. But what
would happen is this would show on your
screen or it would show on your computer
as nothing actually lives here. So like
if I copied this and I pasted this into
a new browser but I changed the number
to 7. I don't think I have anything
running on port 8087
on my local machine even though you
might. So nothing actually loads up. And
it's quite funny. I remember seeing
these these tweets where I think it was
a joke but it was like uh someone was
pretending they're a beginner and they
were like wow cloud code and codeex it's
so cool. Look what I built in one day.
and then they, you know, attached a
bunch of local host addresses and
obviously no one else could open that up
because they're not on that local
device. So anyways, that is the
difference between local and cloud. Now
the other piece here is that when you're
spinning up these new chats, you can
kind of have these be either local,
meaning right here, you know, I'm
working in my local files and folders.
And that's great because codeex can
actually like edit these files, right?
It can delete things, it can make new
ones, it can edit them, it can move them
around, it can go to my downloads, it
can go to my desktop, it can do anything
on my computer really. or you could
actually have these work in the cloud.
And what you'll notice here is when you
choose cloud, you no longer have the
ability down here to actually choose the
model you were using and the permissions
because this sets up sort of like a
cloud sandbox environment. Now, I'll be
honest, I hardly ever do this because
when I'm working locally, as long as I
keep my machine on, as long as I keep my
PC on, it feels pretty cloud-like. And
here's what I mean by that. Right here,
you can see that I'm mirroring my phone
and I'm in the Chad GBT app. And if I go
over here and I click on this right here
which says remote, this lets me see all
of my actual codeex chats that are right
here. So if I go to Herk 2 and I go to
summarize past month, this is exactly
what we were just looking at right here.
You can see this is literally the same
conversation. It has those three chats
and I could come in here and I could say
hi and this gets sent in my actual
codeex right here on my laptop or sorry
on my desktop as well as my phone. So,
as long as my machine's on, even though
this is running locally and I'm out on a
walk, I'm out at dinner. I could even be
in a different state and I could control
my desktop from my phone right here. So,
let's say for some reason I left a file
locally on my computer, I could just
say, "Hey, can you email that file to
me?" And then I could use it on my
laptop. So, anyways, just wanted to show
off that remote capability. And that's
going to bring us into concept number
six, which is work trees. Now, honestly,
this is something where if you're not
really building software or, you know,
production apps, this isn't going to
matter to you too much. Like I don't
hardly ever use work trees, but it is
good to know about since you will see
these in the interface. So right here
you can see that if I was to go to um
the local setting, it says that you can
work in a new local work tree which says
create a copy of Herk 2 to work in
parallel. So basically because I'm
working in Herk 2, if I was going to do
something like risky or if I wanted to
try and experiment with something or for
example, if I was building software and
I wanted to try to change the way that
the onboarding flow worked, but I wanted
to like not interrupt the main branch,
especially if other people on my team
are working on that main branch, I could
use a work tree to basically create a
copy and I could test in there. And then
what you can do later is you can merge
it back into the main. So it's basically
just a duplicate that lets you test. But
like I said, there's hardly any times
for knowledge work that I ever use work
trees. And if I ever am building
software and stuff, a lot of times Codex
will say, "Hey, by the way, you might
want to use this. You might want to do
this in a new work tree." So, I wanted
to call it out because it's important
because you might see things like this
master branch and you might see other
work trees that might have been spun up
automatically. But I will say it's not
something that I'm actively thinking
about or think that you need to be
actively thinking about in order to get
the most out of codeex. So, wanted to
bring that up. But let's move on to
number seven, which is codeex. Now, this
is really interesting. We talked about
how when you're inside of your project,
you have things like an agent.mmd. Now,
if I go to my files, there's also
something in here called a codeex. So,
if I open this up, what you'll see in
here is I have some agents and I have
some workflows, but I also have a
config. ML file, which is basically like
some local settings. And there are
basically going to be two different
places where a codeex file lives. And
that's either going to be inside of your
project. So like in this example, this
is my codeex inside of my Herk 2. But
there's also going to be one which is
user or global, which means this lives
under your actual user. And these are
settings that hold things like memories
and sessions and automations. These are
things that will apply to your global
codec. So whenever you're in Codex,
regardless of what your project you're
actually in, the docex will have
personal settings and app data and stuff
like that. Now once again, I think this
is something it's important to
understand where that lives and what it
does. But this isn't a folder that I'm
actively thinking about and actively
having to like maintain. But I did want
to call that out because sometimes if
you need to have a certain setting
applied or something like that, that is
where it lives. Now, the cool thing
about this is if you're ever confused,
you say, "Hey Codeex, what did you do
there?" or "Do we need to add this to my
codeex or do we need to move this to a
different folder?" You can just ask it
questions because it can search through
its own documentation and understand how
to do things like correctly. But I do
think that understanding the difference
between project scope things and user
scope things that's definitely important
especially as we get into the agents
which is going to come up later. And
that is a great segue into part three of
the core concepts which is control and
customization. So number eight here is
about different AI models. So when you
are starting a new chat you can choose
the model you want to use. You can also
change the model in between messages.
So, I could shoot off a message on Astra
and then I could, you know, change this
to something else and then I could shoot
off another message and I can keep
changing if I want. Now, if you're
watching this video way later, maybe the
model names look different, but
essentially the theory is the same. You
have different models to choose from and
they all have different prices and
strengths. So, like right now, GBD6
Astra is just the absolute strongest,
but it's going to cost the most. It's
going to eat the most of your weekly
limit. Right here, you can see that I'm
at 100% because it just got reset. But
as you chat with Astro, it will drain
your weekly usage faster than you know
5.6 Soul would, which would drain your
usage limit faster than 5.6 Tarot would.
Now, right here, I just want you to look
at the API pricing so I can explain to
you how these models are actually
billing you. So, they build by tokens,
and they usually build by 1 million
tokens. Meaning, on Astra, for every 1
million input tokens, it will cost you
$10. And for every 1 million output
tokens, it will cost you 50 bucks. And
here you can see the different pricing
for these different models. And you can
see how it gets cheaper as you go down.
Now, this is API pricing, which means if
you were building an automation that was
programmatically using these models,
that's how much it would cost you. But
this usage inside of Codex, that's not
programmatic. This is usage limit or
subscription limit. So, when you pay 20
or 100 or 200 bucks a month for Codeex,
this is what you're actually your usage
limit is eating up is that subscription.
And you're getting way more inference.
Like, this is a $200 a month
subscription. And if I use all of my
weekly usage every single week, I'm
getting about $14,000 worth of inference
every month and I'm only paying 200
bucks for that. So the subscriptions are
much cheaper than if you were using the
API pricing. But if you ever do go over
your weekly limit, you'd have to buy
extra codeex credits. I don't exactly
know why they price it like this, but
you know, you can see they just give you
codeex credits instead. So let's say I
went over my weekly limit. I could go
here and I could click on buy credits.
This would bring up this screen which
lets you buy credits by like the
thousands or something like that. And
that is what I wanted to show you guys.
So like 2500 credits, 5,000 credits,
25,000 credits. And this is how it would
charge you based on those tokens. Now,
if you've never heard of tokens before,
I know that might be a little confusing.
Think about it as roughly four
characters or roughly 3/4s of a word.
And there's an OpenAI tokenizer right
here where if I paste in some text, it
will show you how many tokens this would
be. So this paragraph, for example, was
about 240 characters or sorry 274
characters and about 56 tokens. And it's
interesting because sometimes
punctuation is a token, right? Like this
period is a token, this comma is a
token, this word's a token, um this
word's a token. And this is basically
just kind of breaking down what it might
look like for these tokens. But anyways,
you can see this was 56. And what else
you might notice is that I earlier said
input tokens or output tokens. Input
tokens are whatever you're feeding in.
So your prompts or if it's reading like
a PDF or a word doc those are input
because they're going into the model and
output tokens are anything that it
outputs. So even its reasoning here is
output tokens. This entire thread is
output tokens and that's why the output
tokens are more expensive. Okay. So
let's move on to number nine which is
about effort. So within each model not
only do you choose the model but you can
also choose the effort level. So right
here I can move Astro down to medium or
I can move it down to low or I can move
it up to extra high or if I go like
ultra I have to allow full access
because that can get you know pretty
autonomous. But anyways the point being
as you move up on these effort levels
you get more quality like you get more
intelligence but you also get more cost.
it's more expensive to run it at higher
effort levels. And that's why when you
see these benchmarks, when there are new
models released, you'll see the model,
like for example, Cloud Fable 5, you can
see this mark was on low and this one
was on medium and this one was on high.
So, it shows how one model can behave
differently and also cost a different
amount based on the effort level that it
was being used and tested at. Now, it
actually is pretty nice to play with
these because sometimes Astra High is
just so much more powerful than what you
need to do. Like if you were using GBD6
Astra High to help you write an email,
that's overkill and you're paying way
more than you should realistically to
write an email. I could probably come
down here and use 56 Terra and be just
fine with that and it's a lot cheaper.
So definitely try to play with the model
and play with the effort based on your
task. But a lot of times if you're just
doing a lot of knowledge work, I would
just chuck it on sole and I'd maybe just
go to medium and just call it a day
there. Now the other thing about effort
is you can do something called fast
mode. This obviously makes the model
respond quicker and do things quicker.
And it it's 1.5 speed, but it costs you
more usage, so it will eat your weekly
subscription faster as well. All right,
and moving on to number 10, we have
permissions. Basically, right down here,
you can see that this is orange and it
says full access. This is basically
Codeex's yolo mode, which means that
it's not going to stop and ask you a
bunch of permissions and questions. Can
I do this? Can I do this? If you go on
ask for approval, it's going to always
ask to edit external files and always
ask to use the internet. So that's if
you want to sit here and really sort of
like manage it and you're wanting to
make sure everything's safe, you know,
maybe start off like this so you can
just understand, oh, okay, it's asking
me if it can run this command or it's
asking me if it can open up my browser
and then you just get familiar with what
it looks like for Codex to actually run
that agentic loop. You could also go on
approveof for me. So it's only going to
ask you if actions are detected as
unsafe, like maybe deletes or maybe
certain sorts of like API calls or
things like that. So that's how these
permissions work. And if you really want
to get granular about, oh, I want to
like make sure these certain actions
never happen, you can ask Codex about
that and it can work things into those
config files like we talked about
earlier with the codeex that it can
certainly like block things out. But now
let's move on to number 11, which I
think is my favorite one, which is
skills. Skills are so so important.
They're basically reusable workflows.
They're recipes that let you do
something once and then teach Codex how
to do it the same way every single time.
So now you can just run all these
skills. So like I said, a skill is
basically just a recipe. So, let's say
you come in here and you make, you know,
a chocolate chip pancake and you
followed a recipe to make that pancake.
You would basically say, "Okay, if I
ever want to make chocolate chip
pancakes again, I'm going to use this
recipe because I know that I'm going to
get a good result." But let's say that
you burnt these pancakes and you said,
"Okay, well, what I need to do is make a
quick update in this recipe to say, hey,
you know, cook it up 30 seconds less on
each side." And the next time you run
the skill, you basically see, okay, are
these better? Are these good? Do I need
to make any more feedback in here? Or
now, is this skill just the way I like
it? And then your agents are able to use
these skills. So here's an example where
I basically gave it a YouTube video. So
you can see that this is literally just
a local file path of a YouTube video.
And I said that I needed a video
description, timestamps, and a LinkedIn
post. It went ahead and it ran its
agentic loop and it gave me a
description, timestamps, and a LinkedIn
post. And then I said, "Okay, now I need
you to turn this into an X article." And
put the draft into my X as a draft. And
it knew exactly how to do this with a
thumbnail, with a title. It also put
screenshots from my actual video and it
sprinkled them throughout my whole X
article. And this is because it used a
bunch of skills to be able to know how
to do this. So right here, if I ask it,
what skills did you use? It used my
YouTube description skill, my timestamp
skill, my LinkedIn post skill, my X
article skill, my X article from video
skill, my format X article skill. It
used all of these skills because I've
taught it how to do something good once.
And then every time I run these skills,
I just give feedback. Hey, that was
good. You know, I liked this, but I
didn't like this. Update the skill. And
now what's cool is you can just invoke
these either with natural language. It
will be smart enough to do it with
natural language, or you can do it as a
slash command. So, I have one in here
that I can call like the audit. And you
can see this will run my audit or I have
one in here called the 3D brain. And
this runs the 3D brain. Man, I think I
planned this out so good. This is going
to bring us on to number 12, which is
agents. So, we talked about codeex. And
agents is basically the exact same. It
just holds different things. So, right
here, you can see that the agents holds
your skills. And these once again can
either be project level skills or they
can be user scope skills. So, they can
be global skills. So, if I come into
this chat right here, which is inside of
my um you know, Herk 2 project, and I go
to open up the files, and I go to my
agents folder, which is right here, we
have a folder called skills, and this is
a bunch of skills, as you can see. Now,
if I open up an actual skill, so for
example, let me go to my YouTube
description skill. This is an actual
skill.md. So, once again, MD just means
markdown file. So, what we have here is
some metadata, and this is what Codeex
will read to understand, okay, do I need
to invoke this skill or not? So, it has
the name and it has basically when to
use the skill. And then all the skill is
is just instructions. It's, hey, for
Nate's YouTube descriptions, keep them
short, two to four sentences, paragraph
form, no bullet points, no m dashes.
Here's the process. You read the video
outline. You identify the core topic.
You write a short paragraph. And that's
the skill. It's a very, very simple
prompt. But if I go to my ex article
one, they can also be way more in-depth.
So, this one is way longer. There's a
lot of other rules and a lot of other
criteria. There's way more steps.
There's way more things to do. And also
what's cool is skills can reference
other things. Skills can reference other
skills. They can reference other agents.
They can reference Python files or
context files. So in this example, this
skill references my voice guidelines
like my LinkedIn style guide as well as
my ex article style guide. But that is
where your skills live inside of the
agents folder. And then moving on to
number 13. Here we have plugins. And
this is where a lot of the magic
actually happens because you can super
easily come over here in the Codex
desktop app. You can go to plugins and
you can connect a bunch of things. You
can see all the stuff that I have
installed like Alpaca, Gmail, ClickUp,
Clay, Google Drive, GitHub, Canva, and
the list goes on and on. You can also
search for different plugins. So, let's
say you were really interested in
connecting something like, I don't know,
let's see, do they have a LinkedIn
plugin? They have a LinkedIn plugin
where we can find the right profession,
we can grow our business with ads. We
have all these other sorts of plugins,
too. So, if you want to try to connect
your different apps, just come in here
and see if you can connect them using
these plugins. Maybe they have
Composeio, they don't have Composeio,
and if they don't have a plugin here,
you can still connect it using Aenv
using an API key. But plugins are so
much easier because you can just
basically sign in once. They've got ones
for creativity, for developer tools, for
business and operations, for data
analytics, communication, and they're
basically always growing this plug-in
library. All right, so that now brings
us on to part four, which is tools and
scale. Okay, we've got five left here.
Number 14, we have the browser. Now,
this is definitely one of my favorite
things about Codeex. If I open up the
tab over here, we can open up a browser,
which is really cool because I can
basically just control this. So, like I
could go to school.com. And what you'll
notice is when I log into school.com
over here, I'm just going to zoom out a
little bit. You can see right here that
I'm already logged into my school
account. So, I could manage my different
communities, which also means that
Codeex can help me manage my communities
from here. Because when you save these
login inside of the Codeex browser, it
then saves them. So, if you say, "Hey,
could you go to that account and pull
the report for me?" or hey could you go
into school and could you make this post
for me it can do it through the browser
if there's not a plugin or if there's
not like an API or MCP server and the
browser use of codeex and specifically
with GBT6 Astra is the best that I've
ever used ever I'll play a clip right
here where I asked it to basically open
up Canva and paint me and draw me using
the tools in there and I gave it just a
picture of me and it was able to
replicate it in a way that I thought was
really really good. So, silly example,
but it definitely demonstrates the
vision and the browser use capability of
this agent. All right. So, number 15, we
have sites. So, if you go over here to
explore and you click on sites, this is
very, very cool because it basically
lets you put things out there onto the
cloud. Remember earlier we talked about
local versus cloud. Codex can build
something for you and it can be a local
host, but then you say, "Hey, can you
just put that on a site real quick so
that you could have your team log in or
so that you could share it with, you
know, other people and make it publicly
accessible." Like right here, you can
see this London and Paris one is
everyone whoever has this URL could go
ahead and open this up. Whereas this one
is just me. So it would literally have
to be logged into my account in order to
be able to open up this site. And what
else is amazing about that is you can
open up the analytics for this site. So
you can basically host things. You can
connect your own domain and this is
basically going to replace something
like a Versel or like a I don't know a
Squarespace, wherever you wanted to host
your sites normally. You can now just do
it right here from the Codex desktop app
which is pretty cool. You can also even
connect a database. So on the back end
if you had to store like user login data
or you know permissions or settings or
you know a database of customer records
whatever it is you could actually store
that here too and it's really cool. All
you need to do to actually use a site is
you just basically have to do either say
hey can you turn that into a site or you
could do slash site and then it will
basically know that you can you know
host a site or build a site. So great
touch here from codeex. All right so
number 16 we have sub aents. So, sub
agents are really cool because it lets
you delegate work out to a bunch of
different Codex agents. So, right here
in this main chat, you can see that I'm
talking to GBT6 Astra, which is a
really, really smart and intelligent,
but also expensive model. So, let's say
I wanted to do a bunch of research, but
I didn't want to waste Astra's brain on
that. Or let's say I wanted to do like a
bunch of different testing and just do a
lot of stuff at once. Astra here that
I'm talking to can delegate workout to
tons of sub aents. Hey, I need you to
search through X and search through
YouTube and also dig through my own
comments. So, just find, you know, what
are people talking about right now in
the AI space. Is there any big news or
drama? I don't want you to do this
research though. I want you to basically
just delegate a bunch of sub agents out
to do the work and I want all of these
sub agents to be using 5.6 Terra as the
model. So, shoot off those agents and
let me know what they find. So, this is
really cool because I can specify that I
want those sub agents, those little like
researchers and workers to use different
models. So right here it's using its
agentic loop and it's going to spin up
these agents. And whenever you see these
little colorful things, these are
different agents that it's spun up. So
right here, this one's called X. And
when I open up X, it is actually this
sub agent working right here. I can
watch this sub agent go through its
agentic loop and I can watch it like
pull in data and everything like that.
So this is the same thing as over here,
but this one is just a different model
and it's not the main session that
you're currently talking to. You can see
we have two others that started working.
We have this one called YouTube Pulse.
And once again, it's going through the
same exact agentic loop. We have this
one called X drama. We have this one
called audience comments. And we can
basically watch all of these work, but
we don't have to manage them because
once these agents are done, the main
session here will say, "Okay, cool. All
five are done. They reported back to me.
Here's what they found." And this is
really good for gathering different
perspectives or researching out a bunch
of things in parallel. And these
intelligent models are really, really
good at delegation. So sub agents are
definitely something that you need to be
using. So, while these sub agents are
fanned out and they're working, let's
move on to number 17, which is scheduled
tasks. Scheduled tasks are awesome
because this basically lets you have
your codeex working autonomously for
you. So, on the lefth hand side, if you
click on scheduled, you can basically
ask codecs to schedule things for you,
reminders, updates, or run full
sessions. Because all a scheduled task
basically is is it injects a prompt into
a codec session like this. So, it uses
your same local files, it uses your same
skills, it uses your model, it uses
everything. thing the agentic loop it
just does it automatically for you. So
in here I you see that I could create
one and I could set it up manually. I
could have it run locally or I have
could have it run on the cloud. I could
also choose what project to work in. So
Herk 2 or you know Hyperframes editor. I
can also choose what chat. So every one
of these routines could be a new chat or
it could be a new chat for this task or
it could be even in an existing thread
that we already have going. And then you
can basically choose when to schedule
it. So, it could be daily, it could be
hourly, it could be, you know, weekly,
or you could get it really, really
custom in here. And the cool thing is
you can describe everything in here
manually, or you could basically just
ask Codex to make one for you. So, for
example, I have these like seven or
eight different ones that are running
for um trading. They're literally
trading $10,000 of my real money. And I
have this set up as scheduled tasks so
that they can basically all work
together, talk to each other, check the
market, make trades, things like that.
And of course, you guessed it, these run
in a different project right here called
trading challenge. And they all run
inside of this challenge thread. You can
tell that this has scheduled tasks in it
because there's a little clock icon next
to that thread. And moving on to the
very last concept we have for today,
number 18, this is voice mode. Now,
everything that you've learned so far,
skills, sub aents, projects, agents, all
of this can be controlled by using your
voice to have a real conversation with
Codeex. With your voice, you can manage
different codec threads. You can
delegate different agents. You can run
skills. You can set up schedule tasks.
You can build sites. You can do anything
here with your voice. And all you have
to do is come down to the bottom left
and click on start new voice chat. So,
forgive me here as I'm awkwardly like
hunching down because my headphones
don't reach far enough. But watch this.
Hey, Codex. So, I need you to help me
out real quick inside of my Herk 2
project. Can you start a new thread to
make a thumbnail? I'm making this
YouTube video about 18 CEX concepts. So,
if you could make me a thumbnail for my
YouTube channel where you see me sitting
at a desk working on a laptop and I'm
pointing to the right and there's like
18 different little AI agents. Um, yeah,
just start start with that. And then
once you have finished that thumbnail,
could you send it to the thread that is
currently working inside of my her 2 as
well and it is doing research on YouTube
and X and um looking at my channel and
stuff like that. Could you just send
that thumbnail to that thread?
>> All right, let me check on that. Okay,
I've got your thumbnail brief queued up
with you with the laptop pointing toward
the 18s using your existing photos for
reference. And that found your research
thread. So, I'll send the finished
thumbnail there. Now, do you guys see
how this is all coming together? It
started a work tree chat. It was doing
the agentic loop. It also created a goal
down here. It literally created its own
goal because it knew that we had this,
you know, task for it and it started
working. And you know, the voice chat's
still going. So, I don't know what it's
going to think of this, but I just
wanted to call that out because all of
what we just talked about is all coming
together because even you can see over
here, it started making that actual
prompt. Like, it shot off this prompt
right here and it started off this new
thread. And now this is working in a
work tree and it's going to create that
thumbnail for us and then it's going to
send it over into this actual chat and
we'll see that actually happen. But as
you keep navigating, like you can go to
the web and you can go to, you know,
other things and you can keep this voice
working. So as you're just working on
your laptop, it'll show you what's going
on and you can keep talking to it. And
you can also do all this on your phone
as well because of the whole remote
thing. You can use voice mode when
you're on your phone, too. Okay, so that
finished up and you can see what happens
is it actually can send tasks or
messages to each other, right? So what
happened was this was the original
thread that it created to make the image
and it made this and then it sent it to
this thread and said, "Hey Nate wanted
me to send this to you. Here it is." So
with just your voice, I know that was a
very simple example, but you're able to
coordinate a bunch of different codec
threads, manage them, multitask while
you're on the go, while you're flipping
between different apps. Very cool. All
right, so now that you guys have learned
the core concepts of codecs, we're going
to start to actually get in there and
play around with some of this stuff. So,
what I want you guys to do here is think
about the way that we're actually going
to start using codecs. Don't think of it
as a tool that helps you build like AI
workflows. Think of it as your new
operating system. Basically, what I mean
by that is you should be reaching for
codeex whenever you want to do a new
task. And that's the whole mindset shift
behind becoming AI native, which is
actually the book I wrote right here. As
you can see, this book is all mindset
oriented. It's basically just about how
do you talk to AI? How do you use it?
And how do you change the default to,
oh, okay, I'm just going to open up
Google Chrome and open up this new tab
and just do the job. the old way, the
manual way that I'm used to. How do you
shift to, okay, I'm going to open up
codecs and I'm going to use this as my
operating system. I'm going to figure
out how can I build a skill for this?
How can I use the browser used to do
this? How can I turn everything that I'm
doing into faster processes because I've
built systems around it? And that
doesn't mean we're giving up a lot of
the judgment or the control. That still
sits with us, the human. It just means
that we're able to move faster and we're
able to do way more. And the way that
that truly happens is when you build
your AIOS and your second brain, meaning
you're not just opening up a new chat.
you know, a new chatbt tab every single
time you have to do something. You're
building a system where every single
time that you talk to it, it gets
smarter. Every single time that you
build a deliverable, it saves it and it
remembers it. You're essentially turning
AI from, you know, what we used to call
like a personal assistant or like an
executive assistant. Not anymore. We're
turning this into a co-founder. We're
turning this into like a business
partner that actually can work with you
and keep up with you and remind you of
things rather than like forgetting
things or hallucinating things. So,
we're going to jump into this next
section and I'm going to teach you guys
how to build your own AI operating
system. And just a quick heads up, guys,
throughout this course, I'm going to be
playing different clips and different
little segments that I might have
recorded at a different time of day or,
you know, last week or something. So, if
I look a little bit different in some of
these, that's why. But I have very
intentionally laid out this entire
course in the order that I think makes
the most sense to follow it. So,
hopefully that'll make sense. But yeah,
let's get into the next piece and start
building out your AIOS. GBT6 Astra is
the most powerful AI model I've ever
used. So, I turned it into my AI
operating system and my second brain.
And this is just a quick visual, but
right now what you're seeing is my
actual company. This is my second brain.
This is everything that I know and
everything about my business. And
because I have everything actually
stored and usable, that means so does
GPT6 Astra. So when I say AIOS, what I
mean by that is an AI operating system
where now I can basically do anything I
need to from right inside of this
interface with Codeex with GPT6 Astra
because now it doesn't feel like I'm
just talking to a chatbot. It feels like
I'm talking to a co-founder, someone
that actually knows everything that's
going on in my life and my business. So
today I'm going to show you guys how you
set up an AI operating system from
scratch, but if you already have one
going, how you can keep improving it.
And I'm going to give away a bunch of
free skills that help you set up exactly
this and help you set up other things
like auditing your AIOS, leveling it up,
and just setting up the structure.
Right? Now, what you'll notice here is
that this isn't just a random dump of
knowledge. Right here in blue, this is
my business wiki. So it's like AIS
coaching, our corporate structure, our
Ammation Society Plus. And when I click
in, we can see all of these things in
these different relationships. I can
also see how stale this is, so I might
need to update it. and it calls out all
these areas where like this number is
old. I need to update this. But it also
shows me all the different connections
where this specific node is linked into
every other area of my business. So like
I said, that was business wiki. I also
have meetings that I've added in here,
which takes up a big section. I've got
video knowledge. So every single YouTube
video I've made, it has all that
knowledge and it relates it back to
everything in my business and in my
meetings. Same thing with the clawed
memory right here as you can see. Same
thing with codeex memory. I've also got
a bunch of projects and then I have
skills and agents and this forms
together my herk brain and I've even
gone as far as to take this exact brain
and put it in its own OS dashboard where
I can basically have my calendar over
here. Today's a Sunday so I don't have
many meetings and this is fully
functional, fully synced with my
calendar. We've got these three stats,
YouTube subs, AIS, AIS plus and these
are fully synced. I can come in here and
manage my brain. I can search for
different things. I can look through
different things. I also have my
communication fully synced. So Slack,
ClickUp and email and these are
functional. I can respond to things from
here. I can also see different meetings
that I have coming up as well as past
meetings with the AI summaries already
generated. And then I can get community
pulse. So top YouTube comments, top AIS
plus posts, what people are stuck on, as
well as industry pulse from things like
YouTube and X. And all of this of course
was made with GBT6 Astra. But really the
idea of an AIO OS or an operating system
is my framework that I call the four
C's. So context, connections,
capabilities, and cadence. And the way
that I think about this is I think about
these first two things as the second
brain piece. So I think of this as your
second brain and then over here we have
the actual AIOS and this is the
capabilities and the cadence. So let me
real quick explain what I mean by that.
What's the actual difference? So the way
that you get this thing to actually feel
like it knows you is by giving it
context. So I mean things about you and
your background and your business and
your goals and your priorities and
things like that. I think of context as
the things that are in your life that
really don't change too much. So
quarterly goals or yearly goals or what
your business does, your avatar pain
points, things like that. and the
connections. I think of things as the
tools that you use every day because the
data in there is always relevant and
it's always changing every day. So, your
email, different data is always in
there. Your conversation, Slack,
ClickUp, your project management, your
financial information, giving your AIOS
the ability to know all the context, but
also reach for things just in time when
it needs it. That's how you build a
really, really powerful second brain
that helps you actually ask your AIOS
questions or say something and rather
than getting a vague or generic
response, it knows what to do. So, for
example, when I asked Codex to make me
this AIS sizzle reel, I didn't tell it
everything I wanted. I just said, "Hey,
make me a sizzle reel for AI Automation
Society." And it knew all this context,
and it also knew that it could go to my
school community and look things up in
order to make this. In fact, what you'll
notice is it actually went so far as to
go to the community, take pictures from
it, like take screenshots itself, and
add those in here because it knew that
this is what I was talking about. So, I
have these three little tests that I
like to run, which is basically if a
teammate messages you with a question
and you realize that your AIOS would
answer better and faster with the exact
sources, then that's a good sign that
your AIOS really is where it should be.
Another one is context switching
reduction. One thing that you should
challenge yourself to do after you've
gotten this set up is to try to force
yourself to do everything from here,
from this interface. rather than opening
up all those new tabs and doing it the
old way. Try doing it the new way of
using the AI as your operating system.
And then number three is the knowledge
leaves your head. So stop trying to
remember everything. You don't have to
rehearse what you decided last quarter
or what your customer said in that
meeting because you trust the retrieval
of asking your AIOS because it can find
it in your Slack threads. It can find it
in your email, find it in your meetings,
or it just knows it. Because if you
start to build new skills and
capabilities and you start to put
cadence into play, which means agents
that run autonomously and automations
and things like that, these things are
not nearly as valuable without the first
two C's because otherwise these skills
are very generic. And the automations
are just like I said, generic. So these
four things really come one after the
other, context, connections,
capabilities, and cadence. And they all
work together very beautifully. And
that's how we get our AI operating
system. So in order to get started or to
scale all this up and get all the
resources, I need you to go to my free
school community. The link for that is
down in the description. Like I said,
it's completely free. And you're going
to go to classroom. You're going to
click on all YouTube resources. And
you're going to grab the AISOS resource
pack. This thing is going to come with
five skills. It'll come with an onboard
skill to get you set up. It'll set up
your whole project structure, your files
and your folders. Then you'll have an
audit skill to do frequent checks on
your AOS. You'll have a link skill,
which helps you route to different files
when you need to. You'll have a level
up, which you can run after your audits
that tell you, hey, this is probably
some stuff you should do based on this
audit. And then you have the 3D brain
skill which helps you turn your
knowledge into this actual 3D brain like
you guys saw right over here. Now, yes,
it is these four things. And when you
start to run that resource pack, it'll
onboard you and ask you questions and it
will start to fill in this information
which is great. But then what comes next
is something that's super super
important and that is called the
agents.md.
And so if you've been using claude, this
is basically the claw. MD, but now this
is the one that Codeex is more familiar
with reading and it's the exact same
thing. So, if you are coming over from
Codeex, literally what I would do is I
would just copy your claw.md and then
just name it agents.mmd. It's the exact
same thing. And just to show you guys
what mine looks like, if I go into here
and I go to my files, you can see that
it's very simple. It's you are Nate
Herki operating system. Here's your job.
Agents.mmd and cloud.mmd contain the
same stuff. And then I basically give it
a few core operating rules like to be
concise and I use bullet points and
don't use m dashes and you know use the
Oxford comma. But then I go into a
routing map and that's the majority of
my agents.mmd. I think of it as you know
core rules but then I think of it as
routing meaning can my agent understand
where everything lives because if I open
up my Herk 2 project which is just like
we said a combination of folders and
files and that's all this is displaying
is folders and files and it's showing
the relationship between all of that but
the point I'm trying to make is that
this is a lot right there's a lot of
folders and files and I can go into my
projects and there's a lot more in here
and then I can go into things like you
know my YouTube videos in here and it's
even more but because all of this is
laid out in a way that to me is
intuitive That also means that my agents
can crawl it a little bit better. But
the more that I have information in here
like routing logic, like, hey, if you
need business advice or team stuff or
OTAAS, you look in the wiki. If you need
corporate structure or entities, you
look in this section of the wiki. If you
want to look at Nate's voice and style,
you look here. If you want to look at
course knowledge, you look here. If you
want to look X, go Y. If you want to
look A, go B. And you can see there's a
ton of different rules in here, but
what's important is that the agent knows
this every single time it loads up so
that when you ask for something, it
knows where to look. Because that's
essentially how the agents.mmd file
works. You know, you say, "Hi, codeex."
And before it even will read your
message, it reads this first. So, it
reads this and then it reads your
message and then it will respond with
like, "Hey, how can I help you today?"
You know, that's kind of what it will
say. But it always reads this context
first, which is why it's so important.
All right. So, if you're a complete
beginner, how do you actually get set up
with all this? Well, let me show you.
First thing you're going to want to do
is you're going to want to go to
somewhere on your computer. Let's just
say it's your desktop. And you're going
to create a new folder. And so for
example, this is where I am using my
Herk 2 project. But for now, I'm just
going to call this AISOS
demo. So you can call this whatever you
want. Now once that folder has been
created locally, which just means on
your computer, you're going to open that
up in Codeex. So at this point, if you
don't have the Codex desktop app,
download that. And then if you aren't on
a subscription, just get on
subscription. But now what we're going
to do is we need to open up this OS. So
what that means is you would come in
here and you would click on new project.
You would create a local project and
then you would give it a name and then
choose this folder. So this is once
again going to be AIS demo and I'm going
to open up that folder. If I go to my
desktop and I just have to find this
folder we just made right here. Select
that and then go ahead and click create
project. So this now means whenever we
are doing things in here, we're working
inside of this actual local folder which
if I open this up, there's nothing in
here right now. But you will see as we
start this whole onboarding, this folder
will fill up. So, what I'm going to do
is I'm going to go to the resource pack
and I'm just going to copy this actual
URL. And I will now paste that into the
chat and say, "Hey, I want you to
install this and just go ahead and run
the onboard so I can start giving you
some information and building my AIOS."
So, now that this is installed, it's
going to start onboarding you. And you
can see that it's going to say, "I will
save your answer as you go." So,
obviously, you guys should take some
time and give this some pretty specific
information, but I'm just going to blow
through this real quick. So, my name is
Nate and I run an AI education community
and we have a certification program and
we have live events and things like
that. And what's going to happen is it's
going to start creating folders and
files for you. If you click on this
button and you go to files, you can see
that it's already created a bunch of
stuff in here. None of this was in here.
If you guys remember, this was all
completely empty, but now it's starting
to set up the actual structure. But
really, the two most important things to
call out right now are the context
folder. This is where it's going to
start to create some markdown files of
business context and also the
agents.mmd. I remember I showed you guys
mine and this is going to start getting
built out over time with you guys right
in here. Then it asks you to paste some
of your recent writing so that it can
start to build some skills around how
you write. So what I'm going to do real
quick is just basically fly through
these seven questions and then you guys
do this as well and then come back. All
right. So now that I've done those seven
questions, if I open up a new thread, I
can actually say, "Hi, who am I?" And it
will check my profile first because now
it can actually look at all that and
understand that. So if I open up the
files once again, we can now see that if
I go to my context, we have one called
about business, we have one called about
me, and we have one called priorities.
So if I open this up, you can see that
this has information. If I open this one
up, this one has information, too. And
over time, these will continuously get
more filled with context. And this is
context, like I said earlier when I was
talking about these four C's, context
that we want to basically be more
evergreen, right? Information that's not
changing very often. Whereas these are
more the connections where you have
information that changes very often. And
that's when you're going to start
filling it up by looking at things like
this. You're going to start looking at
um what bookmarks do you have? What
desktop apps do you have? What apps do
you use the most on the weekly basis?
And I like to think about it as far as
like revenue, customers, calendar, coms,
tasks, meetings, and knowledge. And then
once you've taken some time to like list
them out here, just say, "Hey, Codeex, I
want to connect to school. How can I do
that? I want to connect to Stripe. I
want to connect to YouTube. how can I do
that? And it will tell you, oh, you need
to get this API key or you need to use
this MCP server or maybe you need to use
browser use. And it will help you figure
out the best way to connect to all these
tools. But what else you'll notice is
that it's creating the things that we
need in case you ever want to go over to
cloud code like acloud folder as well as
a cloud.mmd. So it's really helping you
make this your own AIOS, your own IP
where you're not locked into one
ecosystem. So anyways, I just wanted to
call that out. But the agents and the
cloudmd file are basically identical.
Right now we have like the operating
system, we have some skills, we have
where things live, but right now this is
pretty empty. So obviously we need to
get this filled up a little bit more.
You can also see that in the references
section we have a voice. So if I go to
my references and I go to the voice MD,
we can see that this is stuff about how
Nate talks based on the information that
I've given it so far. So anyways, now
you can see we're starting to get some
stuff filled up here. But now what
you'll do is once you have connected
some things, you're going to go ahead
and run the audit. So you can do /
audit. This will automatically be
installed because you use the resource
guide. And this basically checks the
AIOS. It looks at the four C's. It gives
you a score. And it will also look at
your agents MD or your cloud NMD and
make sure everything's synced up like I
said. And what else is cool about this
is this creates another folder in your
AIOS called audits. You can see there's
nothing here called audits. But what's
going to happen is it's going to give
you a report and then it's going to
store your audit. So every single time
you run this, let's say you want to run
it every Monday or every two weeks, it
will store your scores every time so
that you can see how you're actually
improving your system, you know, month
over month. So I know if you're new to
Codeex and everything, this might feel a
little bit intimidating, but it's really
not too bad. And the cool thing about
this is you can just ask questions if
you ever get confused. Hey, why'd you do
that? Or where should I put this? Or,
you know, how do you feel about all
this? You can treat this thing like your
best friend who's really smart, who's
also a mentor rather than just like a
chatbot. Okay, but you can now see that
this audit is done. And obviously, we
scored a 30 out of 100 because we
literally just built this and there's
not much in here. But it'll show you
across those four C's what needs
improvement. And you can keep working on
that stuff. And over here, you can see
that we have a new folder called audits.
We have this markdown file which shows
us that today, September 7th, you ran
this audit. And here was basically the
conclusion of that audit so that you can
improve on it. Now, what you can do from
there is you can go ahead and run
another skill which comes in the kit,
which is called a level up. So, this one
will basically look at this audit report
and then it will help suggest areas for
you to improve it. It'll help you think
about different connections and
different ways that you could, you know,
build in some more capability and build
in some more cadence so that this thing
keeps growing and keeps growing. So,
here you can see it said, I'd start with
turning team updates into one clear
action list. It targets your stated
bottleneck coordination, taking time
away from learning AI and making videos.
So, two candidates here, which are team
action list and certification
improvement backlog. So, I would then
think, okay, cool. So how do we actually
start driving towards this? You know,
what do you need to see? What
connections do we need to set up? And
then how do we build these automations?
And so you can just keep running this
loop of auditing, leveling up, building,
auditing, leveling up, building. And
this is the type of stuff that Astra is
so good at because it's so so smart. It
really feels like it's got some really
incredible general intelligence,
especially as you give it more and more
data because it's really good at
building automations. It can oneshot a
lot of this stuff and it will help you
build all these routines. So automating
some of these little tasks is no
problem. The real issue is getting
everything from your head into the
system because the more you give it, the
more context you give it, the better it
gets obviously. So yes, it can give you
these recommendations, but now what I
want you guys to think about is how you
can give it more data. So I do have this
other skill here called Grill Me. It was
inspired by Matt PCO's Grill Me and I
will actually put this in the AIS OS
kit. So if you install it based on this
video, you'll have this here. But I
didn't do it right now. So anyways, then
you could use the grill me and say, I
need you to use this grill me skill to
just, you know, find out as much as you
can about my current priorities in my
business. And what this does is it will
basically do similar to the onboard
where it asks you questions, but this is
a separate skill where it just
relentlessly grills you over and over.
And what's cool about this is you just
keep having it grill you on different
topics because every time you start one
of these interviews, it will create a
new file in your AISOs and it will store
all this interview. So every single time
that you come in here for 20 minutes, 30
minutes, and you just get interviewed by
AI, it's going to store all that. So
you're just building up your second
brain over time, and it's really, really
cool. As you can see, it said, I'm going
to save every answer in business
priorities capture. It created a new
folder right here. And now we have this
markdown file where as I start to answer
these questions, it's going to store
everything. So that's something that I
would recommend going through with
business priorities, your team, you
know, your goals, and just like a bunch
of different topics about your business
and about your life. Now, the next thing
you need to do, and it's how you
actually get something more like this
where you actually have like all of
these relationships forming between
these different things that you want to
put into your AISOs or into your second
brain. This gets really important
because the relationships is what makes
this actually connect to everything and
what makes it feel more holistic rather
than just like a data dump. So, the way
that you get to this point with all
these relationships is we're going to
use Carpathy's LLM wiki. This basically
just has AI crawl through data sources
and find those connections for you. So,
it's really, really cool. And guess
what? It's really easy to use because
all you have to do is you can either
copy this URL, which I'll put in the
description of this video. Or you could
just come in here and you could copy
this. Like you could literally just go
like this, copy it, and then come into
your actual AISOs. You can start a new
chat and then say, "Hey, based on what
you currently know about me, I want you
to build me a new LLM wiki, and I want
you to do so on all my business contacts
and everything using this Carpathy wiki
method." And then you can literally just
paste in that prompt, and boom, it's
going to crawl through everything. It's
going to create you a new wiki vault.
And you can obviously be more specific
like I have one vault for my YouTube
videos. I have one vault for my business
knowledge. I have one vault for my
meeting transcripts. And so I started to
separate them out over time. But just to
start, you could do, hey, this one's
just for business or whatever you need
to do. And it will help you find those
relationships. And then once you've done
a bunch of grillies, once you've built
out these L&M wikis, then you're going
to go in here and you're going to run
that 3D brain skill. And that is the one
that's going to take all your knowledge
and it's going to turn it into something
like this. And this obviously will
continue to sync and stay optimized and
continue to improve for you. And it will
probably build that out into something
called a local host. But what's really
cool is you could ask it to turn that
into a site. As you can see, Codex
basically lets you build things and
store it on their domain. So then after
you build it, you could have it be
accessible to different laptops or to
your phone or whatever you want. Or if
you wanted to keep it local, you can do
that as well. And if you also wanted to
connect your own custom domain, you can
do that, too. So really, the
possibilities here are endless. And it's
just about doing that loop, like I said,
of constantly scaling up your four C's
and doing that loop of the audit level
up, audit level up. Now, the last thing
I wanted to address was the whole idea
of GBD6 Astra driving everything, right?
Because Astra is an incredibly powerful
model, but I also wanted to say so is
5.6 Soul and so is 5.6 Terra. And for
the majority of this knowledge work that
you're doing here in your AOS, like
asking, oh, can you find this doc or can
you help me create this spreadsheet? A
lot of that using Astra is probably
overkill. Like Astra is one of the most
it is the most capable model that I've
ever played with. So what I would
recommend is build out some of the
stuff. You know, get familiar with how
this model works. But then when you
start to try to, you know, use different
skills and when you start to try to
connect to different things, I would
recommend trying with 5.6 Soul because
Astro is going to crawl through your
usage limit, which is the weekly limit.
It's going to eat at that more because
it's a more expensive model than 5.6
Soul is. And once you really start to
get comfortable here, you can play with
different things too, like the effort
level. You can make it go on lights,
which reduces some of the capability,
but it also makes it cheaper. And then
you could also go to 5.6 soul, and you
could play with the effort level over
here as well. There's a lot of cool
things to dig into once you really start
to connect a lot of stuff to your codeex
system. Once again, I just think it's
important to call out that all you're
building here is you're building files
and folders. And what's cool about that
is as you build out your files and
folders, it will grow into something
that's just amazing. So now I have my
herk 2 which like I said has everything
in here. And the cool thing is if I
wanted to build a Hermes agent I can
connect that to this. If I go back to
cloud code I connect it to this.
Whatever is the new tool, whatever is
the new AI model, I don't have to worry
about switching over. I don't have to
worry about being vendor locked because
I own all of this stuff right here and
every agent can crawl through it and use
it. And that's really what we're
building here. We're not just building a
codec skill or a codeex hub or a little
like 3D brain. We're building IP. We are
building a knowledge base that is going
to be the most valuable thing because
now we can work through it because
there's so much context and knowledge in
here. So I really want you guys to
seriously get in there and start doing a
bunch of grill me and just building up
your routing and your context. So
remember free school community linked in
the description. You'll find all the
resources that you need right in here.
So you've got the foundation set up.
Obviously like I mentioned this is never
a finished product. I've been building
my own AIOS for about 9 months now and
every day I make a change to it. I
always make improvements. I always clean
things up. And that will always just be
the case. You're always going to keep
improving that thing. But obviously, you
can build things along the way that help
you just become way more fast, way more
efficient, way more powerful. And those
are called skills. So, let's get into
this next section where I teach you guys
how to build skills better than
basically anyone out there. And this is
my proven skill building and skill using
method. So, let's hop right in. Today,
I've got this proven six-step process
for building codec skills better than
99% of people. So, let's not waste any
time and just get straight into this
one. All right. All right, so these are
the six steps that I'm going to go over.
I'm going to explain each of these and
tell you why they're so important and
then we're going to get into Codex and
actually try some of the stuff out. And
real quick before we get started, I'm
going to talk about what actually is a
skill. So, if you already know what a
skill is, then just go ahead and skip
past this part. But for those of you who
need a refresher, here we go. So, I'm
going to use my chocolate chip pancake
analogy. Let's say we have this chef and
this chef makes the most amazing
chocolate chip pancakes and you want to
know how to make those. This is
essentially the output that you're
looking for. The way that you would be
able to copy this chef is by looking at
the recipe that the chef used or the
recipe that the chef made. So the chef
gives you the recipe, this is you. And
now you're able to pretty much make the
exact same output, the really, you know,
popular famous chocolate chip pancakes
because you followed the recipe. So this
recipe is basically the skill. This is
essentially the skill.md file, which
means a markdown file. It's just a
simple language. It just means that
inside of the skill file there are like
pound signs and asterisks to indicate
like bullet points and headers and
things like that. So it's it's just
natural language. But then the agent is
basically able to take this skill file
and just use it so that if you say,
"Hey, Mr. AI agent, you know, make me
those chocolate chip pancakes." It
wouldn't have to be like, "Okay, well,
let me just do some research on how to
make them, and I don't know exactly what
kind of pancakes Nate wants. I don't
know how big they should be." So what
I'll do is I'll just follow this skill.
I'll follow the recipe. And now I get
the same output that Nate's looking for
and I get it consistently the same every
single time because it's all documented
for me right here. And these can be
really simple. It can be a simple prompt
like, hey, you know, help me turn this
email into something that's more
professional or something that sounds
like me and maybe that's like my Nate
email skill. But it could also be
complicated processes like doing
research on the market and analyzing,
you know, 50 stocks and telling you
which one to buy. So really, it's
whenever you want to basically like
codify some sort of process that you do
and so that you can delegate that
process to an agent and then you turn it
into a skill and now your agent can use
those skills. All right, so now that
that is out of the way, let's start with
number one up here where we have reverse
engineer. So the whole idea with reverse
engineering your skills is basically
that you want to start with an output.
You want to start with what is the
definition of done? What are you
actually looking for? Because let's say
you ask your agent here for chicken, for
example, and you actually want like
chicken parmesan on a bed of pasta, but
because you just said chicken, the agent
might interpret that a little bit
differently and make you a chicken
sandwich. And then next time you ask for
chicken, it might make you, you know,
chicken thighs. It doesn't actually know
specifically what you want. So if you
start with an output and you have, you
know, essentially this chicken parmesan
and you say, "Okay, let's reverse
engineer this food and see what went
into it, how long we cooked it, how did
we get here?" And that's how you build
the recipe. So, for example, if you
wanted to build a skill for the end of
the week report, you've got certain
columns in your Excel sheet. You've got
certain calculations that were made.
It's way easier to give the agent that
Excel sheet to give it the final
deliverable and say, "Hey, this is an
output that is really good and this is
what I want to build a skill for so that
you understand how to take some raw
input and turn it into this output that
I have already told you that I like and
this is what we're looking for every
time." And then it can basically walk
you backwards through that process.
Okay, what data did you look at? where
did you get it from? How did you
calculate it? Where did you format it?
You answer those questions and then you
have a version of a skill that already
knows sort of like the north star that
it's building towards. I think it's so
much easier to run the process, get the
output and say, "Okay, let's turn that
into a skill." Rather than saying, "Hey,
build me a skill for building a YouTube
dashboard." And then you might have this
vision and your agent might have a
completely different vision and then
you're going to get frustrated when it
delivers you a chicken sandwich and you
actually wanted chicken parm. Now
remember, all of these concepts I'm
going to, you know, bring back together
when we actually hop into Codex and I
show you some stuff. But let's just keep
moving down the list because I think
this foundation is important. So number
two, we have one specific job and one
specific trigger. So remember how I said
that these skills are markdown files.
Skill.md. What happens in the skill.md
is you've got a YAML description. It's
called YAML front matter. And then
you've got the actual skill
instructions, which is the meat of the
skill. So right here is one of the
skills that I'm going to keep coming
back to in this video because it's it's
one of my favorite skills. And you can
see up here this metadata, this is the
YAML front matter. So if I view the
source, it looks like this. It's
actually just separated by these three
dashes. So this would be the YAML front
matter. And then everything below it
would be the actual instructions of the
skill. Now this is markdown. And when I
said markdown is very simple. It is. You
can see here are two pound signs. And
that just indicates a header. We can see
that we've got these little dashes which
are bullet points. And so when markdown
is actually rendered, it looks more
something like this. And you can see
it's just formatted better. So this is
the way that I like to look at it. But
if you click on view source inside of
the Codex app, you can see the raw
markdown file. But anyways, the metadata
up here is the YAML front matter and
that tells us what is the name of the
skill and when do you explicitly use it.
And there are other fields that can be
populated in here like in this one we
have an argument hint. And basically
this X article skill is used when I ask
my agent to turn an YouTube video into a
long form X post. And so sometimes it'll
feed in this argument which is my
YouTube video URL that it will take, it
will download, it will transcribe it, it
will take screenshots of it, all that
sort of, you know, all the stuff. And
then once the agent has basically said,
"Okay, cool. Nate wants to turn this
YouTube video into an X article. So,
okay, cool. I found this skill that I
need to use. Now that I know this is the
skill I'm going to invoke, let me read
the entire description of the skill. So
now I understand exactly what to
actually do." And you can see this skill
is pretty long. There's a lot of
instructions in here. And this wasn't
like me on one try turning this into a
skill. This is probably a skill that's
been iterated on 25 or more times. And
we'll talk more about that in a bit. But
the whole idea is that you want a skill
to do one very specific job. You don't
want to have a skill that's like run the
marketing team. You want to have a skill
that breaks that marketing team, all of
those processes into individual steps.
So in my book right up here, becoming AI
native, I talk about this and I call it
the function breakdown. I call it the
the tree. Basically, your job is a tree
and you've got different trunks with
different like, you know, bullet points
in your job description and then each of
those trunks have branches and each of
those branches have ultimately leaves
and you want to turn all of those little
leaves or those little tasks into skills
because you can chain skills together
over time. But the point being, if you
have a skill with one very specific job,
you can give it one very specific
trigger, which means that your agents
are going to be able to execute them
more consistently, invoke them
automatically. It just helps you
separate out what your agents are doing
in a much better way than if you have a
skill that's like 30 pages long and it's
supposed to do so many different things.
So think about breaking down processes
at the task level and turning each of
those tasks into skills. All right,
moving on to number three. We have
thinking about the freedom level. So
what I mean by this is when you're
automating things, you basically have to
figure out is this a deterministic
automation or a non-deterministic
automation? Basically, is this something
that's predictable and we know exactly
what comes in and we know exactly what
happens and we know exactly what comes
out or is it more of a non-deterministic
AI agent, more of a nondeterministic
black box where we know sort of what the
input's going to look like. We sort of
know what's going to happen inside the
process, but we do kind of know like
what the output should be. We still know
the definition of good and the
definition of done. You can think about
it like, can I automate this using
rules? Hard rules, hard logic. Is x
greater than 10? Is x equal to 500? or
is it something that needs a lot of
judgment? Analyze this. Turn this into
an email. Turn this into a spreadsheet.
And it's really important to think about
where does your skill live on that
spectrum? Because if you have a very
deterministic skill, like for example,
it just has to take a Excel sheet and it
just has to populate the cells into the
CRM or something and that's basically
just data processing transferring.
That's a very deterministic process. And
if you write the skill in a very
nondeterministic way, there's a lot more
room for error. There's a lot more room
for AI to interpret something wrong and
do something wrong. And that's the case
where you want the skill to be like step
one do this, step two, do this. Exactly,
exactly. Exactly. Do this. It's very
specific. But if you've got something
nondeterministic, like for example, my X
article skill, we don't want to be so
specific. We want the AI to be able to
use its judgment and to be able to use
research and thinking to generate a
unique output because every YouTube
video is different, which means every X
article is going to be different, which
means all the screenshots that it needs
to take are going to be different. I
couldn't say something like screenshot
the video at the 1 minute mark and then
the two-minute mark and then the 5minute
mark and put those into the article at
line 400, line 600, line 700 because
then the articles would come out feeling
generic and they probably wouldn't even
make sense and it just wouldn't be a
very good output. So think about the
freedom level of the process and when
you're doing this manually, do you
follow the same set of instructions
every time or are you constantly using
judgment and are you constantly doing
different things within the process to
ultimately get to that definition of
good? By the way, guys, I've got this
completely free SOP for you about
getting your first a automation client.
It's going to go over the exact steps
that has been proven for hundreds of our
AIS Plus members to get their first paid
gigs. It goes over the one sentence
service pitch that can get you started
today, why your first client should cost
you money, the 5-minute video that
answers, can this person actually
deliver before you've actually received
any money, what to do when you have zero
case studies. There's so many good
things in here that are going to help
you out. Even if you already do have
clients, I would recommend grabbing this
because, like I said, it's yours
completely free. So, if you want to grab
this, there's a link for it down in the
description. Let's get back to the
video. All right, moving on to number
four, we have verification. And this is
probably the most important piece of
building skills. So, the whole idea of
building a skill is that now you can
trust that your agent's going to give
you an output more consistently that
meets your standard. But what you want
to do in there is you don't want to be
constantly being handed the agents V1.
You want to be handed an output that's
already good to go that you can give it
a quick skim, approve it all, and then
shoot it off. And the cool thing about
agents building stuff to ultimately
achieve some sort of northstar is that
you can also have agents check its own
work, verify its own work, or you know,
other agents verify different agents
work. So every single skill that I build
works in some sort of verification loop,
meaning the agent who builds the thing,
delivers this output, and then we either
have the same agent or different sub
agents come in and verify that output
and then provide feedback. And this
verification loop can go on multiple
times. Sometimes it's just, hey, here's
the V2 and it's approved. Here's the V7.
I've even had agents verify over and
over and give me like a V15 or 16. And
that basically just ensures that your
time isn't being wasted verifying and
sending feedback when you can have
agents do that for you. Now, when it
comes to verification, there is a
difference between objective checks and
subjective checks. So, let me explain
what I mean by that. An objective check
is something that can literally be
proven. Sort of like the
non-deterministic versus deterministic
thing. Objective means okay um I wanted
you to do research and then the
verification was to pull in 500 sources
cut that down to the best 250 and then
every single fact that's in the article
I want that to be double checked by
second agent and that's objective we can
literally prove 500 sources cut down to
250 every single fact double checked by
a different agent that's objective that
is a rule does x equal y is a greater
than b but then you have some things
that are subjective like verifying the
video right if it's it's creating a
video for you or if it's creating a
website for you. A lot of these
subjective checks are more like, oh, you
know, does everything look good? Is
everything inbounds? Is it loading in a
certain way? When you don't have an
actual hard metric to align it to, you
have to sort of be a little bit more
subjective on your verification. And
what you're thinking about doing is
turning that agent into an LLM as a
judge, which basically means, okay, so
if AI is going to be applying its
approval, and it has to use judgment to
approve, then how can you tell the agent
exactly what you're looking for? What
does good typically look like or feel
like even though there's not a hard
rule? So, for example, with the X
article skill, I've got some objective
checks in there, like there are 10
screenshots from the video. But then
there's other subjective checks like how
do you make it flow in a way that makes
sense? How do you make it sound like
Nate? How do you make sure that the
images that are put into the the
article, the screenshots, are cropped?
There's other subjective checks that we
have to let it do things where it like
opens up the app and it scrolls through
and it reads through and it screenshots
and it verifies. But a lot of those
checks, like I said, are more
subjective. And so that's where
iterating on these skills takes a lot of
time because you're constantly running
the skill, analyzing the output, giving
feedback, running the skill again,
analyzing the output, giving feedback.
And you're basically just like training
the skill where every single time you
use it, it gets better. But the thing
about verification is there's always a
way. You might be thinking to yourself,
well, I don't really know how I would
have agents verify that process. Agents
can do anything. They can use your
computer. They can use your browser.
They can look at things. They can listen
to things. They can do anything. So just
think about it like this. If you
assigned that task to a human, what
would you do to basically give it the
stamp of approval? And then just explain
that to the agent and that's your
verification. That doesn't mean it's
going to always come out 100%, but it's
going to be more like 95% rather than
giving you something that started off at
like 75 or 80. Okay. And moving on to
number five, we've got walk it down. And
when I say walk it down, I mean walking
it down the model list. So whether
you're using Cloud Code or Codeex, we
all know that different models have
different strengths. And we all know
that models that have the strongest
strengths are the most expensive. So for
example, Astra is more expensive than
Soul, but more capable than Soul. Soul
is more expensive than Terra, but more
capable than Terra. So the idea is you
build a skill and you're getting this
good output. And maybe you were testing
that with Astra. Okay, well let's run
that same skill on Soul. Are we getting
the same result? If we're getting the
same result and it's cheaper, okay,
let's test it on Terra now. Are we
getting the same result? Is it cheaper?
Okay, let's test it on Luna. There's no
reason to be running a skill with Astra
if you could run it with Luna and get
the exact same output. But it is
important to test it because not every
skill fits that. I've had some skills
where I run them on Haiku or Luna
because they're just super simple. For
example, when I give my agent a YouTube
video and I say, "Hey, I need a YouTube
video description and timestamps that I
can do with Luna, and doing it with
Astra is overkill. But for this ex
article thing, I typically like to use
at least Soul or Astra because it just
has a better understanding of
screenshotting things and putting it in
the right spot and cropping it down and
even blurring things out. It's so much
better with the browser use with Soul
and Astra. And then once you've landed
on a model that you like, you can take
that one step further and you can walk
it down the effort level. So start it
off on maybe high and if it's not good
enough, then move it up a little bit.
And if it is good, then move it down to
medium and just keep finding basically
the simplest model or the lightest and
cheapest model that still executes at
the level of quality that you're looking
for. And then moving on here to number
six, we have the bike method, which is
I've kind of already alluded to it
multiple times throughout this video so
far, but really it's just the idea to me
that your skill is never done. Every
single time you run the skill, you're
going to improve it. You're going to
say, "Hey, here's what I really liked.
Here's what I didn't like. Update the
skill so that next time it's better."
Almost every single time I run a skill,
I give it feedback and I tell it to
update. And if you think about this,
like you're teaching a kid to ride a
bike, that's what a skill really should
feel like. You start off very cautious.
You're watching everything. You're
guiding them. You you've got your hand
on the the the steering wheel. Steering
wheel, I meant like handlebars. And
you're you're right there. And then what
happens is you give feedback. You say
like, "Okay, that was good, but you
know, you were leaning a bit too far to
the left. Make sure your weight's more
in the center." And then you keep going.
Eventually, you take off the training
wheels because the skill is getting
better and you're getting more trust in
the skill. and then you give more
feedback again and then eventually you
take off the elbow pads, right? And then
you keep giving feedback. But that
doesn't mean that you just take off the
kid's helmet and let them bike on the
highway. You're not going to do
something reckless like that. You're
also not just going to shoot them off
down the road and then go inside and
take a nap. You're still going to be in
in some way watching or having certain
guardrails in place in order to make you
feel comfortable and in order for you to
have more trust in the actual skill
itself. And I truly believe in the idea
that there's no such thing as a finished
product unless your skill is super super
deterministic and it runs perfect every
time and you don't have to worry about
it. But when the skills are more on the
judgment side of the spectrum, you know,
as we talked about up here, the more
your skills live over here, the less I
believe that you can actually have a
finished skill because like I said,
every time things might happen a little
bit differently and every time your
process might change or new models might
drop and you're just constantly going to
be giving feedback every time you use
it. Okay, so let's hop into Codeex here
and we can take a look at how this
actually works. Now when you are inside
of your project and if you're inside of
your AIOS which is usually what I'm
building in the codec skills will live
in a folder called the aagents and then
inside of the aagents there's a skill or
sorry not a skill there's another folder
calledskills and if you're doing this in
cloud code the skills live in aclaude
and then in a folder called skills now
these can be transferable I basically
just tell codeex or claude hey see all
the skills in there and bring them over
here too so just I have duplicates of
them but that's where they actually live
inside of your um project unless you
have them at a global level which just
means they're living locally across all
of your codeex projects rather than just
inside of your AOS. So that's where they
live and you can always just say hey you
know Codex I have this skill I don't
remember where it is could you show me
the file path and it will find it and
you can move it if you want but anyways
that's where they live and you can see I
actually just ran this ex article skill
on a video so it says your ex article
draft is saved. I'll click into it and I
actually did obviously already publish
this one but I didn't even have to
change anything. I basically just
clicked in here. I read it all and I
published it. And you can see that as
it's going through, it already formatted
everything and it used the video. Of
course, it took screenshots of things
and it like put them in the right spot
to line up with what was actually being
said in the article. And it even added
this little um I don't know what you
want to call it, like a spotlight. It
added that. I didn't actually do that,
but it will basically crop things out
and it will add things like that into my
actual article because I've told it in
the skill to do things like that. And
you can see that for this specific
video, this ran on GBD6 Astra. So, what
I'm going to do real quick is I'm going
to walk this down. I'm going to give
this same prompt to Soul and Terra and
tell it to make the X article and it's
going to use the skill. And we'll see
how those outputs compare to Astra's
output because this is a pretty complex
skill. It has to transcribe the video.
It has to open up the article. It has to
make the thumbnail. It has to format
everything and it has to screenshot
everything and put it in and then
actually like drag it around. So there's
a lot of browser use and there is a ton
of judgment inside of this. Like I said,
this is not a deterministic skill. So
you can see right now I have Soul,
Terra, and Luna all running. It's been
about 10 minutes, so I'll just check
with you guys when this is done. But I
just wanted to show you how all of them
because of the skill, because of the
verification, are viewing images. You
can see how many times Luna has viewed
these images here because it's taking
screenshots and it's trying to
understand, okay, which of these should
be worked into the article and where and
why. Same thing down here with Soul.
Obviously, this one is a super super
visualheavy sort of skill, but because
I've worked that in there, all of them
are viewing images no matter what. And
so, it'll be really interesting to see
how they decide to place them and, you
know, what images they actually choose
to put in there because X limits you to
a certain amount of images per article.
So, I'm going to let these run. We'll
compare the results and we'll kind of
talk about how walking it down has
changed my perspective on this specific
skill. All right, so you can see now
that we have Luna and Terra have
finished up. Soul is still working. So,
we'll start reviewing these two and then
we'll hop over to Soul. Hopefully, it'll
be done by the time we're looking
through these. So, Luna took 28 minutes
and 33 seconds. Let's open up the draft
and see what we are working with. So, we
have um the thumbnail in there. We have
I designed a one person million-dollar
business with Claude. Um the title is
the same as like the opening line, which
I don't love. There's also this weird
spacing was right there. I don't know if
it tried to like center it, but I do
notice that. Anyways, we have sort of
like the TLDDR. We have these different
headers here. I'm yet to see an image.
Here comes the first screenshot. So,
this is talking about um the three
different types of ideas to compare. And
in the screenshot, we do see all three.
So, that matches up pretty well. Um we
see agent report card as well as down
here. So, really what I'm checking for
right now is that it all sounds like me.
So, this is kind of trained on like my
LinkedIn style guide and my YouTube
style guide and like the way that I
speak, but I'm also making sure that the
images look good. So, the test suite is
a golden data set. We know what the
correct answer or correct action should
be. And we see an evaluation right here.
The first run scored 88. That's what we
see. Um, approved the new policy. Same
16 tests. Ran it again. That looks
decent. I clicked create report and we
don't really see the report here. So,
that's a little bit off, I would say,
but it's not too bad. I'm actually
impressed that Luna is doing it this
well. This is customer support. This is
kind of just the home dashboard. And
then down here we see searching for
companies using clay. It did do a nice
little spotlight animation here when
we're looking at the actual pricing. And
then we've got the three Ps down here.
Okay, so this is not too bad. We'll have
to compare, but I would say that I was
impressed by Luna's ability to
screenshot, add spotlights, put it in
the right spots. So that is Luna. That
also took 28 minutes and 30 seconds.
Okay, so we have Terara. And by the way,
all of these are running on high. So we
have Terara here. took 26 minutes. So
about 2 minutes, 2 and a half minutes
faster than Luna. Let's open up this
draft. See what we got. So same exact um
thumbnail. We have an image right away.
How I built a $1 million AI business
model with Claude. This image isn't
great. Like to start off the article
like that, that's not a very strong way
to start it off cuz it looks like it's
cut off like that. So that's bad. Um we
go through the three filters.
Oage
doesn't look very good either. I would
already say right now that um Luna did a
better job. I mean, this isn't a bad
Also, this is a zoomed in. So, it took a
screenshot of the video and then it
zoomed in on the score going from 88 to
94. So, that's not terrible. Read
complaint check company fit recommend
small trial. What you'll notice here is
it actually, if I can open this up, it
redacted sensitive details. So, it put
this block over it and said sensitive
details redacted. So, I think that
that's pretty cool. I like when it does
things like that. It did a little
spotlight effect here. It redacted more
sensitive details in this one. As you
can see, it did it again here. So, it's
it did it again here. It It shows so
many times when it needed to redact
sensitive details. It did it again. It
did it again. Okay, but this is
obviously an issue. It didn't verify
this good enough. Like, you can see that
there's literally four images in a row
down here. This one looks bad. I think
that, you know, you you you have to use
the browser to like drag these around.
And I think that it just gave up or it
stopped and thought it was done. So, so
far I would say that Luna did a better
job than Terara. And Terra was, you
know, it's a more capable model
apparently than Luna. It's also more
expensive. So, right now, if I was
choosing between these, I would choose
Luna. But now, Soul just finished up and
Soul took 38 minutes. So, normally when
I do run this, I run this on Astra. I
usually run this on Astra low, and I run
it on fast mode to get it done faster.
But, let's see. This did it. Let me open
this up. Okay, so here is uh Soul's
version. I built a $1 million business
with Claude. We have the same sort of
like TLDDR, the three filters. We have a
picture of the three filters right here.
So, that's not bad. Choosing the
product. Okay, it's zoomed in here.
These are all zoomed in, by the way. So,
it's it's it's using more, I guess,
vision intelligence to choose what to
actually display in the image. You can
see it redacted here the demo receipt.
So, not too bad. It zoomed in a little
bit here on the report, although we
don't see the score 88. What it what it
highlighted here was 14 tests pass and
two failed instead of showing us the 88.
So, just pointing that out. It also
zoomed in down here on some analysis of
that report. It did a little spotlight
effect here to show the 94. It redacted
more of these receipts. It did another
spotlight here. It shows sales and
support without losing control. So,
that's not terrible. We've got this
customer support image as well. We've
got more internal source ID redacted.
Another spotlight effect on the money.
And yeah, so this one isn't too bad
either. I would say honestly like I'm
wondering if Luna's was better. And
that's the thing, like these are so
different and sometimes I have tutorial
videos, sometimes I have more of this
style where they're edited. So, it's
very hard to just say, "Okay, I've run
one test and I know that now I'm going
to go with Luna instead of like Astra or
something for for a specific example."
Now, I will tell you guys, I've done
this multiple times on multiple
different YouTube videos and Astra just
seems to be the best. So, I do stick
with Astra on low, but I do think it's
worth running them through a few
different examples and and
understanding. And that's why I said
that there's really no such thing as a
finished product, especially the more
non-deterministic you get on that whole
spectrum. And what you can see about all
of these with Luna, it gave us a QA
report, it gave us a visual plan, and it
gave us selected frames. Terra gave us a
QA report as well. And Soul gave us a QA
report. And like I said, that's the most
important part is just them proving that
they've verified stuff. So, it verified
the title, the body, 76 non-mpty text
blocks, um 11 inline screenshots, seven
H2 headings, visual review and privacy,
editorial coverage, artifacts. It's
proving to me that it's done. And it's
proving to me that it did its
verification. And trust me, if it didn't
do this QA report and it didn't do the
verification, this skill would be so
much worse as far as actually getting it
to place the screenshots in the right
spot. So, for this specific example of
the skill, let me talk about how I did
all of these things. I took an article
that I did manually and I did a few of
these manually where I literally went
through the YouTube video, screenshotted
things, put it in the right spot and I
gave it some of those to look at. So,
first was like, hey, analyze all these
outputs. I want to turn this into a
skill. So, help me understand like
what's good about these and and how do
you choose the screenshots and how do
you place them and things like that. So,
I reverse engineered and then obviously
this is one very specific job. It was to
turn a YouTube video into an X article.
It's not just to write X articles in
general. We've got I've got a different
skill for that. This is literally to
turn a YouTube video into an X article,
which means the trigger is very specific
as well. So here, all I said was turn
this YouTube video into an X article.
And it automatically was able to invoke
the X article skill as you can see. But
if I wanted to do a slash command and do
X article, I can invoke the skill like
that as well. But typically, if I say,
hey, I want this YouTube video to be
turned into an X article, it just
invokes the skill automatically because
it's one specific use case and it's one
specific trigger. We talked about the
freedom level in here a lot. This is
obviously a super super non-eterministic
process. We talked about the
verification. We did the walking it down
live. And as far as the bike method,
like I said, guys, I would basically
come into here and I would look at what
Tara did that I didn't like. And I would
basically be like, "Okay, Tara, so in
your article, you had some really weird
screenshots in the beginning. It looked
like things were cropped out." The whole
idea is that people can look at the
screenshot and they won't need context
of what happened a few seconds before
that frame or a few seconds after. And
you have multiple examples in here like
the first screenshot you did as well as
the second screenshot that you did that
just don't look very good. You also have
things at the end like these random four
images that don't feel like they're
placed right. So I feel like your
verification wasn't good enough, but
also the third the third image in this
set of or sorry the second image in this
set of three at the bottom. It's like
halfway through an animation. So that
was first of all a bad screenshot to
take and second of all a bad place to
put it. So that's some of the feedback
that I have for you. Now if you could
analyze this, understand what I mean by
this and then update the skill so that
you don't make these mistakes in the
future and so that you can highlight
some of the important things that I just
mentioned blah blah blah. And then I
would just shoot that off and it would
go through, it would look at the
feedback and it would take all of that
information and it would update the
skill. And that is how you start to sort
of see that bike method coming into play
every single run, give good feedback and
also give bad feedback and tell it to
update the skill. Otherwise, all of
those changes that you have to make
manually, you're going to have to make
manually again the next time. So anyways
guys, those were the six tips. Those
were all of them ran on a real example
of one of the skills that I use pretty
much every day. Every time I make a
YouTube video. So I appreciate you guys
watching through all that. And also
guys, real quick, just wanted to tell
you about my second channel where I just
kind of like document these things that
I'm doing at AI events or these
different trips I'm taking to meet up
with AI creators or speaking at things.
And if you want to check out sort of
like what else I'm into besides just
like making tutorials, then head over to
the second channel. I'll put the link in
the description and I hope to see you
guys over there. I hope you enjoy this
type of content as well. All right, now
that you guys understand how skills work
and how you use them, let's talk about a
few specific examples of how you can
start to build skills that are very,
very specific to you and they feel like
they're coming from you and they feel
like they're coming from your business
when you're creating deliverables or and
or when you want your team to create
deliverables that sound like you guys
and that they all look the same and
things like that. So, let's hop into
this next section. Okay, so we've built
our AIOS, we've got that all set up,
we've talked about skills, now let's
start to talk about some specific use
cases of using your business and skills.
So, what I wanted to talk about here is
how we can start to create some branded
deliverables like sheets or docs or
slideshows or, you know, even videos and
websites and all that kind of good
stuff. But one thing that you want to
get set up is kind of like your brand
guidelines, your brand rules, logos,
color schemes, typography, things of
that nature. So, right here we're inside
of the AIS OS that we have set up. And
you can see that I'm said, hey, what's
my company in this AIOS? It's up at AAI.
It's a Automation Society. And if I go
in here, we have all of our files and
folders set up. So, if you are ever in a
situation where you want to add some
context or you want to do something with
your AIS or sorry, not your ASOS, your
AIOS, and you don't really know exactly
where things should live and you feel
like you're going to do something wrong.
The first thing I want to say is I don't
think there is such thing as wrong.
There's not like one universal standard
because it's AI. AI is able to search
through things and understand your rules
and every single person's AIOS is going
to be different, but no one's is like
wrong. The only way it's wrong is if
it's going to hallucinate things or if
it can't find things and if there's way
too much data, things like that. So, if
you're noticing that it's lying or that
it can't find things or that it's making
up details, that's where you probably
did something wrong and you just need to
sort of run an audit, analyze things,
and clean some things up. And once
again, you can do that with natural
language. But let's say I wanted to add
some like logos and some color schemes
and things like that. I would say, "Hey,
so I want to add some logos. I want to
give you some more brand guidelines so
that in the future when we're making
things like docs or any deliverables,
you can make sure it feels branded to
me." meaning like my voice but also you
know physical styling when it comes to
these deliverables. So I want to have
some sort of folder inside of the AIOS
called brand guidelines. Where should we
put that based on our current folder
structure
and we will go ahead and shoot that off.
So it made the suggestion and it
suggested what we could put in there and
I'm just going to say yep go ahead and
set that up. And now you can see that it
created that folder right here brand
assets and we have some things in there
like a few markdown files some spaces
for logos and things. And so I opened up
this in my actual folder right here. You
can see this is the U brand assets and I
clicked into logos. I clicked into uppai
and then I opened up another file
explorer where I actually just want to
drag in some logos. So I'm going to copy
these three and I'm going to copy them
and I'm just going to come and paste
them right in here. So now we have three
upi logos. And then I could also do the
same thing. I'll copy these four and I
will paste these into the AI automation
society side over here. So now we just
have a few logos set up. And now you can
see that those are showing up here in
our actual AIOS. Now what I would
recommend doing from here is yes, it's
good to have logos in there. But I
probably want to brainstorm a little bit
on what are our brand guidelines. If you
already have that, like if you already
have your colors and your typography,
like the fonts that you use, then just
go ahead and give that information to
codeex right here and it'll put it in
there. But if you need to brainstorm on
it, then just brainstorm on it a little
bit. And what else you can do is have it
generate you a brand guidelines doc. So
watch this. You can see that I just
dropped in some logos for UPAI. Now, in
there, I have a few different logos.
I've got like a white one and a light
blue one. The light blue one is the main
logo. That's like our primary logo, and
that's what I want you to always add on
our deliverables. Like in the docs, I
want you to have it as a header. In the
slides, I want you to have it like in
the bottom left or something. And the
colors are pretty much that same way.
You know, we like to use white and we
like to use that light blue. And I
always want our deliverables to feel
professional and they should feel
trusted. And so we really like to
utilize that light blue and those light
colors. I don't exactly know what type
of font that I like to use, but I don't
want it to feel like too techy. I want
it to feel very modern and clean. So
could you just go ahead and generate me
a brand guidelines sheet, you know, like
an actual image that shows um the way
that we like to have our buttons, the
way that we like to have um logos,
colors, things like that. And that's
actually how I've made all of these
different images that I have where we
see like our brand guidelines with, you
know, Nate Herk. It has like these
colors. it has these sorts of buttons
and all this stuff like that so that as
we're generating new things in the
future, I can always just point my AI
towards that file and that's like the
source of truth. And I like to usually
have one that's a markdown file so it's
easier for the AI to read and you can
see the actual hex codes and everything
like that and the font names, but then I
also like to have one that's like an
image in case you want to send that to
your team or send that to a sponsor or
something like that. And so while that
is making that, I'll show you guys some
other examples and I'll also talk about
like why this is so important. And real
quick, you can see that inside of the
readme of the brand assets folder, here
is what it generated. It says, "Hey,
this folder is the visual source of
truth for UPAI and AIS deliverables. It
keeps approved assets and usage rules
findable, so future work uses the brand
instead of guessing for any document,
PDF, presentation, report, whatever.
Read this, read this, read here, go look
at the templates, go look at the logos,
do all this." And so it basically is
just creating this read me so that your
agent always understands why does this
folder exist and where should it look
for different things like fonts and
templates and examples and colors and
whatever else you want to give it in
here. So you can see right now it's
using its generate image tool to
actually make that for us. And then we
can turn that into a markdown file
that's a little bit more structured. And
there you go. You can see that this came
out super super quick for us. I can
click into this. We see we have the
primary logo. We have the reverse. We
have a primary action button. We have a
secondary button. We have things about
placements like docs and like slides. We
have typography that it shows. We have a
color palette right here as well with
different actual hex codes that we could
put into Canva or to whatever we need to
put them in. And obviously I could mark
this up and I could make comments. If I
don't like this and I wanted to comment
on that or if I wanted to change
anything. That's what's so cool about
the desktop app is you can do so many
things right from inside here. You can
even remove backgrounds. So you can play
around with this until you get it the
way you want it and then say, "Hey, can
you also turn that into, you know, like
a markdown version for me or a text
version for me so that different agents
can read that easier." But look how easy
I was able to turn one logo into a
formal brand guidelines doc. And now
that you have that, what you can do is
you can generate deliverables with this
in mind or websites or videos or
whatever it is. But also you work that
into the skills. And now I have skills
like this. This is a student resource
guide skill. So whenever I have a
YouTube video or I read an article or I
just want to do a brain dump and I say,
"Hey, can you turn this into a student
resource guide?" It does all the stuff.
It puts the AIS header up here. It uses
this font. It uses these sorts of colors
and headers. It links my YouTube channel
at the top. You can see this link right
here to my YouTube channel. It puts
these horizontal bars. It does all of
this in the way that I love it. And then
at the very bottom, what it does is it
also links people to AI automation
society plus. And this is because I gave
it the skill with my brand guidelines
and with also, you know, of course, my
rules for building the student resource
guide. I also have one for writing up at
AAI memos. It has a UP at AAI header up
here. It has this sort of like um I I
guess I was about to say YAML front
matter as if this is a skill. Whatever
this whatever you call this, like a
little header. Once again, it has like
different colors. It has these the way
that I structure this. It even has the
footer here, the confidential internal
UPAI communication footer. It has all of
this now because once again, I gave it
brand guidelines, but also I told it how
I like to write our internal memos. It
also works with things like sheets. This
is one that I run whenever I want to do
like a YouTube report, whether it's
quarterly or whether it's threequarters.
Look at all this stuff. It has colors on
the tabs down here, so I can easily
navigate between all these tabs. It has,
you know, colors inside of this. You can
see that the font isn't just the basic
font. It's using Monsterat for the font
because that's on our brand guideline
doc. It put the logo up here. It has big
hero text up here. And then as I go
through, I'm getting data visualized for
me as well. I'm getting charts. I'm
getting different things like this
because this is the way that I told it.
I like to see it. And not only is it
giving me all of this data with all of
these links and all of these, you know,
interesting insights, but the whole
thing feels branded to me. It feels like
something I would send to my team and
they'd be like, "Yeah, this is an upai
sheet." And that's what I want you guys
to realize is that every single time
that you're generating outputs with your
AIOS, you can have it be exactly the way
you want it. And you can give the brand
guidelines and you can give the skills
to your team. So now everyone is
generating things that look exactly the
same. So that it all feels like it's
coming from your brand voice so that it
all looks consistent. And then when you
guys start to push out things like
articles or blog posts or LinkedIn
posts, it always also has the brand feel
as well. And it doesn't just have to be
Google Sheets. It can be PDFs or HTML
docs or whatever you want. But here's
another example with a slideshow. This
is a slide deck where we can see we have
the branding up here. Once again, this
all just feels consistent because it's
using the same color schemes and it's
building it in a way that feels like
it's an UPAI doc. And obviously, there's
some other things that I put into the
skill here like having these sorts of
visualizations, having, you know, swim
lanes or um calendars or having actual
data being visualized here with charts
and things like that. And what's cool
about this one is it also generated this
Excel sheet or Google sheet to go with
it because it had to actually generate
these visualizations. And it did this in
Google Sheet and then it brought all
these over and put them into the actual
slide deck that it built which I was
just on the other tab for. And you can
see that was actually right here. It was
the mock data slide deck. We have all of
these different things with the
branding. It also created um a different
workbook which was the Google sheet to
make all of those charts. And like I
said for all of these we talked about
how with skills we like to sort of
reverse engineer them. So what I did was
I basically used codeex to help me get
to a place where I liked an output. So
let's say the student resource guide. I
went back and forth. Now I have an
output that I like and now I turn this
into a skill. And in that skill I
basically say, "Hey, by the way, include
all of these things from the brand
assets. Include the header up top.
Include the logo down there. Include
these colors, whatever." And the reason
I really like to do it inside of Google
is because we work out of Google Drive.
So it also knows when it's creating
deliverables to put it in the share
drive, to put it inside of the education
folder or the marketing folder or the
AIS folder or wherever it needs to go.
It knows to just throw it right there so
that my team can access it
automatically. Because when you're
building things locally like this um
HTML report for example, there's not
really a problem with that. It's just
less editable because now if I wanted to
edit this, I would have to manipulate
the code and I would have to say, "Hey,
you know, Codex, can you change this
line or can you make this a different
color?" Whereas now in here, if I wanted
to make a quick edit, I could just come
in here and make a quick edit. And then
I can also send this to my team right
away. With this, I would have to like
download this and send it to them over
ClickUp or email, they'd have to
download it, open it up. If they wanted
to make a change, they'd have to make a
change and then send it back to me. So,
I just like to work with live cloud
data, you know, cloud deliverables like
Google Sheets, Google Docs. I really
just like the Google ecosystem,
honestly. And it's pretty cool because
you can obviously just come into your
codecs, you can go up here to the
plugins, and you can just connect the
Google Drive plugin, and it lets you do
pretty much everything through Drive,
Docs, Sheets, or Slides. And I know this
is starting to sound like a Google ad,
but trust me, it's not. But here is
another example of an HTML skill. And
this is what I call an HTML explainer.
So whether this is a deliverable or
whether this is just something that I
want, whenever I want to turn a concept
into something that's a bit more visual
and in a way that explains it to me or
to my students or to my team, I use this
HTML explainer skill. And this one isn't
as branded, but you can still see that
in the top left, we have the logo. And
you can still see that it kind of fits
the color scheme a little bit. But the
whole point of this one is that this
creates HTML. So it's explaining some
sort of concept to me, and it does it in
this way where it's very visual. It's
not very wordy. It's very easy to
understand and it just lays it out as if
it was trying to teach me a lesson. And
it, like I said, it uses visualizations
really well because that's the way that
I like to learn. I like to actually see
examples and I like to see flowcharts
and little symbols and things like that.
So, this is an HTML explainer skill. So,
whenever I need something explained to
me or I want to explain something to my
team, I just go ahead and use this
skill. And this also created a different
version for us. One with like a
transparent background and then one like
this. So, we could send that around and
like I said, make some tweaks. And now
you have some brand guidelines. And that
was just a visual brand guideline doc.
This is something else that you can
start to work in is like how does your
company actually talk? Do you guys have
slogans? Do you guys have mods? Do you
guys have big hero stats that you always
want your whole team to know when
they're writing emails or deliverables?
For us, we have this thing called an AI
phrase kill list, which is things that I
hate that AI says a lot. And I've got a
ton of things on here and this is shared
with my team so that then when they're
generating emails or content or you know
copy I don't want them to have their
output sounding like AI. So this is one
of the other things that we work into
our like team brand guidelines not just
from a visual perspective but also from
like a what does our voice sound like?
Who is our avatar we're speaking to? All
of those things that you want everyone
on the team to have sort of like a
unified view on. That's also stuff that
you can put into your AIOS. You can turn
into skills and then you can share with
your team. So, I would encourage you to
think about stuff like that. How do you
know that something came from your
brand? And more importantly, what kind
of stuff do you want to make sure
doesn't come from your brand? So, for
me, that was things like m dashes and
things like saying, you know, and
honestly, and honestly, it's not just X,
it's Y, not a tool, not a feature, a
revolution. And speaking of visual
elements of a brand, we know that codecs
can make us images because chatgbt image
2.5 or whatever the image model is from
OpenAI by the time you're watching this,
it's inside of codec. So if I ever say,
"Hey, make me a picture, make me a
thumbnail," blah blah blah. It can do it
from here, which is amazing. And I
really think OpenAI's image model is the
best right now. But what it can't do
right now is generate video or it can't
use other AI models. If you wanted to do
a different, you know, maybe Gemini's
model is really good, nano banana, or
maybe you want to do like a sea dance
video or a cling video. Well, let me
talk about next how can you connect
codeex to a different tool that will let
you generate images and videos with tons
of different models. So let's jump into
the next segment. One of the great
things about Codex is that right inside
of it, it can make images for you. As
you can see right here, I gave it these
three images and I said, "Hey, I need a
YouTube thumbnail." I described what I
want and then I got it right here. But
if I asked it to turn this into an
animated video, it wouldn't be able to
do it with its native capabilities. It
would have to find some other form. It
would have to build code. Like here, it
wants to use hyperframes. So, typically
what you'd do is you'd connect it to
something like Higsfield that has a
bunch of video and image models like
Cance 2.5 and all these other ones like
Cling and Omni Flash and Miniax. The
problem with Higsfield was that it was
way more expensive because you had to
get on a subscription. If we look at the
monthly, if you wanted to use Seedance
2.5, you had to be on a 60 bucks a month
plan and you still had a limited number
of credits. But Higfield just actually
dropped an API which means that you can
actually just pay per usage. Meaning you
can connect Codeex to Higsfield API and
then you're not actually paying every
single month. You're only paying for the
times that you actually make requests.
So today I'm just going to show you real
quick how easy this is to set up. So
let's get right into it. So this is a
completely separate account. What you're
going to do is you're going to go to
Google and you're going to type in
Higsfield API. And then you're pretty
much going to click on this first link
right here. And it's going to take you
to this API dashboard where you'll be
able to create your own key and create
your own account. And when you sign up,
you're going to get a ton of discounts
because they just dropped this, which is
15% off sale models, up to 50% off your
favorites, and you get 15 bucks right
away in your account to play with. So
create an account, and then when you're
inside of that, it's going to look like
this. What you're going to want to do is
you're going to go to either the quick
start on this right hand side and you
can copy this prompt if you want, but
you don't have to. It's it's a lot
easier than that. But you do have to
make an API key. So you'll click on
create API key. You'll type in a name.
So I'll just call this one demo and
you'll create your key. And then all you
have to do is copy this key right here
and then hop into CEX and I'll show you
what to do next. Real quick before we
hop into CEX, I just wanted to show you
guys how to make sure you take full
advantage of this launch because this is
a 7-day limited offer. So, these things
up here that we see, 15% off all sale
models. That is just when you sign up,
you'll already have that discount. In
order to get up to 50% off your picks,
you have to come into the pricing
section and it says choose three models
with max discount up to 50% off. And
then you would just come in here and
choose two video models and one image
model. And you can see all of the prices
over here. As you can see, with 30% off,
we would be getting it for this price
compared to the original current price.
And then the last one is getting 15 free
dollars to play with on your account.
All you have to do here is connect a
credit card and use an eligible business
domain email. And then once you've
claimed all of that stuff, you now have
that API key. You now have everything
set up and you can run 30 generations at
a time. So let's hop back into codeex
and I can show you how to get this all
set up. So you're going to open up a new
chat and you're just going to say, "Hey,
inside of myv file, can you just create
me a placeholder for Higsfield API? I'm
going to drop you in a Higsfield API
key." And then you can just figure out
how that all works so we can start
running some image and video
generations. and then just shoot that
off and it will tell you exactly where
to paste in your key. You don't want to
paste it right in here into the chat
thread. You want to paste it into thev
file. So you can see I already have that
in there. So it says, "Hey, that already
exists." But if it doesn't, it'll give
you a placeholder. And then all you have
to do is ask for the file path that you
can actually open this up. So I could
rightclick this, go to open with, and I
can just open this with whatever I want.
I'll choose default app. That opens up
my notes where I can go ahead and see
right here it added Higsfield API key.
And then you will just go ahead and
paste in your API key right there. And
then make sure you save that before you
close out of it. and then just go,
"Okay, cool. I put in that API key. Can
you see what models are available for me
through that Higsfield API?" And then
just go ahead and shoot off a test video
generation where there is a man sitting
at a laptop using Higsfield and using
codecs to generate videos. But you guys
won't have to worry about that at all
because I have this skill right here
called Higsfield API generations. And it
has all these defaults in here. It has
all of the settings. It has all of the
different things that you might need or
you would have your agent have to
normally go out and do research on.
Everything's right here. So basically
all you have to do is you've put in your
Higsfield API key into your EMV. And now
you can see it's basically going to use
that whenever you need an image or a
video and it knows exactly how to work
with Higsfield API. It knows about all
of the different functionality and
options that it has in there. And now
it's just generating me a bunch of
different images and videos that you can
see right here on screen with just using
natural language. So pretty cool stuff.
If you want to grab this skill, it's
completely free in my free school
community. The link for that is down in
the description. Just head into the free
school community. You're going to go to
classroom and click on all YouTube
resources and there will be a huge
database with a bunch of resources. You
should be able to find it right in
there. And that skill is also going to
tell you exactly how much each of your
generations cost you so that you don't
have to be constantly going back into
your Higsfield dashboard to look at the
analytics. You will just get that right
there in your chat thread. So, while
that's running, I'll just go over here
and show you real quick what actually
this stuff can look like. So, we have
Higsfield API benchmark out of all of
these videos that I generated. So, I'll
show you each one like how much it
costed or sorry, cost. My goodness, how
dare I. You can see that the total spend
for these was $7.40 and we were using
models like Cance 2.5. And once again,
this would have been only available to
us on a 60 bucks a month plan. And then
you're just sitting there paying 60
bucks a month even if you don't generate
anything that month. So, anyways, we
have some video outputs here. You can
see this is Cance 2.5. This one has no
audio, but you can generate these with
audio as well. So, that's a super super
clean shot. Same exact prompt went off
to cling 3.0. And this one has I don't
know those letters look a little bit
different compared to that image, but
they have similar sort of like
background. The letters in this one are
also off. So, it's really good to get in
here and shoot off the same prompt to a
bunch of different AI models and see
which one comes back best. In this case,
Nova came through only as Nova in
Cedance 2.5. So, in this case, it was
the best. But, of course, with Cedance
2.5, you are going to be paying a little
bit more, but once again, it's only pay
per usage. So here, this one was 1.6
bucks. This one was only about 20 cents,
and this one was only about 50. But they
also can generate sound. So let me play
you guys a few examples of some UGC
content. And we'll take a look at the
cost as well.
>> I used to skip breakfast. Now I grab
Nova protein coffee. 20 g of protein,
real coffee, and I'm out the door.
>> So this was Cedance 2.5, and it was
$3.23.
Here is Cling 3.0.
I used to skip breakfast. Now I grab
Nova protein coffee. 20 gram of protein,
real coffee, and I'm out the door.
>> And as far as realism, I think Cling 3.0
did a really, really good job here with
this character, you know, selfie style
UGC for only 60s, whereas this one you
wouldn't say. I don't know. It's like
it's not noticeably better as far as
like makes a huge difference. But in
general, I mean, Cance 2.5 is in my
opinion the leading video generation
model right here. But we also have Mini
Max and this one was a $110.
>> I used to skip breakfast. Now I grab
Nova protein coffee. 20 grams of
protein. Real coffee.
>> Anyways, I think that this one was
clearly the worst out of just these
three very, very simple videos. But it's
important, like I said, shoot off the
same prompts at different models. See
how the cost differ. See how the quality
differs. See what they're good at.
because Cance 2.5 might be the best at
like people and product shots, but maybe
Miniaax or Cling is better at different
sort of like cartoon animations or
something like that. And then of course
you can use Codex image generation. GBT
image 2.5 is really really good. It's
probably my favorite, but there are also
other image models you can try out like
Higfield Marketing Studio here or Grom
Imagine 2.0, Soul 2.0, and these are
obviously much cheaper than generating
videos. But I did take this exact same
prompt and put it into codecs. And this
is what we got here. So if you like this
better then maybe you want to just stick
with GBD2.5 and then you also have the
benefit of this just counting towards
your codec subscription or your chatbt
subscription rather than paying
separately per usage for that. Anyways,
hopping back here into codeex. What's
cool about this is Codex will go ahead
and do all the research. So you don't
have to think about the API endpoints.
You don't have to give it anything else.
You just tell it to figure it all out
and it will. And so that's why back in
here you can copy this prompt if you
want or you can just say like figure it
out because you can see this prompt is
literally pointing it to the actual
Higsfield API documentation. You can see
it says your key authenticated
successfully. The live catalog returned
76 endpoints. 18 are text to video, 44
are imagetovideo, 11 are text to image
and plus there's a few other routes. And
it's going to use Cance 2.0 for this
first run. The request was accepted with
this ID and now it's basically just
going to keep pulling on that request
until the generation is done. And
polling just means it's going to check
in and then if it's not done, it's going
to wait and it's going to check in
again. If it's not done, it's going to
wait and it's going to keep pulling or
checking until that video is actually
done. And then it will download the MP4
locally. And so, while this is finishing
up, let me just show you what else is
available inside of the Higfield API. If
you go to pricing right now, it says
that you can get up to 50% off. And this
is only for the next 7 days. So, if
you're watching this early, go here and
you can choose two video and one image
models to get 50% off on. So, you'll
literally just come in here and it will
say, "Hey, what are your models you want
to choose?" I personally chose Cance 2.5
and Clink 3.0. And then for the image
model, I chose the marketing studio
image. But then you can just go ahead
and look at all of the models in here.
And you can see the different modes that
they run in like standard or turbo or,
you know, 4K, whatever it is. And you
can see all of the information about all
these different types of models and
their pricing. And then the analytics
will basically just show you how much
you've spent. Um what is your request
looking like? What are the models you
like to use and things like that. So
just a pretty little analytics dashboard
for you. But you can see we have this
video back. Now, this is already looking
a little bit weird with Cance 2.0
because the laptop is facing the wrong
way, but let's give this a quick play.
Now, I'm really not quite sure if
anybody uses a laptop like that, but
either way, this was Cance 2.0 and there
is a better model out there now. But
what's important to realize is that the
model isn't just going to run perfectly
for you. You have to be able to prompt
it in the right way and you will start
to build skills around how you like to
prompt image generations and video
generations. And that's where this gets
really powerful is when you work in all
of these different skills and you can
add things too like your brand
guidelines or a consistent character
that you want to have and then over time
your ability to just inside of codecs
generate these different videos and
image assets is going to get better and
better. Now I did want to end off this
video talking about is this actually
cheaper? And the answer is yes and no.
It all depends on the break even point
because now that you're being charged
per usage rather than based on your
credits that reset every month, there's
a break even point. And if you're paying
per usage to the point where you're
going over that break even point, then
this is probably where you'd want to be
on a subscription. But if you're only
infrequently generating videos and
images on a monthly basis and you're
below that break even point, then it's
much cheaper obviously to be on the pay
per usage billing, especially when
you're trying to figure out like what is
your cadence, then starting with pay per
usage is a lot safer than just
committing to a monthly subscription.
And so I've run the math here and on the
plus and ultra plans within Hicksfield,
this is what it would kind of look like
as far as those break even points. So if
you're on the plus monthly, it's about
fewer than 19 clips. And if you're on
the plus annual, then it's roughly 16
clips. And if you're below that, then
the API makes more sense. If you're on
ultra, it looks like 50 on monthly or 39
on annual. So ultimately, these are the
three kind of questions I wanted to
answer here. If you're maxing out your
subscription plan every single month
consistently, then you probably just
want to stay on a subscription. If
you're only generating things
occasionally, like maybe some months
you'll run, you know, 15 videos, some
months you won't do any at all, then API
will win. And if you need programmatic
workflows or you want to bake this API
into your own, I don't know, your own
website or SAS product or your own
internal tools or whatever it is, then
the API is going to win there as well.
So, it's always hard in the AI space or
in the tech space to just come out of
the gate and say, "Yes, this is
objectively cheaper or yes, this is
objectively better." It's always very
situational. So hopefully this all kind
of makes sense and you can kind of use
this to figure out in your specific
situation what is probably the right
path for you. And what's really cool is
when you get all that dialed in, you can
do all this in bulk. So we've actually
done things where we've generated assets
for like our events or for you know ads
or whatever it is and we basically just
use codeex or claw to help us brainstorm
all the briefs and all the angles and
then we just shoot off a bunch of
workers to generate all those assets and
then you wake up and everything is done.
Now, what's really cool is what you can
actually do with Codeex as far as
building websites when you actually have
learned now how to generate other videos
and other images to put on those
websites. So, we're going to hop into
this next section where I kind of show
you guys what's possible with Astra and
with Codeex when it comes to designing
things like websites. We have a new AI
design king and it's not even close.
Take a look at some of these outputs
I've been getting with Astra. Look how
cool this scroll is. How about this
example with GLO? I think that this is
just absolutely incredible. I think Asha
does a really good job at making things
3D, dynamic, immersive without making it
overwhelming because this is still a
very clean hero section. Now, this one
for perk form is a little bit more out
there, but it's very impressive what it
was able to do, but I still think it's
pretty clean. And we have other types of
animations here. Look at these cans come
in. I love how it was able to create
these in 3D. Now, I just put out a video
that I said Fable 5.1 was the design
king because it helped me create
something like this, which I loved. But
Astra is so much better with it so far.
Now, all of these examples that we just
looked at and that we're going to keep
looking at were oneshot prompts. Think
about that. If I took the time to
actually sit down and iterate on these,
they would be so much better. This was
Astra's first pass at an AI Automation
Society website. You can see it tried to
keep the same vibe. So, right now, the
one that Fable built, I think, is the
winner because I've iterated on this
like 15 times, but as a first shot, I
think that this is really, really good.
It's on brand and like I said, it has
these animations and these interesting,
you know, like immersive parallax
things, but it's just it's not too much.
I've been seeing you guys talk about in
the comments how, oh, I don't think
these sites convert. And I think you're
right, but it depends on the three Ps
that I talk about, the pain, the person,
the promise. But I love how subtle this
is, but instantly I think that this
feels premium. You feel the depth and
it's not too overwhelming, and it still
fits the brand that you know that you
have here. It still fits the messaging
that you're trying to get across. even
something like a luxury watch brand. I
think that even just this little element
right here that lets us sort of scroll
through really makes it, you know, it
sets it apart from other types of
websites in this industry because it's
not just about the hero section. I think
that the way that all of these sites are
designed are very on brand. It's not
like one super specific template that
we're following every single time. It's
different each time. So, I know that
I've just been jumping all around with
examples. I just wanted to show you guys
some of the different things that it's
been able to do and some of the
different ways that it uses its creative
freedom and taste because I basically
just told it to make me a bunch of
websites. Now, the one thing that all of
these that I just showed you have in
common is that they used my scroll craft
skill, which if you guys don't have
that, join my free school community
linked in the description. That's where
you can get the skill, and I'm
constantly updating that thing as I find
out more about AI design. Not only does
that skill understand things like
layering, as you can see here, and
scrolling, but it also understands
things like typography and spacing and
all of those other elements that you
need to make the website actually feel
good as you continue to scroll through.
But I think that's been one of the
biggest things that I've realized lately
is the layering adds so much depth
because you can clearly see how the text
is on a different layer than the
background image, which is on a
different layer than the bike, which is
on a different layer than the rocks
right here. And that's what makes it
feel super immersive without being over
the top, at least in my opinion. because
at the end of the day, all of this stuff
is subjective and it's all about taste.
But like I said, my scrollcraft skill
has all that knowledge in there. And
what you've noticed about all of these
different websites I've shown you so far
is that they're all different types of
businesses. We had a content agency, we
had physical products, this one is a
consulting firm, and all of these have
different vibes. They have different
ways that the sections are actually
structured. This one has like a sidebar
over here. And we haven't seen that yet
on the other ones. Now, on top of
website design, I'm also talking about
things like motion graphics and design
using something like hyperframes. So,
let me play this example for you and pay
attention to the 3D elements and also
pay attention to the music and how it's
synced to what's going on.
and I'm not going to play this whole
thing, but it also created me a vertical
version. So, I'll play a few seconds.
Now, those obviously aren't anything
crazy. they're not going to go viral.
But if you consider that that was just
two prompts and took me, you know, 20 to
30 minutes, how much time would that
have taken and how much would that have
cost you if you paid a human editor to
do that? So much more time and money.
And here's an example that I think is
even crazier because what I had to do
here is for AIS Live, we have this
folder where we have like over 100
gigabytes. You can see 152 GB of footage
to look through. And all I did was give
it the link and I said, "Hey, create me
like a sizzle reel recap that's a minute
long from this event." And look what I
got. logged off yesterday just buzzing.
I had goosebumps. I was so excited and I
had so much fun.
Cost doesn't justify price. Price
justifies cost.
What is the value of what you know and
what you know how to do?
This culture that we have here at AIS is
is just really special.
So, the only thing wrong here is this
domain. That's not the real domain. But
I am just so impressed by this. And I
know some of you guys might look at that
and be like, uh, I saw some editing
mistakes or eh, whatever. But the music,
what it had to think through all of
that. It had to look through all that
footage and basically figure out how to
tell a story out of it. And I thought it
did a really good job at that. It also
had to look through all of our logos and
our designs and our branding and our
images and our assets for that. It found
everything and it pulled it all in. And
I was just like honestly for 35 minutes
is how long it took. So so impressed
because I've tried to do something like
that with Soul. I've tried to do
something like that with Fable 5.1 and
it did not go nearly as well. this thing
just has the understanding and it's so
pragmatic and logical about it that I am
just like seriously it's it's it's
another huge leap forward to me now when
we talk about actually killing AI design
slop or having things that really go up
to the next tier of course it's using
things like skills that you might find
on GitHub like mine or like other
people's but what I think is the most
important thing is inspiration it's
really hard to just give an AI model a
task like make me a website here are the
brand guidelines and have it just
actually create you something that
doesn't look very AI generated so what
you have to do is you have to have
inspiration and you can find that in the
form of something like godly.design
where you can find actual websites to
take inspiration from or you can find
individual components like the hero
sections or the CTAs or the footers and
you can find these components. You can
do the exact same thing on something
like 21st.dev. There are so many amazing
things here. Like I said, hero sections,
different components for the UI, you can
find forms, AI chats, you can find
buttons. Using all of these things and
giving these code blocks or giving these
website URLs to Astra makes them so much
better because now I could come into any
one of these 10 sites or the other ones
that we had generated and just be like,
you know what, I really like this, you
know, um, button for example right here,
but I would like this to be changed out
with, you know, this button that I found
on 21st. Because I feel like it's more
on brand or I like the, you know,
dynamic element around it. You can also
come to something like awards with three
W's, awards.com that has a ton of
award-winning sites. And you can also
come in here and organize by category,
which I think is really important
because an e-commerce site probably
needs to look different than, you know,
a restaurant and hotel site, which
probably needs to look different than a
fashion site. Because yes, there's one
element of AI slop where it's like, you
know, you've got those certain types of
buttons and the certain type of fonts
and the certain gradient in the
background. But the other element of AI
slop is when it feels like you're
looking at something that is meant for
someone else. If you're a 70-year-old
man and you're looking for medication on
your website and you're scrolling
through a 3D world, you're going to be
like, "This is the worst thing I've ever
seen." But if you're a teenage dude and
you're trying to buy new headphones and
the headphones on the site are spinning
and you can see inside of it and it's
like transforming. You're going to think
that's sick. And that's just the truth.
So think about the pain, think about the
person, think about the promise, and
think about inspiration sites. And then
you just get out of Astra's way. You
give it your brand guidelines, you give
it the copy, you give it scrollcraft
skills so you can create all of this
sorts of cool stuff. And then you watch
the site or you scroll through it. You
say, "Uh, I don't like this. Fix that. I
don't like this. Fix that." And then you
just keep iterating. And that's how it's
done. So CEX is probably the best
browser use agent I've ever played with
ever. And browser use is super powerful
for many things, which is what I'm about
to get into the next video about. But
basically, it just can control your
computer. Not only can it control your
computer, but it can also control
browser tabs and it can save sessions
and things like that. So, if you can't
use an API for some reason, maybe the
website you want to use or the service
you want to use doesn't have one, you
can use browser use. And like I said,
Codeex is just the best at it, at least
right now. So, I'm going to hop into the
next video with you guys about how you
actually can take advantage of Codex's
browser use. Codex's browser use is
probably the best that I've ever tried
before. It can literally do anything on
a browser or on your actual local
computer. And if you need to be signed
in for something, you just sign in once
and Codex will save it. So, the
possibilities are endless. You can
actually automate anything. Now, let me
show you guys how to set it up, how easy
it is, and a few good use cases. All
right, so I'm using the Codeex desktop
app, which is just honestly the main way
that I like to drive Codeex. It's super
super slick, and we get the browser to
pop up on the right hand side, which
I'll show you guys in a sec. So,
luckily, we live in a world now where
most tools that we need to use have an
API. So, it's much easier to just
connect codecs through the API, or if we
just go to the plugins, there's hundreds
of plugins in here. But every once in a
while, we don't have an API, and you can
do that with browser use. But before I
show you an automation like that, let's
just take a look at this example where
you might be building a website. You
might be building some sort of app and
you need a browser, an agent to actually
test through things. If you guys watched
a recent video I did on like building an
AI SAS in one day, then this was
actually from that demo where I had a
browser agent get spun up and test the
heck out of our app. And it did 85
focused automation checks with real
browser workflow testing, which means it
was clicking around, it was typing
things, it was hitting buttons, and it
was trying to break the app. And it
found a ton of bugs. and then we were
able to just fix them. So, in this
example, I have a super simple website
spun up here on the local host. It's a
form submission as you can see, and
there's a few issues before we actually
go ahead and start testing this thing.
You can see like this spacing is weird.
This thing is overlapping. And so, what
you can do is you can click on this
annotate button, and that lets you
choose very specific elements to
actually change. So, I can click right
here on this phone number box, and I
could describe, hey, this is kind of
like overlapping. It's out of bounds.
It's covering up the company box. So, I
need you to fix this. And then when you
shoot that off, it actually goes over
here into your chat. And then you can
make another annotation like, okay, so
this whole box isn't really aligned on
the same y-axis as number one and number
three. So you need to fix that as well.
And then those annotations are saved
over here and we can just go ahead and
shoot them off. So that's kind of like a
lovable style or like a claw design
style thing that you can do with the
inapp browser in Codeex. What else is
really cool about this is that you can
actually just drive this thing. So you
can go to Google, you can search for
Grand Canyon images, you can go to all,
you can go to different links if you
want. You can use the browser right here
while you have Codex open. But of
course, Codex can also just take control
of it. Now, we can see right here is my
mouse, but also this is what Codeex's
mouse looks like. And that's how you
know it's now sort of getting ready to
take control of the browser. Okay, so
now that those changes have been made,
let's actually start testing out our UI.
I want to see things that maybe me as a
human, I would maybe go through here and
test like five or six edge cases, but we
can see how Codeex can do it way quicker
and way more. Okay, so you have the UI
open. I want to make sure that there are
no bugs. I want to make sure that this
thing can't break. So, what I want you
to do is use your browser use and just
test the heck out of this thing. Try
different things. Try your best to break
it and let me know what bugs you find
and what things we need to fix. And so,
by the way, while this is running,
there's a difference between browser use
being headless or headed. Headless means
it's running in the background. So, you
can keep working in the foreground and
you won't actually see it going on, but
it can run a lot of things in the
background. But, if you want it to be
headed, that's basically where you're
able to see it. So, we're probably going
to be able to see some things right
here. But if you wanted this to just
work for a few hours for you headless in
the background, you could ask it to do
so and then it wouldn't disturb whatever
work you're doing. So if you ever hear
that terminology, that's what it means.
So there you go. You can see that the
mouse is moving around right now. It
tried to click continue and then it says
first name is required. Enter a valid
email address and enter a 10-digit phone
number.
And now you can see it just entered in
some information and it was able to hit
continue. And it's just going to keep
going through this QA check. We're
validating that some of these fields are
required options and that the continue
button won't actually let it move on
without filling those in. And by the
way, the reason you're seeing some of
these UI bugs is because I asked this
chat to like make there be a few UI
things to fix because I wanted to show
you guys the annotations. So just ignore
that. Mainly what I'm trying to show you
guys now is the actual browser use QA
function. So here you can see as it's
clicking around, as it's trying to
navigate this UI, it already said the
core click path mostly works, but I've
confirmed two real data integrity
problems already, which is that
obviously invalid contact data does get
through and changing the country code to
UK resets to US when you return to edit.
I'm now testing keyboard submission and
restart behavior, which often exposes
bypasses the click path misses. So think
about it like this. No matter what you
get, you're going to want to test it.
But would you rather have something that
has been not tested at all, or would you
rather have something that has been
tested 100 times already by an AI agent?
Especially if you tell the agent to try
to break it, it's going to find some
things that need to be fixed. No matter
how good you are at trying to predict
edge cases, when you push an app into
production and users start using it,
people are weird. People are
unpredictable, so they're going to do
things. And so this agent is able to
hopefully simulate weird humans and just
find things that you might not have
thought of. You can see here, it even
switched this to mobile view to still
make sure that everything's working. And
look at this. In mobile, it found a few
failures in responsiveness. So that
isn't something that I yet had tested.
Okay, so this thing finished up now. And
you can see that we have a bunch of
things that passed, but a bunch of
things that also failed. So it was able
to find all of these bugs because it was
testing the UI. And it didn't even do it
that long. If we wanted to make this
even harder, we could do a /go goal and
we could say, "Hey, don't stop until
you've tried a 100 different unique
scenarios of, you know, UI edge cases
and then come back to me." But it still
found a lot of things that were broken.
And now all we'd have to do is say,
"Okay, cool. go implement those changes,
go fix all those bugs. Okay, so let me
show you guys another example. This is
when you maybe have some sort of
platform where you want to be able to
like download statements or something,
but they don't have an API. So you can
actually interact with it with Codex's
browser use because it basically uses
vision and then AI to analyze like what
it's looking at and where to click. And
I would I just want to show you how easy
it actually is to build these. All I
said was, hey, you know, I want to build
this skill blah blah blah, what would be
helpful? And you could record a quick
loom. You could send screenshots with
arrows, but you actually don't have to.
you can basically just describe pretty
clearly what you need to do. So, what
happened here is it opened up Relay. I
signed in and it saved that session.
Now, I said, "Okay, in the relay
dashboard, you're signed in. What I need
you to do is go to the dashboard, click
on accounts, find the statements, um,
click on these two accounts, download
them as CSVs, and then put them into
this folder." And it was able to do that
on one shot. I didn't have to give it
any feedback and it downloaded them and
saved that whole flow as a skill. Now,
this is super helpful because now I
could at the end of the month just set
this up as a scheduled routine because I
could set a scheduled routine here and
say, "Hey, use this skill on the most
recent, you know, month statement in
Relay." And for the most part, Codex is
going to save your sessions when you're
logged in. However, there are some
limitations like the fact that Relay is
going to pretty much boot you out
because it's, you know, it's a banking
platform. It's going to be secure and
boot you out. So, look at this here. I
asked it to do this again and it said,
"Hey, relay is open at the login screen,
but you have to sign in again." Now,
what's really interesting that you can
do is you can actually open up your
settings. You can have a password
manager inside of Codeex and you can see
this goes to your browser and now you
can go to import them so that Codeex can
actually fill that out for you. And that
way, you're not putting it into the chat
history or anything like that. You're
saving it more securely. So, all you
have to do for that is create a CSV file
that looks like this. I've got the name,
the URL, the username, the password, and
any notes, which in this case are empty.
I imported that here right here as a
file, a CSV file. And now we have
relay.com password. Go ahead and try
this again in the password manager for
the inapp codeex browser. You should be
able to log in now and then run the
skill on June. All right. So over here
now you can see the browser has taken
control and it is going to put in my
email and my password. Now if this asks
me for a two-factor authentication code
for my phone or something, then I'm
obviously not going to be able to do
that. I'd have to do that manually. But
hey, if I was on a Mac and my text went
there, and I used computer use to do
that, technically, you would be able to
automate that whole thing. But I would
say you probably want to be careful
about stuff like that. But as you can
see, it was able to pull the passwords
from my password manager, paste those
in, and now it should be able to log in
to relay for me. You can see here that
the mouse has moved over to accounts.
It's then going over to statements, and
it's going to be able to download these
two statements for us. So, you can see
it's pretty cool that it was able to
figure all this out. Remember, I've only
ran this skill once, and all I did was
instruct it with natural language to do
this. Now, realistically, is that the
way you should do it, especially with
something like a bank account? No. What
you should do is have it do the skill.
You sit here and watch it and have it do
that like at least 10 times where you're
very closely watching it to make sure
nothing goes wrong and you're making
sure the script in the skill is super
strict because at the end of the day,
it's using vision, it's using AI, and
that's how it's deciding what to click
and what to do. So really the way that I
think about it is when you want to
automate something, your first call
should always be to go for an API. Like
that's what you want to do. It's the
fastest. It's usually the cheapest. It's
usually just the most consistent. Now,
if there's no API, that's where you
would maybe say, "Okay, cool. Well, now
let me see if I could use like a
deterministic, you know, like macros
script, right? And that's where you'd
basically be able to have Yes, you know,
it'd be more of a browser use because
you have a mouse that's clicking around,
but it's not like your mouse needs
reasoning. Your mouse doesn't need to
look at the screen, figure out where to
click, and based on the next UI that
pops up, where do I click again? This is
basically more like, okay, I have to
click on this pixel, then this pixel,
then this pixel every single time.
That's something that you could do for
much cheaper and much safer by just
programming a macro. And that's not that
hard either. You just ask Claude or
Codex, hey, help me figure out how to
make like a deterministic macro script
to just click on these pixels in that
order every single time. But if you
can't do that every single time because
there is an element of vision or
reasoning, then you need to come in here
and you need to do something like some
browser use. And luckily, Codex has your
back. I've tested a lot of different
apps and different CLIs and different
things for browser use. And so far,
Codex is just really solid. So, as you
can see now in my downloads, this is the
statements that it just downloaded as a
zip file and it basically took these and
it put it into my Herk 2 project. If I
go in here and I scroll down to
statements and I go to um probably June.
Yes, June. You can see right here, it
put those in here in the correct spot.
Okay, so that was an example where we
needed to save a password somewhere,
right? But I've done this with things
like school. I've done this with things
like X. I've even done this with things
like Instagram that don't make you
constantly resign in because it saves
that session. So, let me show you
another example. I'm going to go over
here to YouTube and I'm going to grab
the URL from the video that I uploaded
earlier today. I'm going to go back into
Codeex, paste in that URL, and say, I
need you to turn this YouTube video into
an X article for me. and then use
browser use to go ahead and um format it
and put it into an X article as a draft
and then I will go ahead and review it.
So, I know some of you guys are probably
thinking, why don't you just use X's API
for that? You can, but it's a little bit
weird with the formatting. It's also
weird with sometimes adding things like
media or thumbnails for some reason, at
least with my testing that I used to do.
And it's also it charges you, right?
Because you have to pay X per usage in
order to do something like that. And so
because this is just part of my codec
subscription, I can just run this skill
and it will go ahead and format
everything for me and take care of it. I
even have this skill worked out where it
can go ahead and open up my YouTube
videos and it can take screenshots of
specific moments and put those into the
article too where it makes sense. So
obviously this is a bit of a loaded
process because it has to do a few steps
before it actually has the article ready
to put into X. So while that's
happening, let's just open up a new chat
and let's see if our X session is there.
Can you open up a browser? I want to see
it right here in the app and just go to
X and scroll around a little bit and
show me if there's anything new that has
just come out um like in the AI space.
Just scroll on my X feed. And so because
this was a brand new session, we can
actually see if X is already signed in
and if it's able to interact with
things.
Cool. So it just opened up X. Let me get
my mouse out of here. You can see
clearly that this is already signed in
as me and my feed is visible and now it
is going ahead and it's starting to
scroll on the X page. So just start to
think about already how could you create
some sort of skills out of this and then
schedule these as tasks. So maybe every
morning if you wanted it to scroll
through Instagram and things like that
or scroll through your own profile or
mark things as red or unread, you could
totally go ahead and do that no problem
because you can set up the schedule
tasks right in here and use browser use
skills that you've already set up. So
you can see the two things that I
already noticed was Grockbot and Grock
4.6. So this is an interesting case
though because there is an API but using
the browser use is actually cheaper. So
that's why in this case we decided to do
it and test it out. Now what about
computer use that you guys have also
probably heard. These are basically the
same thing. It's still going to use
vision. It's still going to use AI. But
the difference here is that the browser
is basically things that are on the
internet or things that you would type
into a browser like Chrome. But the
computer use are things that might be on
your actual computer. So changing your
computer settings, opening up desktop
apps of things. So, let's go back into
codeex. While we're waiting for this X
article to finish up. Let's see how this
is going. It is still breaking down and
turning it into an article. Let's see if
we can do some computer use. So, one
thing you will have to do though is
you'll have to go to plugins and you'll
have to actually install computer use,
which is just as simple as typing in
computer use and hitting install like
literally 2 seconds. And then, hey
Codex, I need you to use computer use to
open up my desktop app for Glido. And I
just want you to go to the settings and
turn on the ability for it to allow and
use like Bluetooth devices. So, just go
ahead and get that set up for me. And
so, this is a little bit different,
right? Because it's not going to open up
your inapp browser. It's going to
actually kind of show your screen being
taken over. It said, "I'll stop if
Windows asks for an admin password or
presents a security sensitive permission
that it can't safely interpret." It
shouldn't run into any of that, but it's
good that it sort of has that guardrail
baked in. Interesting. Okay, so it said
Bluetooth access is a privacy
permission, so the computer use won't
let me actually do that, but what it
said it's going to do is open up Glido.
As you can see, I didn't open that up.
It opened up Glido for me. And it
doesn't look like on my recording you
guys can actually see this right now,
but my screen kind of has like a big
blue hue around the edges. So you will
clearly know if Codeex is using your
computer.
And there you go. You can see that it
actually turned on the include Bluetooth
devices button. And I think it got
confused because I think at first it
thought that I was messing with my
actual computer settings rather than
like an inapp settings. So it thought
that that was a security thing. But it
looks like it figured that out on the
way. And I think the computer use thing
is pretty interesting because you can
remote into your codecs from your phone.
So I can control all of these sessions
on my phone. And what I could do is on
my phone I could say, "Hey, computer
use, go ahead and change my settings or
go ahead and do something on a desktop
app that's on my PC that I'm actually
not sitting in front of." And then you
could control your computer from your
phone. So anyways, we're back in the
session where it's creating that X
article. You can see that it is actually
creating some thumbnails for the actual
article. So hopefully we're getting
close to the point where it's going to
actually open up X and start to put
stuff in there. But I'll check in with
you guys when we get there. Okay, so it
just decided to open up X. You can see
that it's going to the drafts in my
signed X and then it's going to will go
ahead and format this new article and
then we'll take a look. It's clicking on
the plus button. Man, I think it even
just like resized the page a little bit.
It was getting a little picky. In goes
the title and then it just pasted in the
entire content of the article. And now
it's uploading this thumbnail which I
don't think looks very good. that part
of the skill has not been refined at
all, but it's still cool that it was
able to make that thumbnail and then go
ahead and put it in there. So, I
literally just have to make sure that it
looks okay and I like it and I can
publish it. Now, I know what a lot of
you guys are probably thinking when it
comes to this browser stuff. It's like,
what's the point, Nate? Like, where's
the value? And honestly, I understand
where you're coming from. And that's why
I wanted to show you guys this piece
where it's like pretty much API will
handle 95% of your automation things
that you need. And then a lot of the
browser use opportunities might just be
a script, but then when you need it, if
you have this in your back pocket, it's
good. And you also might think, okay,
cool, but like how much time does this
really save? This probably saves me like
maybe 5 to 10 minutes, like
realistically. But what's cool about it
is that I can basically have this
pipeline now where I have a bunch of
these browser use skills. And so when I
need to do something, I just open up
codeex, I shoot off that skill, and I
can go back to the other task that I was
working on. It kind of just like helps
you do more without context switching as
much. And as you start to stack more and
more of these pipelines and combine them
together, you can get some really cool
things to happen when you start to chain
together these skills. And look, this
one actually did it. It basically did
the thing where I said it opened up the
YouTube video. It took screenshots of
it, and now it's going ahead and it's
planting some screenshots from my video
in the article. So, if that doesn't
prove the capabilities of this thing
being intelligent, take screenshots,
look at the page, know where to click,
know what to do, then I don't know what
else will. Besides the fact that I've
had this thing play chess, I've had it
play games. I've had it set a world
record on Tetris, it can do a lot of
cool things.
Look at this. You can see that it even
took the image and drugg it all the way
down to where it actually fits in the
article. I haven't actually seen it do
that before live. That was pretty cool.
All right, I hope you guys are enjoying
all of these use cases. This next one is
personally one of my favorites. I used
Codex to edit the intro for this video.
I use it to edit probably this course
that you're watching. I use it a lot and
my team also uses it a lot for courses
and for ads and for creative content.
So, it is one of the things that truly
helps us move really fast because
editing is no longer the bottleneck when
you can use a tool like Codeex,
especially if you've never edited a
video before and you don't have video
editing experience. So, let's hop into
this next section about how you can use
Codeex to help you edit some videos.
Stop prompting Claude. Andre Garpathy
thinks there's a much better way to work
with AI and his method has three layers.
Layer one is the spec. Instead of giving
Claude a task and hoping it understands
you, work with it to create a detailed
spec first. Have Claude interview you
about what you're actually trying to
achieve. Then break the work into
smaller checkpoints before it starts. So
Nvidia just made building with AI
basically free. They're giving
developers free API access to over 80 AI
models. Here's how you use it. Go to
Nvidia, choose the model you want, and
generate an API key. You can choose from
models like Kimmy, GLM, Deepseek, and
loads more. So, you want to start a real
business, but you can't afford people
for content, marketing, sales, and all
the other types of work yet because you
can now install AI agents for free. One
to help create content, one to help
follow up with leads, and other types of
agents to help handle the jobs that your
first employees normally would do for
you. Isn't it crazy that with just my
natural language, I can get all of these
crazy motion graphics right here, and I
can get all of these insane animations
over here as well. I can have subtitles
appearing at the bottom, like you see. I
can take my face and I can put it in the
bottom right corner, or I can bring it
up to the top left corner. And I can
even play you guys clips of a bunch of
my different YouTube videos right here
in this sort of 3D fashion. So by the
end of this video, you will know exactly
how to actually do this, even if you've
never really used codec before or you've
never edited videos before. So I don't
want to waste any of your time. Let's
just get straight into this video. All
right, so I hope you guys are excited to
learn how to do this. What you're going
to need is you're going to need the
Codex desktop app and you're going to
need to install Hyperframes. But I'm
going to show you guys all that. Before
we go through the setup, I just wanted
to show you a few examples of how I've
been using it and the skills that I'm
going to give you guys for completely
free. So this first example is just
having it help me edit YouTube videos
because what it's able to do is it
transcribes the audio and then it can
cut out mistakes and stutters and things
like that and you know dead space. So
for example in this one I gave it two
different recordings. I gave it my face
cam and I gave it my screen recording.
And this was a 14-minute video that got
cut down to 9 minutes and now it has
like the background and it also has a
few cuts. So let me just show you what I
mean by that. So here's the video. It's
not live yet but this is how it starts
off. Today I'm going over the 18 core
Codex concepts that you actually need to
know in order to start using it right
away and getting value from it. It
doesn't matter if you're not technical
at all or you've never used codeex
before. By the end of this video you'll
understand exactly how this thing
actually works so that you can start
using it right away. So as you can see
that first animation with the 18 cards
coming into the screen that was
hyperframes as well as you know codecs
here driving the actual edits, the
rounded crops, the background, all of
this. And so part one we're going to
start off here is foundations. So we're
going to kick off with concept number
one which is projects. Now a lot of you
guys I'm assuming have used chatbt or
claude in the now all of that logic was
once again hyperframes. It basically
created the card that said you know
number one projects. It then decided to
also zoom me in here because it realized
that for the next you know 10 to 15
seconds I might be talking about
something but I'm not showing anything
on screen. So, I prompted it in this way
and I gave it the skills in this way to
understand that when there's nothing
going on on the screen, maybe you do a
full screen, but then when it's time to
do more of a tutorial, you go back into
this view. So, anyways, throughout this
whole video, that's basically what it
does. It's able to jump between full
screen and this basically, you know,
template or scene and then it also
creates those cards in between each of
the concepts. There is like a transition
screen. All right, so that's one quick
example. Let's take a look at some short
form content which I think is getting
much much better. So, here I have it
doing two reels. One is about Claude and
one is about Nvidia. So, let me just
real quick play these two for you and
then we'll break them down. Stop
prompting Claude. Andre Karpathy thinks
there's a much better way to work with
AI. And his method has three layers.
Layer one is the spec. Instead of giving
Claude a task and hoping it understands
you, work with it to create a detailed
spec first. Have Claude interview you
about what you're actually trying to
achieve. Then break the work into
smaller checkpoints before it starts.
Layer two is the verifier. Before Claude
does anything, define exactly what a
good result looks like. Then give it
ways to actually check its own work.
Whether that's another AI model or real
data or tests that it can run on its
own. And layer three is the environment.
Build a workspace where Claude already
has your instructions, your knowledge,
your skills, and your rules every single
time you use it. So instead of becoming
better at writing prompts, you're
building an entire system around Claude
that makes it better every time you use
it. I made a full YouTube video breaking
down Karpathy's method and exactly how
to build this yourself. So just comment
method and I'll send it to you. So
Nvidia just made building with AI
basically free. They're giving
developers free API access to over 80 AI
models. Here's how you use it. Go to
Nvidia, choose the model you want, and
generate an API key. You can choose from
models like Kimmy, GLM, Deepseek, and
loads more. Then take that key and plug
it directly into whatever you're
building with, so you can experiment
with AI apps, automations, and other
projects without immediately racking up
API costs. And because they're OpenAI
compatible APIs, you can use them with
loads of existing AI workflows. If you
wanted to start building with AI, but
didn't want to burn your own money
testing different models, this makes it
way easier. So just comment key and I'll
send you the full setup. So I thought
that those outputs were really, really
solid. You can see that what it does is
it kind of starts off with like a visual
hook. I guess we'll go to the clawed one
first. We have the three missing pieces
and what it did here is it's kind of
creating that open loop because it's
saying, "Hey, yeah, you know, Andre
Carpathy uses it in this way and it's
creating this open loop of, oh wow, I
need to stay to the end of this short to
see what all three of these are."
Because as we go through, we can see we
have number one. We could talk about
little number one and then we go into
number two, the verifier. And then we
get into number three finally at the
end, which is about the environment. And
so about every one or two seconds here,
it's switching. You know, we've got some
scenes where it's like this with B-roll
up top and me down here. It's got some
where it's a full screen animation. It's
got some where it's full screen me. And
all these animations are sort of like
paper style. There's texture. It's 3D.
They're always moving. So, we're never
having one element be still. You've also
noticed that it went out and it got all
of this B-roll. It either created it or
it recorded it itself. And the
subtitles, it was made by Hyperframes
and Astra. The music, the sound effects,
all of this is being synced to the
actual reel for engagement. And pretty
much same thing with the Nvidia one.
This one was shorter, but it's a similar
style. This one has more green accents
rather than orange because it's about
Nvidia, but it has the same types of
animations. It has the same types of,
you know, scenes, and it has the same
way that it's fast-paced. It's always
switching. We have music. We have real
B-roll that it went out and it collected
on its own. And here's even more AI
generated B-roll that it created on its
own. I think that this is getting
really, really good. And I've turned
this into a skill. And like I said, all
of these are skills that come inside of
one sort of student kit is what I'm
calling it. So, if you want to get it
all for free, just go into my free
school community. The link for that is
down in the description. And then you're
going to go to the classroom and you'll
go to either AI skills or all YouTube
resources. I have it linked in a bunch
of spots, so it's really easy to find,
but you'll be able to find it right in
here in the AI skills section. It'll be
called like hyperframes student kit.
Here's another quick example. This one
is an AIS reel, and it made this one for
me in both um 16x9 as well as 9x6. But
let me just real quick play the 9x6
version for you guys because it's kind
of like a reel, but it's a little bit
different cuz this one was meant to be
an ad. What if you could build the team
before you hired it? So, you want to
start a real business, but you can't
afford people for content, marketing,
sales, and all the other types of work
yet? Because you can now install AI
agents for free. One to help create
content, one to help follow up with
leads, and other types of agents to help
handle the jobs that your first
employees normally would do for you.
It's like building your first AI powered
team before you hire your first
employee. And that doesn't eliminate
every future hire. It actually gives you
the capabilities to start before you
need them. At AIS Live, I'll show you
how to build your own AI OS, a
personalized system of agents, tools,
and workflows that helps you operate a
real business. You'll discover the most
important AI agents for starting a
company, and how to install them for
free. You'll also see how an AIOS can
support content, marketing, sales,
operations, and even recruiting as your
company needs to keep growing. So, if
you want to start a highly profitable
business without building a huge team,
then click below for more details on AIS
Live. Now, it has similar elements,
right? But what I want you to pay
attention to here is all of the B-roll
that it went and collected from me. It
grabbed YouTube videos of mine. It went
ahead and it grabbed past AIS live, you
know, segments. So here's one with me
and Pat. We can go into here's like a
VIP session. Here's a video of me like
talking about my iOS and a second brain.
So it was able to use the context of
what the ad was about. Here's a session
with Hyper Agent and Alex. It used the
context of what we were talking about
and it actually put it inside so that
this doesn't just feel so much like
theory. It feels more real. and even
animated this logo here at the end,
which I thought was just beautiful
because it had to go to my Google Drive
to find the AIS Live logo. And I think
that this turned out really, really
nice. And I'll play one more for you
guys real quick, which was a call to
action that I gave Codeex. Real quick,
guys, just wanted to say if you're
enjoying this video and you're enjoying
the way that I teach, please consider
subscribing and joining my free school
community. The link for that is down in
the description. We're building a global
community of AI builders and
entrepreneurs and business owners. We're
almost at 450,000 members. We're almost
at half a million, which is super super
exciting. and it would just mean a lot
to me if you joined. We have a lot of
resources in here. We've got agent
skills. We've got every YouTube video
where I give away free resources. Like I
said, skills, guides, templates, docs,
GitHub repos. I give it all away in here
for completely free. We also have a
7-day challenge. We have a build your
AIOS course. We've got a lot of fun
stuff going on in here. Events,
certification programs, tons of cool
things that we're building towards. So,
if you're enjoying it, if you like the
way I teach, please definitely check it
out. Hope to see you guys in there.
Let's get back to the video. Now, what I
liked about this is this one felt very
clean, right? It wasn't super
fast-paced, super energetic. There's low
music, but once again, it's proving to
us that it can go grab screenshots, it
can crop them, and it can use context
about me and my business in order to
make these feel more relevant. It
grabbed all of these different, you
know, skills and docs, and it put them
in here in a really, really nice way. It
even went and screenshotted some of our
courses from the community. It grabbed,
you know, event assets and pictures and
videos, and it just made this call to
action feel so much more real, so much
more human. So, if you guys are getting
excited by that, go ahead, like I said,
to my free school community and grab all
of those skills to be able to replicate
those sorts of outputs. But now, let's
actually get started with building this.
Like, how do you actually do it? And I'm
going to walk through a real example
with you guys. If you guys remember the
intro from this video, I'm going to
build that out live right now with you
guys. So, the first thing that I want
you to do is you're going to open up a
new project. So, I would just open up a
new folder in your desktop or something.
And we'll just call this one for now.
I'm going to call this um Hyperframes
demo. And that is the project that we're
going to be working inside of. So I've
got this folder on my desktop. Now I'm
going to come into here on the lefth
hand side and open up a new project. I'm
going to choose for this to be a local
project. I'm going to give this a name.
So Hyperframes demo. And then I'm going
to choose that actual folder so that
Codex can work inside of it. So that was
on my desktop and it was called
Hyperframes demo. Cool. So there's the
project. I'm going to select that and
open this up. So, when you open up a new
chat in this project, there's going to
be nothing in here. So, if I go over
here and I go to my files, there's
literally nothing here, but we're going
to start to fill this up with things
like video projects and different
renders and different files and things
like that. So, the first thing that I
want you to do is I want you to go to
this GitHub repo, which I will link in
the description. And this is called
Hyperframe. So, you're basically just
going to copy this URL for the
Hyperframes GitHub repo. You're going to
open up Codex, paste that in there, and
then basically just say, "Hey, Codex, I
need you to um basically pull in this
hyperframes repo so that I can um use it
to have you edit videos for me and
stuff. I need you to make sure that all
the dependencies are installed and
everything like that and, you know, grab
in some skills or things that you need
inside of this codeex project in order
to actually make this stuff useful." So,
that's the first step. You're going to
go ahead and shoot that off. Now, while
this is getting set up, let me talk
about the mindset and the idea of what
we're actually doing here when we're
editing videos with AI. So, there's a
few steps, right? And in this case, I'm
taking the example of we're giving it
some sort of footage and having it edit
it and animate it and things like that,
but it can also create things from
scratch. So, if you gave it um a rough
outline and you wanted just motion
graphics and like sizzle reels or like
SAS demos, it could do that 100%. But
that's not what I'm going to be focusing
on right now. You would just remove this
first step. So basically in my mind,
step one is you have footage and what
you need to do is you need to transcribe
it. And basically that means it needs to
find out all the text that you're saying
in that clip and exactly when it
happens, the exact second to the
millisecond of when you say certain
words so that it can sync it up with
different animations and different text
like subtitles for example. So
transcribing comes first. You can do
this with a free local thing that it can
set up like called whisper, but I
actually like to use 11 Labs for this.
So I'm going to show you how to set that
up as well. After you transcribe, then
the next thing that we want to do is we
probably want to cut. So, basically
having it cut out um you know, mistakes
or five seconds of silences and things
like that. So, that would be step two.
Step three then in my mind is to plan
the beats. That's kind of what it calls
our beats. So, beats are basically
different scenes. So, for example, with
this reel, like this install capability
slide, this is one beat and then like
this is one beat and this is one beat.
Every basically scene is a different
beat. So now what we like to do is we
like to have Astra, the model, read
through the text, understand the intent,
and start to plan out the beats of
what's actually going to go inside of
this reel or inside of this video. And
then what it's going to do is it's going
to use its, you know, skills, and it's
going to use hyperframes, and it's going
to use other tools like this in order to
actually do the generation of the HTML.
It's basically just creating HTML and
it's animating it. And that's what
really gives us all these 3D elements
and it gives us this text and it gives
us what we are basically looking at and
considering the motion graphics or the
motion design. And by the way, part of
planning the beats is like understanding
that there's going to be like, you know,
music that's going to sync to it and
sound effects and all of that is
basically coming into um this element of
planning. And the thing about it is we
have to have transcribed and cut all of
that first in order to be able to do
this properly. And then the last step
here is basically honestly it's kind of
a loop. So the last step is basically to
verify, meaning have the agent watch
through all of this again. It will watch
through it. It will take screenshots. It
will look at the transcript again. And
basically what we want to do is we're
going to do this loop of verifying and
then going back into here and using the
skills again and then verifying and then
using the skills again. So we get in
this loop of just going like this until
the agent is confident that everything
is in bounds and everything syncs
properly and everything feels how it
should. So that's kind of the flow.
Let's actually go get set up. So, we are
now inside of this project and it's
still getting everything set up. So,
what I want to show you what to do next
is we want to do um 11 Labs to
transcribe. So, you're going to go to a
new page. You're going to open up 11
Labs and create an account if you
haven't. You can get started on this for
like a five bucks a month plan, which it
it'll last you quite a while. So, you're
going to come in here and then what
you're going to do is you're going to go
on the bottom left to developers and
you're going to click on API keys right
here and you're going to go ahead and
create a new key. I'm just going to call
this um Astra demo. You can have this
expire. You could just leave this at
never. And then as far as restricting
the key, if you want to say, okay, this
key is literally only going to
transcribe stuff. That would be speech
to text. You could give it access to
speech to text. If you also want to give
it access to like sound effects and
music generation and image and video
generation, you can give it access to
other things as well. But right now, I'm
just going to start with just speech to
text because all we really need for this
endpoint is the um transcription. So,
I'm going to create this key. This gives
us basically a password. So, don't share
this with anybody. And I'm going to
delete this as soon as I'm done filming.
So, don't even think about it. But,
you're going to copy this to your
clipboard. You're going to go into
codeex and then we're going to come into
your files right over here. And you can
see now it's starting to build out some
folders and files and things like that.
And what you need is you need a file
called aenv which lets you store secrets
and passwords like your 11labs API key.
So all you have to do is just you can
chuck in a message even while it's
working here. And look it actually
opened up a local host which is kind of
how we can see our video projects. This
is just you know it just lets us test
them and look at them and even like move
elements around and stuff which is
really really cool. But I'm just going
to close out of that because that was
just an example. But what I can do is
say when you do the transcriptions I
want you to use 11 labs. So, can you
please create me availabs
API key in there? And also make sure
that you include this in the agents.md
that says whenever you know Nate wants
you to transcribe a video, use 11 Labs
for that. So, the agents.mmd is this
file. This basically just explains how
the project works. So, right now,
because there's not much information in
there, it just has some very basic stuff
from hyperframes. But as you start to
learn more about the way you like to
edit videos and the way you like to
store your projects, you'll basically
want to come in here and update it with
certain information. So right here you
can see it says, "Okay, I will add that
rule into the agent.MD so that in the
future I'll stop the whisper setup which
is that local thing that I talked
about." Now nothing's wrong with
whisper, it's just slower. And so 11
Labs, yeah, you have to pay for it, but
it's much quicker and I like that speed
and it's not that expensive. So now ourv
has a placeholder for the 11 Labs API
key. So, what you're going to want to do
is just paste in your 11 Labs API key
right inside of here. And by the way, if
it's not letting you paste or type
anything in here, um, which it should,
but if it doesn't, then you can just go
into here and click on open in default
app. And for me, that opens up in my
notes. I can paste in the API key. Hit
save. And then, as you can see, it's
going to refresh live right inside of
here. All right. So, at this point, we
have enough information in here to
actually be able to use hyperframes. So,
I'm not going to use my skills that I
mentioned that I showed all of these
examples where I use my skills. I'm not
going to use these right now because I
just want to show you what this kind of
looks like at its core. But don't forget
that you can definitely grab those
skills and come in here and make these
things better. And so one thing that you
can do is you can give it a video file
and just say, "Hey, edit this for me."
You know, add motion graphics, make it
tell a story, blah blah blah. Or you can
be very specific, which is what I'm
going to do for this specific example.
So let me pull up the video that we're
going to be working with. It's right
here. It's called edit intro. So let me
actually open this up and we'll give it
a quick watch. This is just my natural
language. I can get all these crazy
motion graphics right here. And I get
all these insane animations over here as
well. I can have subtitles up here at
the bottom like you see. I can take my
face. I can put in the bottom right
corner. Okay. Anyway, so now you see
that I'm basically planning out what I
want to happen as it's happening. So
here's what I'm going to do. I'm going
to grab the file path of my um video.
I'm going to come back into here. I'm
going to do a /goal prompt for this,
which basically just means that I'm
setting a goal and it's going to keep
pursuing until it hits that goal. I'm
going to paste in the file path of that
video and I'm just going to start
instructing what I want to happen when I
want it to happen. But first, I have to
set up the loop of transcribing,
cutting, planning the beats, and then
it's going to go ahead and get to work.
But instead of planning the beats, I'm
kind of directing this a little bit
more. So, this is kind of like
plan/accept beats. But anyways, let me
show you what this is going to look like
as I instruct this thing.
So, I've just dropped in a video for
you. This is going to be an intro. So, I
need you to help me turn this into a
super premium and polished edited video.
So, the first thing you need to do is I
want you to transcribe the video because
we need all of the beats and all the
motion graphics to sync exactly when I
say them. And then I need you to cut out
anything if there's mistakes or if
there's um you know, silence. There
shouldn't really be like a second or a
half second of silence. I want this to
feel fast-paced. After you've done those
two things, it's time to start actually
animating this video. So, let me tell
you what I'm looking for when it comes
to the animations. So, I start off this
intro by saying something like, "Isn't
it crazy that I can use just my natural
language to get all these crazy motion
graphics over here and all these crazy
animations over here?" What I want to
happen then is I want this whole vibe of
this video to be very, very like Apple
style motion design. So, like liquid
glass, clean animations, um, and they
feel very professional. So, when I say
motion graphics over here, I believe
that my hand was on it was pointing to
the left side of the screen. So on the
left third of the screen, I want them
from top down, sort of like my hands are
creating these motion graphics. I want
them to come into screen and just make
them, you know, against like some sort
of liquid glass card where we see three
different types of motion graphics.
Maybe like cards and documents moving
around or um laptop screens and charts
and elements that are being like
animated and things like that. Just make
things over here that are impressive and
that tell a visual story. And then
similarly when I go into the insane
animations over here as well that's on
the right side of the screen. So same
thing I want them to come in from top
down like I'm drawing them in. I want
these to be 3D. So I want these to be
against some sort of um maybe little
overlay in the back so that we can see
them against the background just like a
subtle dark overlay. And these should be
3D. So um they should maybe look like
they're spinning. They should have
shadows. They should have depth. And
these can just be 3D like letters or 3D
um animations and I don't know like
symbols that are moving. Just make
these, you know, subtle and
professional, but they should certainly
give some sort of like wow factor. And
for those two beats, I want them to stay
on the screen while I'm talking about
them. And then I want them to leave the
screen or sort of like fade away at the
same moment. So the motion graphics on
the left come in first, animations on
the right come in second, and then they
leave the screen at the same time. The
next section is pretty simple. When I
say I can have subtitles appearing at
the bottom as you see, I just want a
super super clean um overlay at the
bottom of the screen with subtitles,
they shouldn't cover um my face. So,
they should be sort of near the lower
third. And if you could just have the
words like subtly highlighted with maybe
like the words are white, but they're
highlighted in blue when I'm actually
saying them. So, make sure they're
synced exactly to the transcript when
I'm saying them. Now, in the next
section, I go on to say, you know, I can
take my face and I can move it to the
bottom right corner or um the top left.
And what I want you to do for that is I
want you to take my face cam and sort of
shrink it into like a um a vertical
rounded crop. So, you kind of just bring
in the left and right sides to keep me
centered. And you make it rounded crop
with a drop shadow. And you put it
against this background, which is the
full screen background. And so here what
I'm doing is I just pasted in this
picture which I like to use as uh my
background in some YouTube videos. And I
want you to make that background 50%
opacity so it's a little bit darker. And
then for the next part when I say I can
play you guys these um clips from my
YouTube videos, I want you to go to my
YouTube video directory locally which
I'll give you the file path too. So I
will just copy in this file path real
quick right there. What I want you to do
is just grab a few of my most recent
videos, maybe like four or six, and I
want you to sort of fan them out, like
animate the process of you fanning them
out, and have these be 3D with like a
little bit of a drop shadow, and they're
sort of like rotating and swiveling back
and forth just to create a really cool
effect. But I want them to actually be
playing throughout. I don't want them
just be static images of the videos. I
want you to just play, you know, all of
them are sort of actually playing at the
same time. And then to end off the
video, what I want you to do is
basically against that background I gave
you, if you could bring my main face
cam, sort of align it on the left side
of the screen, but make it bigger so it
kind of touches the top and bottom of
the screen, but we should still see the
rounded crop and the drop shadow. And
then on the right side of the screen, we
can just have some other text and other
motion graphics that tell a story based
on what I'm saying. So like um you know,
you don't have to be technical, you
don't have to have used codecs before,
you don't have to have a video editing
background. if you could just make
little icons and animate them in a fun
way to tell that story. And then at the
end, you know, it says like, "Hey, I
don't want to waste any time. Let's just
get straight straight into the video."
Do the exact same thing there. And
that's going to pretty much be the end
of this intro. After you have then done
all of that, I just want you to make
sure it looks good. I want you to sort
of like verify it by taking some
screenshots and looking through, making
sure that the beats actually sync to the
text that I'm reading out and make sure
that um everything's in bounds and
everything looks professional and it's
giving off the quality that you want it
to. I'm not looking for a PC or a
version one. I'm looking for a finished
product ready to go here. Out of breath
a little bit. So, that was a massive
prompt, right? That was me being super
super specific about what I'm actually
looking for here. And that's kind of
what this looks like to start. The way
that I got to all of these skills that I
now use for YouTube videos, lessons,
reals, ads, is because I did that so
many times. And now if you get an output
here that you really, really like, you
say, "Cool, that was awesome. Turn that
into a skill." And then next time, you
don't have to give such a big prompt.
You basically just say, "Hey, edit this
video. Use this skill." And then when it
comes back, if you have feedback, say,
"Hey, I didn't like this. Make sure you
do this next time." And then update the
skill, too. So, what I just did is
really the hardest it'll ever be. And
then it's always just about iterating on
those skills. So, I'm just going to go
ahead and let this cook a little bit. I
will check in with you guys when this
one comes back with the first version.
And hopefully it's what you saw in the
beginning of this video. Okay. So, I
have not yet watched this, but you can
see that this went from the original
being what was this? A little over a
minute, a minute and 5 seconds to now
being cut down to 28 seconds. Let's go
ahead and give this a watch and see how
this looks. Isn't it crazy that with
just my natural language, I can get all
of these crazy motion graphics right
here? And I can get all of these insane
animations over here as well. I can have
subtitles appearing at the bottom like
you see. I can take my face and I can
put it in the bottom right corner or I
can bring it up to the top left corner.
I can even play you guys clips of a
bunch of my different YouTube videos
right here in this sort of 3D fashion.
So, by the end of this video, you will
know exactly how to actually do this
even if you've never really used codecs
before or you've never edited videos
before. So, I don't want to waste any of
your time. Let's just get straight into
this video. Okay, not bad. Not bad for a
first pass. Um, you can see how my very
specific prompting obviously benefited
us here. I think that these look good,
right? Like we get some 3D animations,
we get some motion graphics. I like it.
I think that's a good way to start. I do
think maybe we need something more in
the first two seconds. Yeah, I think we
should add something right there in the
first two seconds just to make it more
engaging. But the other thing I noticed
is right here. It's playing videos,
which is good, but they're like inter
overlapping with each other, right? So
they it's not realistic. What we need to
do is make this feel more legit. And
also, I want to make this text bigger. I
don't think that text is big enough. And
I think this looks fine. This is all
simple. Nice little animation as well.
Basically, that's my feedback. So, let
us shoot off prompt number two. I'm
going to once again do another slash
goal prompt. Awesome. So, I mean, that
was 18 minutes. That was a really good
first pass, but let's do another version
here. What I want is a couple things.
First of all, in the first two seconds,
I want you to get creative here. Do
something that feels on brand
to make the first two seconds more
engaging. I'm not sure I want like a
full screen cutaway and I don't want
anything that's going to lay on top of
my face, but you know, I start off the
video by like, isn't it crazy that with
just my natural language, some sort of
animation, some sort of motion graphic,
make that a little bit more emotional?
Just do something right away to sort of
like hook the viewer in. Now, besides
that, the only other changes I need are
in the part where you show my YouTube
videos, you show the four. I like how
these look like they're 3D and they have
depth, but if you could make this more
realistic because they clearly are like
cutting through each other almost like
it's not realistic. We need this to be
more like the physics of it need to feel
better. So, if you could just maybe make
them thicker and make sure that they're
they're fanned out behind each other
rather than like cutting through each
other, that would be great. And then the
text on that screen, it says like your
videos or something. um if you could
just make that larger because that text
was pretty small. I want it to be bigger
and easier to read. But besides that,
everything else I thought looked really
good and it matched the transcript
really well also. So make those changes
please and then let me know when you're
done. So that is prompt number two going
off as another goal. And you can see
that this is the actual hyperframe
studio that it created for us. Um this
is at 107. Let's just reset that. And
what's cool is I can literally move
things in here. So I can actually take
this element and I could increase the
text size over here. I think font this
is where I would do it. I could change
this to what, like 80, and see how that
looks. So, it would reload and now I can
just sort of manipulate this stuff right
from here, which is pretty cool. You
know, you can move stuff around and um
you can see there's even different
elements for the actual like 3D scene
and the actual video inside. So, I'm not
going to mess with that right now. I
honestly don't use that interface too
much. But if you're editing a really
long video, let's say it's like a
10-minute video, and you just want to be
able to like tweak one thing really
subtly, it's probably easier to come in
here, make a little tweak, like just
move this over and then export it rather
than having to do the prompt layer
again. So, it's really nice that
Hyperframes gives you this local host
environment as well. But for something
as simple as what we're doing, I just
wanted to shoot off another natural
language prompt. So, I will check in
with you guys once this one has finished
up. All right, so that took 10 minutes
now and V2 has come back. Let me go
ahead and open this up full screen and
we'll give it a watch. Isn't it crazy
that with just my natural language, I
can get all of these crazy motion
graphics right here and I can get all of
these insane animations over here as
well. I can have subtitles appearing at
the bottom like you see. I can take my
face and I can put it in the bottom
right corner or I can bring it up to the
top left corner and I can even play you
guys clips of a bunch of my different
YouTube videos right here in this sort
of 3D fashion. Okay, so this was much
better. The text got larger and this
feels more 3D and it also just feels
like, you know, it just looks better.
And so right here, this is pretty much
the only section where I didn't tell it
exactly what I wanted. And this is what
it came up with. I don't honestly love
it. But for now, I'm just going to keep
it in because I told it I didn't want a
full screen takeaway, which would have
meant it created its own animation to be
the full screen. But actually, let's
just see what that would look like if I
just shoot off that quick prompts real
quick and say, "Awesome. Now, can you
create me one more version where in the
first two seconds before you cut into
like the motion graphics and everything,
let's see what this would look like if
you did a full screen takeaway." So, it
would be the full screen is animated um
against some sort of, you know,
background that feels on brand with the
rest of the intro and maybe the text is
sort of comes in in an animated way that
says, "Isn't it crazy?" So, anyways,
just going to shoot that off. This
really shouldn't take long at all, but
just to show you guys that it can also
do things like, you know, a full screen
cutaway and animate it in that way, too.
So, I'll show you guys that in just a
sec. All right, so that one came back
and it's done. And I have a feeling that
it's basically just going to be super
simple right here. I'll play it from
this interface. Isn't it crazy that with
just my natural language, I can get all
of these crazy motion graphics right
here and I can get all of these Cool.
So, that is looking good. We can see
basically all this did was just add some
very simple animated text that came in
here. It had a little bit of layering as
well with these little liquid glass
looking cards and it kept the background
consistent to what we actually used
later over here. So, I thought that's
pretty good. Anyways, guys, at this
point, we've set up the project. You've
set up something to transcribe if you
decided to use 11 Labs and you
understand now the loop that we actually
go through in order to do all this. I
didn't dive too much into this actual
interface and how you control it, but
like I said, it's very, very intuitive
once you get in here and it's a nice
touch by Hyperframes. So, don't forget
if you want to get this student kit that
has all of the skills that you need to
build these sorts of reels and videos,
you can download this for completely
free by going to my free school
community. The link is in the
description. You'll go to classroom and
click on AI skills and it will be in
there. Okay. So, now that you have a
really good understanding, at least I
assume, of how Codex works when you're
in it and you're sitting at your desk
and you want to drive automations and
drive, you know, skills and different
sessions like that. But what if you want
to build automations that run without
you being there at all? And I know we've
talked a little bit about scheduled
automations, but what if you want to
build things that live somewhere else? I
don't know if you guys have ever used
Nitn before or make, but what was cool
about that is you could just deploy
those automations in, you know, make
server or NEN server or something like
that. But what Codex lets you do is it
lets you build automations in code. I
know we don't want to look at code, I
understand, but it lets you build
automations in code and then you can
just deploy those automations somewhere
else. And now you don't have to have
your Codex desktop app open or you don't
have to have your laptop turned on in
order for those automations to keep
running all the time. So we're going to
talk about how you can use Codex to
build automations and then host those
automations in something called
trigger.dev. It is a lot simpler than it
sounds. So let's just hop into this next
video. Codex lets you build automations
right inside of it using scheduled
tasks. However, because these scheduled
tasks basically just send messages right
into an actual chat thread, what that
means is this eats at your actual weekly
usage limit. So, it doesn't really make
sense to build a bunch of your personal
and company automations inside of
Codeex. A lot of the most useful
automations can run somewhere completely
independently of codecs, but we can use
codecs to help us build them. So, that's
exactly what I'm going to show you guys
today. Even if you have no technical
background at all, by the end of this
video, you'll see how to build scheduled
automations or ones that are triggered
on some sort of event that live outside
of codec so they don't eat away at your
subscription. So, I don't want to waste
any time today. Let's just get straight
into this one. So, like I said, when you
have an automation running inside of
Codeex all the time, it's eating away at
your subscription limit. So, what I'm
going to show you guys today is how we
actually build our automations with
Codeex and then instead of actually
hosting them there, we're going to host
them in something called trigger.dev.
Because when we actually build the
automation, what happens is we can
actually just turn that into code. So
instead of having, you know, our
schedule task run a skill on a certain
cadence, it basically just turns that
skill into code that can actually be
executed and then that code is just
given from codeex to GitHub and then
GitHub basically says, "Okay,
trigger.dev, you're supposed to run this
code, you know, every hour or you're
supposed to run this code whenever
someone submits that form submission."
So if that sounds overwhelming or scary
at all, don't worry about it. It's going
to be super simple. Just think of it as
the idea that you're giving your skills
to something else to run it so that it
doesn't eat your codeex subscription. So
that way instead of your usage limit
looking like this, it will look more
like this one down here, which is green
and a lot more full. So what you'll need
for this video is a CEX subscription.
You'll need a trigger.dev account and a
GitHub account. That's what we're going
to be using. Okay. So there are three
different types of automations that I'm
going to show you guys today. And I'm
also going to explain the difference. So
it's going to be a scheduled automation.
We're going to have a web hook
automation. And then we're going to have
a codeex SDK automation. So let's start
with just number one. This is a
scheduled automation, which basically
just means we're going to have
trigger.dev dev execute our code that we
write on a schedule every 30 minutes
6:00 a.m. on Mondays however we want to
set up that schedule very similar to the
way that the schedule tasks inside of
codeex actually work. So the first step
of planning out the automation is the
planning. It means we just want to kind
of brainstorm with um Astra in this case
to help us make sure that it fully
understands what we want built and to
make sure that we're not, you know,
missing anything. We're not we're
thinking through all the different
scenarios. And yes, this example is
going to be very simple, but it's just
to show you how this actually works. So,
I want to build an automation, and I'm
going to put this on trigger.dev to
actually be hosted there. But you need
to help me plan this out and then
actually build it. So, the first step is
just the planning. I want this to be a
morning routine automation. So, this is
going to go off, let's say, 6 a.m., and
it's going to look at my calendar for
the day, and it's going to just give me
a brief. So, it will have to check my
Google calendar and it will just look at
the events I have and then if there's
any additional research or anything like
that that it could do to be more
helpful. It can just sort of help me
prep for the day. Is there anything else
important that I'm not thinking of and
do you understand how this will actually
be built out? And what's cool is it will
actually be able to use some of the
context that's already in your projects
if you are working inside of a project
because you can see the first thing it
said is I'm going to check your existing
morning routine workflow so that I can
actually understand a little bit better
how you want this built. So, trigger.dev
hosts something called TypeScript, which
is just basically a coding language. If
you used something like modal, then you
would be writing it in Python. So, don't
worry about this word. It just is
basically the language of the code that
we're writing, but don't worry about it.
So, it's explaining now how is this
going to work. So, the morning trigger
would go off at 6:00 a.m. America
Chicago time. And then we would look at
Google calendar and we would read
today's events. We would read their
descriptions and their times and their
attendees and locations. And then it
would decide whether the events need
prep. So, if it's with someone new, we
have this stuff that could be helpful.
if it's a podcast, we could have this
stuff. So, it's going to do a little bit
of AI reasoning here, and then it's
going to use AI once again to write the
short brief. And then after that, it
will send it to me, but I didn't
actually tell it where. So, it said,
"Where do you want this to be sent? Um,
what's the timing? What's the calendar
scope?" It's asking me some questions
here. So, all of these are good
thoughts. I want this to actually be
sent to me in ClickUp. I want this to be
sent to me as a DM to Nate Herk, so to
myself and ClickUp. And you will use the
Upit AI account to actually send this.
As far as timing, we want this to be
6:00 a.m. And let's just have it be on
weekdays. It doesn't really matter to me
how long it takes. If it if I get it at
6:05 or 6:10, that's fine. The calendar
scope, we're going to use my main work
calendar. And research boundaries, let's
just do public web research for now.
Later, we could always work in other
things like meeting notes and clickup
and Google Drive and things like that.
As far as the research, there's really
no reason why you should be spending
more than, you know, 25 cents for
research at this point, but we can
increase that later. Right now, let's
just assume that the calendar is locked
at 6 a.m. So, don't worry about checking
in later. So, now that I've given it
some more information, I will go ahead
and send that off as well. Now, what I
wanted you guys to notice here is
figuring out if the automation is one of
these two things, which are it's either
a deterministic automation or it's a
non-deterministic
automation. And so, what this means is
basically is it a predictable process or
is it unpredictable? And usually the
unpredictable automations when you get
into this territory over here, this is
when we really need to go for, you know,
a full agentic harness, a full codeex
routine because these are very
noneterministic. They're unpredictable.
And in this specific example, this was
pretty simple. We basically have, you
know, a 6 a.m. trigger. So we have 6
a.m. it goes off. Then what happens next
is we will read calendar. And so that is
the next step. And so far there's not
even any AI involved. where we start to
get AI is in this next step when we sort
of do like the decision-m on do we need
research and you know what would we do
so this is research and this would be an
AI step so I would fill in this with
green just to indicate that this is in
fact AI the other thing that we would
need AI for is drafting the message
because you can't really draft a message
um with code unless you were just using
explicit placeholders and it's not as
flexible and then the final step is to
send that message to ClickUp so what I
wanted you guys to see here is this is a
very deterministic automation because it
goes 1 2 3 4 5 oops five and it happens
in that order every single time. So that
is a deterministic flow. What's not
deterministic in here are these specific
AI steps. So step number three and step
number four are nondeterministic because
the research is going to be different
every time based on the input that goes
in. And then the draft message is going
to be nondeterministic because it's
different every time based on the
research that goes in. So these are
important things to think about because
the more deterministic your automation
gets, the more of a waste it would be to
use codeex to host that. There's no
reason to use the full Astra agentic
loop inside of codeex if your automation
looks like this. 90% of business use
cases or personal productivity use cases
are more like this. They're more of the
deterministic automations that help you
out and really save time. So anyways,
just wanted to call that out. Hopefully
you're learning some new stuff in this
video. All right guys, real quick break
for a message from today's sponsor,
Hyper Agent. Now, I know that a lot of
you guys are running AI agencies and a
very tedious part is teaching the same
thing over and over again to every new
client's agents because every client
wants it done a certain way. So, Hyper
Agent handles that with skills and
memories because you can teach an agent
a skill once like your due diligence
framework or your press release
framework or format or you know some API
that you always end up wiring in and it
will just keep it in its memory and then
it will build up memories as it works on
things like the client's preferences,
their data sources and how they want
things formatted. And then you can watch
the whole fleet from a command center
that runs eval rubrics and it can do AB
tests so that you can see which agents
are actually getting better and what
each client costs you to actually run.
They can also sit in your Slack channels
and they can jump in when something
needs doing instead of just waiting
around for you to ask. So if that sounds
like something that could be useful for
your agency, then check out Hyper Agent
through the link in the description and
you'll get some free credits to start.
So thanks again to Hyper Agent for
sponsoring this part of the video. But
now let's get back to it. So anyways,
Codex comes back and says, "Okay, cool.
That gives us a clear plan. Here's
exactly what we will do. Here's the
budget. Here's the research. Here's all
the stuff that's how it's going to work.
And now, let's actually go ahead and
start building it. It also calls out
this hosting detail, which is that
Trigger Dev's current free plan
scheduling window can delay a 6 a.m.
start by up to an hour. So, if we really
need this right at 6 a.m., you might
have to upgrade your Trigger.dev plan.
But, as far as getting started, you can
start on the free plan. All right. So,
sounds like you have a good idea of how
this works. What do you need from me?
Are there any different API keys that I
need to get, or do you already have
access to all of these keys? So that's
really the next step to be thinking
about because if you have been building
inside of codeex and you're using a
bunch of these plugins, so you've
connected to all of your accounts inside
of these codeex plugins, those will not
transfer over to trigger.dev, which is
why I really like to use plugins not
very much. I like to use thev file and I
like to put all my API keys in there so
that if I ever need to move them over to
cloud code or if I need to move them
over to trigger.dev, I already have them
in one spot and I can just copy and
paste them. And I will show you guys how
that works later. But yeah, now that
we've done sort of the hard part, the
heavy lifting of actually planning out
what we want, the implementation is the
easy part because now we let Codeex
actually go ahead and build this out for
us because as you can see, it says,
okay, it has access to Google Calendar,
ClickUp, OpenAI, Perplexity, and we will
obviously set up trigger.dev, but
basically everything we need to move
this over once Codex has built it is
already here. If you don't yet have your
API keys for Google Calendar or ClickUp,
you would just say, "Hey, can you help
me set that up with Google Calendar,
with ClickUp?" and it will tell you
exactly where to go and what to click on
and what to get. So getting API keys and
getting that set up is not really
technical. It's not really a technical
lift anymore. It used to be a little
more intimidating in the old days, but
now it's so easy. So if you don't have
API keys, just ask Codex to help you
find where those are and just go grab
them. But now we're ready to start
building. So I'm just going to tell it,
yep, go ahead and start building. And
I'll check in with you guys when we're
ready to move this over to trigger.dev.
But the one thing I'll say is before we
move it into trigger.dev, we want to
have Codex do as much verification on it
as possible. So, if it's able to test it
out and basically fix it before we move
it over, then that's good. You know,
we've talked a lot about giving agents a
way to verify their own work and telling
them to verify their own work so that
you're not getting their first attempt.
So, go ahead and build this out for me.
Make sure you feel confident in how it
works and you've validated that it will
work before you actually tell me we're
going to move it into trigger.dev and
then once you're done, we will move
everything over and host it. Now, you
can see what it's doing is it's building
it out and it's testing it. You can see
it's using test-driven development. It
is sending DMs. It is looking at how
much all this costs and it's basically
optimizing for what I actually said. It
even made sure that the DM was the
correct conversation. And the reason why
this whole deterministic or
nondeterministic thing is important to
understand is because yes, you could
easily do this as a routine inside of
codeex, but I actually did this before
where I had a routine that was very
simple like this and after about a
month, it started to just go rogue. It
just randomly started to send to
different DM channels and it started to
send to like the team channel and stuff
like that. And the reason for that is
because it was an agent on the back end.
the agent was just interpreting the
message different every time and it just
acted differently. But what we're
actually building here is we're building
a script so it doesn't have the option
to act differently. We're literally
saying, "Hey, this is what runs and it's
goes the same way every time." So in
this code, we're basically like hard-
coding the direct channel with the
channel ID and the message ID and
everything that gets sent rather than
giving the agent the full connection to
ClickUp and saying, "Hey, just send it
to Nate." Anyways, this has just
finished up. So you can see, whoops,
that it was built and validated locally.
And we should have a test brief in
ClickUp. So let me check that real
quick. Awesome. So you can see right
here that I do have this DM where I see
my Tuesday morning briefing. I have my
day right here. Every single one of
these things has a link to my calendar
as well. If I click on this, for
example, it pulls up the actual event in
my calendar. And then it also comes back
with, hey, here's some useful prep. And
here are some things to notice. So we
know that the ClickUp connection works.
We know that the AI is working on the
background. And we know that the Google
calendar connection is working as well.
And it says that everything has been
built and validated. And this costed
about 1.33 cents. So us giving it the
gate of, you know, maxing each run at 25
cents seems pretty realistic. Anyways,
now we have to deploy to trigger.dev and
validate one run there before we turn on
the schedule. And the cool thing about
this is yes, you're going to be able to
follow this tutorial so you know exactly
how to connect to trigger.dev, but if
you didn't, so how exactly do I get this
automation from the code that you built
into trigger.dev? And while it's doing
this, let's go ahead and make sure we
have a trigger. So, head over to
trigger.dev. Go ahead and create an
account. Like I said, you can get
started for free. Now that I'm in here,
you can see I'm on a free plan in this
account and I just created a new project
up here called YouTube. And this is what
it will look like in order for you to
sort of like get everything set up.
There's nothing yet in here. So, this is
how it gets really cool because we're
able to basically just connect codeex to
trigger.dev and it can basically talk to
trigger.dev in order to do all of this.
Now, you can also have it connect to
GitHub, which is something that I do
recommend because that way GitHub
connects to trigger.dev and the three of
them talk together. And the reason why
we like to use GitHub is because then
you can have like different version
control and you can have other people
more easily contribute to the automation
if you need someone else to change it or
something like that. And Codex can
connect to trigger.dev and GitHub via
the command line tool. So, that's what I
would probably say next is let's get
connected to GitHub and trigger.dev dev
via the command line and then we can
just push our code to GitHub and then
trigger.dev will sync with that code.
And what this will do is it will use the
CLI and it will prompt you to just
authenticate in. So it will do one of
those things where it opens up the
browser, you sign in with GitHub, you
sign in with trigger.dev, and then you
come back into Codex and it says boom,
got it, I'm connected. So here is the
trigger.dev authorization. I just have
to go ahead and authorize right here.
And then it says return to your terminal
to continue. So Codex should have gotten
that now. And you can see that because
my codeex is already authenticated to
GitHub, I didn't have to do that. But it
would be the same exact flow if you
haven't done that yet. So now I want you
to create a new private repo for this
automation in my GitHub account. And I'm
just going to shoot off this message to
steer codeex in the right direction now
that we know we're connected to these
two tools. And you can see that it says
the API keys, the calendar snapshots,
and anything sensitive are excluded from
Git. Even though we're creating it as a
private repo, it gets completely
excluded. And that's the whole point of
the env. So, what we'll have to do in
trigger.dev is we will have to manually
move those over. And look at this.
Because Codeex's browser use is so good,
it also pulled up my trigger. account in
this browser. So, if there's anything
that you're confused about navigating
the trigger interface, you can have it
help you out by just clicking around
right in there. But, it says that we did
create this GitHub repo for the morning
brief. So, basically, this repo, just
think of it like a Google Drive. It
holds the actual code and the rules for
how this automation runs. And
trigger.dev will grab this and actually
host it. So, it's super simple. But also
if you make different versions you will
update it here. So you could roll back
to previous versions if you want and
that way if a team member later wants to
take over this automation all of the
details are here and they can contribute
to this project. Okay. So take a look at
this. It actually created its own
project in my trigger. So it said in
morning brief and settings and git is
the GitHub repo connected. So basically
what that's saying is okay it got into
my trigger.dev. You guys saw me create a
new project called YouTube but it
decided okay I'm going to create my own
project. So it made one called morning
brief. And now what we need to do is we
need to see if this trigger.dev project
is connected to our actual GitHub
codebase called morning brief so that
they can sync and talk to each other. So
that's what it's asking me to verify. It
said to go to the settings in here, but
you can see that it says GitHub isn't
connected. So it's actually not syncing
to anything at all. So what I need to do
maybe is install the GitHub app. But
let's see. I'm just going to say I don't
see any deployments. I don't see any
integrations. When I go into
trigger.dev, it tells me that GitHub
isn't yet connected. So that's what I
see. But this is really cool, guys. You
can see how proactive this thing is. It
actually just went ahead and started
doing all of the connections rather than
telling me what to do, which is pretty
cool. But every once in a while, it hits
a snag and it will just tell you, hey,
can you check this? Can you check this?
But hopefully with this context, it's
going to be able to help out with that
now. And now you can see it's going to
open it up to actually do it itself. So
you can see the mouse right here moving.
This isn't me. This is Codeex using its
browser use to check on all this for us.
Okay. So you can see that this says
connected and verified and morning
delivery remains disabled until the full
hosted delivery test passes. So that's
good. And it actually moved it back
under the personal account where the
GitHub connection already exists and
ClickUp still uses UPAI. Now let's go in
there real quick so I can show you guys
something. If I go back into the other
project and it actually did it in a
different org. So if I go back to my
personal org, this is where we should
see the morning brief. There we go. So I
was just looking at the completely wrong
one. And if I go to tasks, this is where
we can actually see the interface of our
weekday runs. And what's cool is it did
two different tasks. It did the
scheduled one. So this one you can see
is the one that goes off at 6 a.m.
Monday through Friday. And then what
actually happens when this runs is it
calls this other I guess runner. So it
calls this and this is the one that has
the actual process in it. So it does it
in two parts. And that's pretty cool
because as you create these longer, more
complex workflows, they call individual
tasks and pieces that codeex will build
out for you and it just helps with some
visibility. So anyways, what we can do
here is if I go into the schedule and I
hit test schedule, this basically starts
running this. So I'll hit run test and
now this runs in production. And then
what you can see is that it actually
calls this other little task. And now
this thing is running. It's showing us
how long this is taking. It's going to
show us all these little different
details so that if this errors, we could
copy all this data, give it to Codex and
say, "Hey, this is what happened. Help
me fix this." So, you can see that this
already finished and we can look through
the payload. We can look at the status
which came through as disabled. And
you'll notice that I didn't get a new
DM. So, we have to figure out why this
didn't seem to work. My first thought
would be, okay, well, do we have all of
our API keys and all of our secrets in
here? And if I go down to deployments,
this is where I can click on environment
variables. And you can see that we have
a bunch of stuff in here that got added
today. Today's September 15th. So Codeex
actually took our ENV and via the CLI
put everything in here, which is
awesome. So we should have our ClickUp
ids. We have our workspace ID, client
ID, all of this stuff should be working
in here. So what I would do is I would
say, okay, so I just ran a test run
inside of trigger.dev, but I didn't get
a ClickUp message. I didn't get
anything. Can you just check and see
what happened there? So you guys
remember how it came through and said
status equals disabled. It's because it
had morning brief enabled as false. So
if I go back into our trigger.dev and I
go to our environment variables, you can
see right here, morning brief, it says
false. So we would basically have to
come in here, edit this, and we would
have to change this to true. Hit save.
And now if we go back, let's see if this
fixes the issue. So I'm going to go into
the morning brief weekdays and hit test
and go ahead and run that. And there we
go. This looks a little bit different
now because you can see it called on our
different runner. We can see what's
actually going on. And we can see this
thing actually in real time sort of like
playing out. We got a little bit of a
green message here. We get output equals
delivered. Let's open up my ClickUp.
See, was this a new run? Okay. Well,
unfortunately, this still doesn't look
like it was a new run. So, once again,
we have to go figure out why this didn't
work yet. Because if you guys remember,
it worked when Codex was testing it
locally, but it didn't work yet in
production. So, okay, that run seemed to
work. It showed that we actually got the
output, but I didn't get any DM in
ClickUp. So, take a look at that run and
help me figure out how do we fix this.
Okay, that's really interesting. What
happened was the run found today's
earlier test message. So, it skipped
sending a duplicate because it would
have been essentially the exact same
message. So, it seems like that run
didn't actually fail. It was more so
done by design. You can see the existing
message was sent at 12:01 and we just
tried to run a new one at 12:33, so it
didn't get sent. That's why it's always
important that when you're having AI
build you automations and build you
code, you don't have to know what every
single line is doing. But you do have to
test the stuff out to figure out how it
works and why it does what it does. I
mean, look how powerful this is. It's
basically able to deploy everything,
debug everything, move around in the
interface, and then just test it all for
me. And we're just using our natural
language, and we're using our intent to
drive all of this. This is so much
quicker than the way I used to have to
build automations. it worked in this
variable that shows that if it was
already delivered and it got triggered
twice for some reason to not send a
duplicate message. So duplicate
prevention remains intact. I think it
did a really good job there. But I do
want to prove to you guys this works. So
I'm telling it to override that just so
we can see that it works as expected.
And then we'll move on to the next
automation. There we go. We can now see
that we got the hosted proof test for
the morning brief. And now we can feel
better about turning this thing on
inside of trigger.dev and knowing that
it will actually have all the
connections set up because we've seen it
in here. We've tested it. We know that
all of the environment variables are
also moved over. So, we are all good to
go. All right. So, we took care of the
scheduled type of automation. Let's look
at one that is triggered by something.
So, typically this is triggered by a web
hook. So, we're going to go back into
Codex and we're just going to start
having it do two things for us. It needs
to build sort of like a very simple
front end that will actually be our
trigger for this specific example. And
then we'll build the back end, too. So,
I'm actually going to try to do this in
one fell swoop. I'm going to do a slash
goal. And here we go. So now I want to
build a web hook triggered automation
inside of trigger.dev. So this is kind
of a two-parter. The first part is we
need to use or sorry I need you to help
me build just a very simple local host
that is sort of like a form submission
that you might see on a website.
Collects information like the name, the
email and um team size and what they're
looking for. So, a simple landing page,
a simple form that we can fill out, and
then when the user hits submit on that,
that's what I want to trigger the actual
automation on the back end that we're
going to build and put in trigger.dev.
So, basically what I want is for um that
automation to just send me a ClickUp DM.
So, same DM as before, and I want this
one to just say, "Hey, you got a new
form submission. It's for this person.
Here's what they asked for, and here is
how I recommend you reach out to them."
So, sort of like just creating a draft.
So, I'm going to shoot that off and it
might have some questions for us. But
this is a very simple use case just to
show you how it works with a web hook.
But this is still a very much a
deterministic automation. Even though it
is AI, it is still deterministic. So,
let me show you real quick what this one
looks like. This one is a web hook
trigger. So, this is just going to be a
form submission. That is basically what
kicks this thing off over here. From the
form submission, what happens is it's
going to actually read the form and it's
basically just going to have to do one
thing, which is create the actual um
message that will go to us in ClickUp.
and then it will basically send it to us
in ClickUp. So, it takes a very similar
shape as to what we've already seen,
except for instead of going off on a
schedule at 6:00 a.m., it goes off based
on the actual action which is triggered
by us. And then once again, the only
time we actually see AI inside of this
process is just here. Now, you could
actually do this with no AI. If you
wanted the form submission to just shoot
you a message in ClickUp, you could do
it with placeholders and you could do
that. you'd save yourself some money and
some time because there'd be no AI
message or sorry, there'd be no AI step
and that would be 100% deterministic
every single time. Now, obviously, there
are some edge cases you might want to
think of. You know, how do you build the
form so that they can't, you know, spam
it a thousand times in a second? How do
you build the form so that if you're
expecting an email field, you're
actually going to get only email fields?
There's a lot of other edge cases to
think through. But what's cool about
that is after you build this, you could
say, "Okay, cool. Now, spin up 50
different sub aents and have all of them
test this thing, try to break it, and
then let me know what you find." and you
can really stress test and QA your own
automations before you actually have any
sort of human or customer find these
bugs or anything like that. So, that's
pretty cool. It's going to spin up a
local page. It's going to use the
existing trigger.dev deployment on the
back end. And now, because we've already
set up the connection with like GitHub
and trigger.dev, all of the automations
we want to build in the future are going
to be much much easier. So, I'm
basically just going to check in with
you guys when this one is done and show
you how that works. Okay, so it says
that this is done. You can see that we
have this form here to fill out. It says
that it has built and verified this end
to end. So submitting it now will start
the hosted trigger. Task. It will
generate the outreach recommendation and
it will send everything to ClickUp. So
let's go ahead and real quick check in
trigger.dev. We do have this new one
right here. I'm going to refresh just in
case. And you can see that we have this
new one called form submission. It has
already been triggered a few times. It
looks like actually let me just zoom out
so that we can see this better. It has
been triggered five times. So this was
Codeex testing it. And now let us go
ahead and test it ourselves. So, I'm
going to go back into Codex. I'm going
to fill out this form. So, we're just
going to say Alex Morgan, Alex
company.com.
Team size, we will just put 20 plus. We
are spending so much time on, you know,
making hamburgers and it's just becoming
a real bottleneck. So, I'm looking to
see if we can automate that. And let's
go ahead and shoot that off. What do we
get on this front end? Your request is
in. Let's go back to trigger.dev. Let's
see if we get some sort of run. I'll go
back to the tasks. We should see it
looks like there's a new one executing
right now. If I click into this run, we
should see that all of this is actually
going on. So that proves that this web
hook has been set up correctly. Now, in
the old days, we would have had to set
up the URL and kind of sync them
together and like build out the payload.
But we don't have to do that at all and
it this is the payload basically like
the information that comes through and
now we have the output. Let me check and
see if we got this in ClickUp. Sweet.
Okay, so we actually got a lot of these.
These are all of the demo examples that
it tried, you know, the new form
submissions. But this is the one that we
just submitted. You can see right here,
Alex Morgan. Here's the email. Here's
the team size. Now, this took no AI.
This is what I meant when I said that
this could be just placeholders. So, if
you wanted just to just get this
notification, no AI needed. But here's
where we needed AI, the recommended
outreach and the email draft. And this
is what had to be obviously generated
with artificial intelligence. So, that's
kind of the trade-off there. But, super
simple, super easy. That took me no time
to build. And I barely had to do
anything as far as like wiring things up
by hand. So, that is a web hook
automation. That doesn't obviously have
to be just a form submission. That can
be a new record in the CRM. That can be
a new email entered the inbox. There's
so many different event-based triggers
that you can have for a web hook style
automation. By the way, guys, I've got
this completely free SOP for you about
getting your first aation client. It's
going to go over the exact steps that
has been proven for hundreds of our AIS
Plus members to get their first paid
gigs. It goes over the one sentence
service pitch that can get you started
today. Why your first client should cost
you money. The five-minute video that
answers, can this person actually
deliver before you've actually received
any money, what to do when you have zero
case studies. There's so many good
things in here that are going to help
you out. Even if you already do have
clients, I would recommend grabbing this
because, like I said, it's yours
completely free. So, if you want to grab
this, there's a link for it down in the
description. Let's get back to the
video. All right. And for this last use
case, now that we've done the web hook
as well, this one's a little bit
special, and this is when you kind of
want that full agentic loop that you're
used to getting inside of codeex, but
now you're getting it programmatically,
and that is through the codeex SDK. So,
a really good opportunity to see if you
want to actually use the Codex SDK is
when you need to bring something that
might be an already existing routine
into something like trigger.dev. Now the
thing about this is most of the time if
you're running an automation in a
scheduled task inside of codecs, I would
recommend you keep these as a codec
scheduled task because then it actually
eats away at your subscription. But if
you need to do this at scale and you
can't use your subscription
programmatically, then you probably want
to build the automation with the Codex
SDK and then host it on something like
trigger.dev. So if that ever does become
the case, you kind of get the full
agentic loop. So here is what that might
look like. We saw these first two
examples. Now, what I'm going to do here
is this is going to be a scheduled task.
So, we're just going to call this
actually let's just call this every 30
minutes. And I actually do this for real
inside of a a scheduled task inside of
my codeex where 30 minutes it wakes up
and we basically just have this full
agent. And what it does is it basically
it looks at my I'm just going to call
this an agent because it does a lot of
things. It looks at my alpaca account
and actually let me just like go down
here and make some tools. Just pretend
that these are tools. So, it has to like
check alpaca, which is where I have like
some trading going on and my agent here
helps me trade. It will also, you know,
like do research. It can also just like
look at like past logs and stuff like
that. So, it's leaving logs for itself
every time so that the next time the
agent wakes up, it's not completely
stateless and just like doesn't know
what to do. So the reason why this is
the SDK rather than just being more of
like one of these deterministic AI
automations is because we don't know how
many times it might need to look at the
logs and read things or look at the
research or check back in in alpaca if
it's doing research for 10 minutes and
it's like wait let me just check the
current holdings one more time because
things may have shifted this it it has
the ability to basically just go back
and forth you know it can go like this
and then this and then this and then
this and then this and then this and
then this and it's basically an agent
and it has that luxury and then what
happens is It essentially just sends an
email with a recommendation. So, I'll
just call this email. And it sends that
to Grockbot. And then Grockbot actually
places the trade because OpenAI models
and cloud models don't actually let you
trade anymore. They just won't do it. I
think it's cuz all this security stuff
is going on. But Grock still lets you
trade. So, my Grockbot is the one
placing the trades and Astra is doing
all of this heavy lifting research. Now,
yes, you could do this exact same sort
of thing in a deterministic flow, but
that would just look different. It would
basically be a predetermined amount of
research. So, for example, it could hit
like a research step or maybe it hits,
you know, two research steps. So, I'm
just going to like sort of demonstrate
this like this where maybe it does two
different like research sources. So,
maybe this one is firecrawl and this
one's perplexity or something. And then
it basically will send it to an agent to
um look at the research and can create
the draft, create the email and then
send it off. But what if it looks
through this and it's like, "Wait, I
want to do some more research." Because
now the AI agent has analyzed it and
it's like, "Wait, let me do some more."
We would have to work in somehow the
ability for the agent to loop back and
do more research. And that's essentially
why we would just use something like
this where we're now using the SDK to
give us that sort of autonomy. So, let's
go ahead and build that out real quick.
Now, this would be a very similar
process where I would like you to say,
"Hey, I want you to interview me about
this process. I want to get very clear
on what this does." Especially the more
autonomous your systems get, there's
more room for error. There's more room
for, you know, you're increasing the
risk, you're increasing the cost, you're
increasing complexity, you're increasing
the maintenance, you're increasing a lot
of things. So build the simplest
solution possible and only move up the
sort of AI systems pyramid as I call it
when you truly need that functionality.
So I would go through this whole process
of interviewing to get what I want. But
we have this luxury here of all of this
is already set up because we have these
routines going. You can see that I have
this um thread called challenge thread
where I'm doing this actual trading and
you can see that every like 30 minutes
or so it's basically just starting this
routine and it's doing the whole agentic
loop. We see that one is actually
running like right now and this is the
this is codeex. This is codeex working
and we're basically just trying to move
this over to trigger.dev. Now I'm not
really wanting to I obviously want to
keep that using my subscription but for
the sake of the demo. So what I need you
to do now is I want you to build me a
codeex SDK automation and we're going to
host this inside of trigger.dev. dev.
Now, what I want to do is I basically
want to transition the Astra trading
challenge, that thread, I want to move
that routine over to trigger.dev. So, we
basically wake up like every 30 minutes
during trading hours, one check before,
one check after, and we do this research
loop. We check Alpaca, we check the
logs. So, familiarize yourself with that
actual process, and then just turn this
into a Codex SDK automation for me and
host it in trigger.dev. Let me know if
there's anything else that you need to
build this. So once again, the hardest
part is already done here, and now we're
just going to get that built out. So
I'll check in with you guys when this is
all done. Okay, so this run took about
15 minutes, a little over 15 minutes.
And we can see now that this is ready
for our review. It did 44 passes or 44
tests and it paused the old desktop
routine, which I'm going to say, you
know, I don't want it to pause that.
This was just a demo. So anyways, um it
was being pretty proactive there,
though. But anyways, what it did is it
made a new project. So it created a full
new one rather than what we were doing
earlier. And I'm actually just going to
open this up full screen in my desktop
over here. Give this a quick refresh.
You can see what it did is it basically
made a few different like tasks or
runners or whatever you want to call
them. And they kind of call on each
other. So you can see here there's the
check. This ran 18 times. Um then we
have an install plan. We have a
pre-flight and we have a proof. So I'm
not exactly sure the right order to run
this in, but this is what it did. And if
I go to the runs, we can see exactly
what happened. So it basically runs, you
know, these failed, these completed.
We've got these checks. So what we're
going to want to do is we're going to
want to figure out what does each one of
these do? So I'm going to go ask um
Codex that real quick. So I can see that
you actually created four different
tasks. We've got a check, an install
plan, a pre-flight, and a proof. Can you
just explain to me what these are and
how they work together and how these use
the codeex SDK to give us sort of that
full agentic loop that we're looking for
here? Okay, so Astro check is the actual
recurring worker. that is the one that
should fire on the schedule. The other
three help it do things. So the
pre-flight checks the codeex runtime,
alpaca connection, SIP market data,
policy files, and the checkpoint
storage. And it can optionally make a
small model test call. So this really
only needs to run during setup or
troubleshooting. We have proof, which
runs the full research and reporting
workflow, including the the test label,
email, and clickup delivery. It prevents
actionable trade tickets during the
test, and this will run before enabling
the routine. currently disabled after
verification, the install plan during
setup, and then the check at each
scheduled check. So, it's actually
interesting. It made all of those to
help it build and to check. But now, I'm
not sure because each check now follows
this process where we have it loads up
the context. It asks codeex what needs
investigation. It finds the evidence. It
has Codex evaluate all that. And this is
with the SDK, of course. It validates
and delivers, and then it saves the
handoff. So the agendic part is Astra
choosing what to research using web
tools, doing deeper evidence, and
adjusting its conclusions based on the
result, which is pretty interesting.
This is the only one that will actually
run now that this is all built. So I'm
going to go back into here and we're
going to go to Astra check and we're
going to hit test and just test this
thing out right here. Now look at this.
It just called this attempt right here.
And we open this up, we can see
everything that's actually going on. Now
this is pretty cool. The reason why this
did nothing is it actually sent this
payload over which was like the time and
the date and then the output was hey
this is early because this was set up by
Astra in a way where it's supposed to
check in during market hours and right
now the market has already closed. So
the next scheduled run isn't until
tomorrow morning before the market
opens. So that's why it basically fired
and it was like oh you know this
actually isn't right. I'm not supposed
to run yet so I'm outputting the word
early. But I do know that this works
because if I go into my ClickUp thread
where I'm actually getting these
notifications every day from the actual
routine, you can see that these started
to come in. You can see we have the test
migration here, 341, 347. We have
another test migration for Nate's
review. It's doing the research. It's
giving us assessments. It's linking
things. It's looking at our account.
It's pulling in all the sources. It did
another one at 352 for the market close.
So, this is currently working. And what
it's actually doing is it is messaging
Grockbot. This is my trading Grockbot
that actually places these, you know,
trades based on getting an email. So
everything transferred over to the point
where it's getting these test migration
reports as you can see because what's
going on is trigger.dev automation with
the Codex SDK like it said, it's
checking, it's doing research, it's
looking at the evidence, and then it's
making recommendation and it's sending
it to ClickUp, but also as an email to
my Grockbot. So you can see we now have
already set that up in trigger.dev dev
to basically mimic a codeex routine with
Astra on the back end with a full codeex
agentic loop, but we could now trigger
this programmatically and we could do it
by web hooks and on different schedules.
And like I said, you only would really
do this when you need it to truly be
programmatic and at scale because
otherwise you want to throw it on your
subscription because paying for Astra
via API credits is obviously more
expensive than paying for Astra via
subscription. But that is how these
three types of automations differ. And
now I can come back in here and I can
cross out Codex SDK. So Codex also has
this really cool feature inside the
desktop app called voice mode, which
basically just means that you can
actually just talk to it and it will
talk right back to you. So it's super
super cool. Let's hop into this next
section about how to use Codex's voice
mode. Hey there Astra. I've got a few
tasks today. The first one that I want
you to help me do, I want you to
delegate off to a codeex thread where we
take a video that I made on YouTube a
few days ago. Or actually no, it was
just yesterday. So, I want you to turn
that into an X article for me and put it
in my X account.
>> Got it. Let's line that up. So, that X
article is ready. Let me open this up
and we'll take a look. We can see that
we have all of this formatted. We have
that 5x2 thumbnail that we wanted that
matches our YouTube one. And now we can
see that these screenshots are coming
through. So, the prompt, it analyzed the
entire video, screenshotted it, put this
in here. It even cropped it. If you guys
notice, this isn't the full screen, but
it's matching these up because it
understands what am I seeing in this
image and where do I put it in the text
based on the actual article that was
written. Let's also try something else.
So, inside of my school community, AI
Automation Society Plus, we just did a
little bit of a revamp to the actual
course. So, if you could sort of just
like look in there, get familiarized
with that course structure and just help
me build a really simple, you know, AIS
branded landing page.
>> Yep. I'll start on that.
>> All right. I just got word that the AIS
Plus curriculum page is done and it's
looking pretty impressive. Let's open it
up full screen. Holy, this is actually
the courses. So, I just built this
entire personal OS with just my voice
using GBD6 Astra voice mode. Now, at a
glance, it might not seem too
impressive, but it had to figure out how
to connect my entire Herk Brain. It had
to go pull all the data from these
sources. It had to connect my real
calendar, and this is actually
functional, meaning here's my actual
calendar, and if I came here and I
wanted to add an event right here, we'll
just call this test, save event. This is
actually going to reflect on my real
calendar over here. Now, there are still
a few things that I'm looking to
connect, but I can communicate with my
team through Slack, ClickUp, and email
right from this interface. So, I can
open up this conversation and I could
reply to it right here. And I can also
kick off new threads via email or
ClickUp from here as well. And I also
have community polls from YouTube, from
my school communities, what they're
stuck on. And I also have industry polls
from X, YouTube, things like that. The
reason voice mode is so powerful is
because it just uses codecs on the back
end, which means it can look through
your AI operating system and it can do
everything that Codeex can do, but you
can control it with your voice and
multitask, kick off different threads.
You can do it from your phone, so you
can literally be on a walk and doing
everything you need to be doing. And the
browse use capabilities from GBD6 Astra
are the best I've ever seen. Right here
on screen, you can just see a silly
example where I gave it two pictures and
I had it paint me in Canva. And this did
take quite a while, but if you think
about all of the little strokes and
everything that needs to do, both on the
vision side and the browser use side,
it's actually pretty impressive. Now, on
top of all of the capabilities, you also
need it to have the right context and
connections to actually be useful. So,
when I tell you guys that I've been
talking to Astra in voice mode, and it's
just been feeling like it actually knows
everything about me and my business,
it's on another level. So, we just had
an event in July called AIS Live and
right here there's over 150 GB of
footage to look through. So, I gave
Codex this link and I basically just
said, "Hey, we need like a 60-second
sizzle reel from this event, like a
recap." And in only two prompts, this is
what I get back, which is really
impressive. Logged off yesterday just
buzzing. I had goosebumps. I was so
excited and I had so much fun.
Cost doesn't justify price. Price
justifies cost.
What is the value of what you know and
what you know how to do?
This culture that we have here at AIS is
is just really special.
If you think about the actual story that
it told and how much data it looked
through and what it was able to create,
that was really, really impressive, like
I said. So anyways, let me stop yapping
to you guys and start yapping to GBD6
Astra and show you guys what it can do.
So all you're going to do is down here
you can see there's a little button
called start new voice chat. You're
going to click on that. And now it's
time to put my headphones in. Hey there
Astra. I've got a few tasks today. The
first one that I want you to help me do,
I want you to delegate off to a codeex
thread where we take a video that I made
on YouTube a few days ago or actually no
it was just yesterday. It was called
like Astra made this. It made the whole
video. So, I want you to turn that into
an X article for me um and put it in my
X account.
>> Got it. Let's line that up.
>> And while you're working on that, can we
have a separate thread actually start
making the thumbnail for that?
>> Sure. Adding that as well.
>> Now, I do want to make sure that you're
using all my right skills and my right
context. So, make sure you're working
inside of my Herk 2 project for all of
these little tasks that we're going to
kick off today.
>> Got it. I'll make sure that's the
context going forward. The original
article task has been told to stop and
hand off any verified finds. And the
thumbnail task has just been told the
same.
>> Okay, awesome. Yeah, cuz I see that you
kicked off two regular chats and these
wouldn't have had the same context. So,
it's important that I told you to work
inside my Herk 2 project and now you
should be kicking off the right ones up
there. And it looks like you are.
>> Yep. Doing that now. And the article
task now has the thumbnail tasks details
so they can coordinate the source, the
angle, and the finished cover. Both
replacements are running inside Herk 2.
Awesome. Now, for the actual thumbnail I
want for this X article, I actually
already made one that I really like. um
the one that I put on my actual YouTube
channel, it was like an image of
um it was like me with my feet up on the
desk and the
OpenAI logo was editing the video. So,
all I really actually need you to do
there is if you could just turn that
into a 5x two version so it fits into
the X article.
>> Sure. I'll update the thumbnail work
with that.
>> Awesome. So, I know that probably will
take a little bit of time, so just let
me know when those are done. Let's also
try something else. So, inside of my
school community, a automation Society
Plus, we just did a little bit of a
revamp to the actual course. So, if you
could sort of just like look in there,
get familiarized with that course
structure. Um, I'm talking about the AI
Automation Society Plus group inside of
that one. if you could just analyze the
structure real quick and understand sort
of like the transformation from a new
joiner to the end state once they've
taken all the courses and just help me
build a really simple you know AIS
branded landing page that I could
basically send people to if they're like
hey you know what is AIS plus I could
send them there and they could get a
rundown of what that curriculum looks
like and I want you to also design that
in a way where you use my scrollcraft
skill to have layers and to have it be
you know dynamic and visual but don't
make it too overwhelming So if you could
start designing that website as well
based on that knowledge.
>> Yep. I'll start on that and I'll keep
the design dynamic but not overwhelming.
>> Awesome. So now I see that I'm talking
to you in one thread but then I can also
see when I look at the all the threads
that you're kicking off. I can see how
you're clearly multitasking. And then by
the way I see the thumbnail that you
made. That looks great. That's exactly
what I was looking for. Will my other
thread that is making the actual article
it knows that that's there. Oh yeah. It
looks like you sent that exact message
where I said that looks great. That's
exactly what I was looking for. So, you
are able to actually coordinate these
different codec threads to talk to each
other.
>> That's right. The article task has the
approved cover and your go ad.
>> Awesome. Well, while I wait for me to be
able to verify that that all worked,
could you let's make another improvement
to the Upit OS. Let's see if we could
add I guess let's add another section
for meetings. I know we already can see
all of my meetings in the actual
Herkbrain visual, but let's add another
tab on the left that just shows the
meeting. So, you pull that in from
Fireflies and it's just kind of like a
nice visual of the date that the meeting
was and just like a one sentence summary
of what was discussed or if there's any
important action items from there just
so I can visually see all the meetings
that I had. Um, and maybe if there are
any important meetings coming up as
well.
>> Okay, I'll take that on.
>> Cool. So, while you're cooking on that,
I'm going to go ahead and actually pause
this voice chat. I'll pick it back up
with you in a bit when you have some
updates for me. But, I want to kick off
some voice threads on my mobile device
and see how that all works as well. So,
I'll be back in a bit. Okay. So,
anyways, just wanted to show you guys
what was actually going on here. So, it
made this thumbnail, which was actually
based on if I go to my thumbnails, this
one. So, this is the one that I wanted
to use because this is the one that did
best on YouTube. And I just needed it to
make that a 5x two. And what you guys
will notice is I didn't tell it to find
this exact thumbnail. It looked through
my YouTube probably to see which one was
the live one. It looked through the
local files to actually build that. Same
thing over here. What happened was I
don't know what it delegated around, but
all I said was I need an ex article for
this. And so what it did is it had to
pull in the actual video. It's
transcribing it. And now what it's doing
is it's making the expost, but it also
took 11 screenshots. And so it's going
to place those screenshots in the X
article at the right spot. So we'll get
to view that in a sec. But I just wanted
to call out what's actually going on on
the back end there cuz it's very
impressive. But now I need you guys to
look at this. So you can also do this on
your phone. So imagine you're on a walk
or you're in your car driving and you
need to kick off some tasks or delegate
some work to your team or whatever it
might be. Because it has all the
connections in here. You're going to go
to remote. You're going to scroll down
and this is where you'll Oh, wait. Right
here. This button right here. This is
where you'll start a new voice chat. And
now it's going to be the same thing.
Hey, so I need you to help me kick off a
thread inside of um my Herk 2 project.
What I want you to do is I just need a
nice rundown of the best use cases that
you've seen, the best viral demos that
you've seen of Astra 6 um you know, GPT
Astra 6 on X.
>> Sure.
>> So, the point I'm trying to make here is
that I can keep scrolling on my phone
even when it's doing things on the back
end. As you can see, it's still keeping
this conversation
Got it. I'll keep going here. Yep,
that's exactly it. I kicked off the
Astro research thread and we can keep
talking here meanwhile.
>> Awesome. So, while we're while we're
waiting on all this, could you just take
a look at my, you know, the look at the
YouTube space, look at some of my past
videos and look at what else is going on
in the space and give me a quick
analysis of maybe some trends and maybe
some things to start preparing for. I'll
scan the current landscape. Now, big
trends heading toward 2027 are more AI
assisted production and personalization,
deeper community play with memberships
and owned audiences, short and long form
blending into one funnel, and creators
rewarded for building recognizable shows
and perspectives, not just one-off
uploads.
>> So, the point I was trying to make there
was just that you can do this on your
phone as well, and it's a super clean,
crisp syncing between your desktop and
your phone. So, we've got the Up OS
working on adding a Fireflies task or a
Fireflies meeting section. So, I can see
that stuff. We've got the X article
being finalized and we'll pull that up.
So, that X article is ready. Let me open
this up and we'll take a look. We can
see that we have all of this formatted.
We have that 5x2 thumbnail that we
wanted that matches our YouTube one. We
have all of this formatted in a good
way. And now we can see that these
screenshots are coming through. So, the
prompt, it analyzed the entire video,
screenshotted it, put this in here. It
even cropped it. If you guys notice,
this isn't the full screen. We keep
going down. This is the full screen.
This is a full screen. Full screen. But
it's matching these up because it
understands what am I seeing in this
image and where do I put it in the text
based on the actual article that was
written. And there is nothing sensitive
in this video. But what it will actually
do too is if I have like an API key in
there or if I have like a personal
email, it actually will like blur it
out. So it does that automatically. And
now that is just worked into the skill.
So this is now an article that I would
just be able to read through. All of
these screenshots are taken. They're
cropped if they needed to be. They're
blurred out if they needed to be. And
then I can just go ahead and publish it
because it did all of that with just my
voice. We can also see that this one
that I kicked off from my phone is done.
It searched through X and it found um
multiple posts. One from Ben Davis, one
from Ethan, one from Thomas. You can see
that it gives us the actual link to all
of these threads. So if I want to click
on, you know, this 3D graphics build, I
get taken straight to that actual post.
1.3 million views. I did see this one.
This one was pretty impressive. We can
see that now we have this little
rundown. And if we would have stayed on
the voice chat, it would have, you know,
told us about all this. It looks like
the upp one is also done. Let's see what
happened over here. Meetings is live.
So, let me open this up and we'll see.
Actually, I'm going to open this up full
screen. We now have a section called
meetings. You can see on the calendar,
I've got one tomorrow. I've got one on
Monday. And we can actually pull up the
actual calendar details. So, if I open
this one up, does this take us straight
to the calendar? Yeah, it takes us
straight to the actual calendar. And we
see the event details there. And now we
can also see past meetings. So this all
hands we can see the team reviewed
learning community growth product
updates operational improvements AI
tools and a shared mission centered on
customer happiness. We have an action
highlight Nate Herk share bookmark links
to the most used Google Drive folders.
Yep. Yep. Yep. And we can see other
action items here and we can also open
up this recording which takes us
straight to Fireflies. So that quickly
we were able to develop a new section
into our actual um OS here which is a
combination of Fireflies and Google
Calendar. And I don't even know if it
uses any AI in the background because
Fireflies already processes these AI
action items. Maybe it hit, you know,
the GBT endpoint or the Enthropic
endpoint to actually put this stuff in
here, but really impressive. All right.
And I just got word that the AIS Plus
curriculum page is done. And it's
looking pretty impressive. Let's open it
up full screen. Build the skills shape.
What's next? And we've got Holy, this is
actually the courses. I wonder if it
Okay, it takes you down to here. There's
like a curriculum section. Now, I think
this looks really good. It pulled a
picture of me. You also will realize
that the background, right? The
background, you can see these layers.
The mountains are in different spots.
They move in different, you know, paces.
But what I love about this that it did
is if I actually go to our AI Automation
Society website, it kept a very similar
vibe, right? Like the blue feeling, the
backgrounds um of the mountains and
stuff, even on the certification tab, it
kept the consistency. Now, honestly, I
think these mountains look a little bit
cooler and there's like fog, but it kept
everything on brand because it was able
to crawl through my workspace, look up
what it needed to look up to make sure
that it actually understood what I was
asking for. And that's what I think is
so cool about Astra is when you give it
a task, it feels like it just will
contextualize and ask you questions and
crawl through things first because it
wants to make it more specific to you.
And that's what is just really, really
cool. I mean, this is this is the actual
curriculum. If I go to AS+ and I go to
classroom, that's exactly what happens.
you know these are the actual courses
and then over here uh wrong one these
are the actual courses that we have in
there so it was able to look through all
of that and build out the actual
curriculum I think this is really really
slick all right so voice mode is one of
the big differentiators between cloud
code and codec but there are a lot of
other things and I will be honest in
this space you are jumping back and
forth a lot like I use both of them
every day and sometimes you know codeex
will come out with a big new release and
then the next week claude code will come
out with a new big release or maybe
there's a new tool like Hermes agent or
Grockbot or whatever you know is going
on in the AI world because it moves very
fast. Now the first thing I want to say
is that you should not be worried
because this whole course we've been
talking a lot about building your own
AIOS and when you're building your own
AIOS you guys know that it's just a
bunch of folders and files and those
live on your machine. So whether you are
using codeex or cloud code or Hermes
agent or whatever the next tool is you
just say hey Mr. Mrs. AI agent, look at
my AIOS, get familiarized with it, and
now you can in a matter of 5 seconds,
all your skills transfer over, all your
instruction files transfer over. You
don't have to be worried about being
like vendor locked. Everything that
you're building, not only your local
files and folders, but also your brain,
your knowledge on how to work with AI
and how to talk to it and the mindset
around it, that is all your IP. And it's
very tool agnostic. It's very model
agnostic. So, you can be flexible. Don't
worry about it. But I do want to show
you guys this next video which is about
me running a bunch of different use
cases on these two coding agents and
just showing you the difference what
that might look like sometimes with cost
and speed and just like quality. So hope
you guys enjoy this next section which
is kind of just like an experiment where
I show off the differences between these
tools in these different use cases. I
just put GPT6 Astra headto-head against
Fable 5.1 across 15 different use cases
that actually apply to my day-to-day.
I'm talking things like web design,
personal organization, taxes, browser
use, vision, and building actual
automations and software. For every
single one of these use cases, I break
down which model did better, how long it
took, and what it cost. So, if you've
been wondering what model to use for
which use case, then this is the video
for you. I don't want to waste any time.
Let's just get straight into it today.
All right, so these are the 15 different
use cases that we have. And like I said,
I chose these because these are things
that I actually see myself doing with
these models. So, there are timestamps
down below if you want to jump around.
And at the very end, I'm going to show
the final sort of like takeaways and
final cost and time breakdown. And by
the way, guys, I've eaten through like
three CEX subscriptions, four cloud
subscriptions, and thousands of dollars
in usage credits. So, I really hope that
this one's helpful. All right, so for
number one, I'm not going to read off
every single prompt, but here's
basically what I asked. I wanted a
McKenzie level presentation on the state
of SMB report for my Hercules Consulting
brand. So, I needed this to be branded
and I needed it to apply to our target
audience with this fake consulting
business. So, that was Claude. You can
see that I gave Codex the exact same
prompt. Now, immediately what I've
noticed is that Codex asks more
questions or GBT6 Astra specifically
asks more questions. You can see right
here, it already asked me questions,
whereas Fable just took this and pretty
much just ran. And that is something I
noticed overall. So, I just wanted to
call that out to start. So, let's take a
look at these two decks. Here is deck
number one. I won't tell you which model
it was yet, but right away, I love the
way it feels. It is, you know,
capitalized. It has the branding. This
feels pretty professional so far. Now, I
already did check both of these for the
sources and the verification, and they
are good from like the fact perspective,
right? The research they both did was
good. Now, I'm looking more so at the
way they actually formatted this
deliverable. I think we're at a place
now where GBT6 Astra and Fable 5.1,
they're both so so intelligent. You
don't have to worry as much about
fanning out agents and doing research.
It's more to me now about how do they
come back and present this in a way that
tells a story and in something that I
can actually like present over, right?
because that's what we want is we want
to turn that messy data into something
that's readable and something that's
high quality. And right now what I'm
feeling is that this is very very
branded. It matches our color scheme. We
have a footer down here which I love.
It's consistent. We have like structure.
There's columns. Like it did a good job
creating this. The thing that I think
right now though is it's very very
wordy. As far as being able to present
over something like this, it would be
tough because there's so many words and
it's tough to control like where
people's eyes will be looking and what
they'll be speaking about. So, as far as
a presentation deck, not the best, but
as far as like a deliverable you might
turn in, you might send to someone and
not present, this is very good. And
there's a lot of sources down here. This
came out to 35 slides. Now, let's look
at the other version, which right away I
don't like how this isn't capitalized. I
don't know. I just feel like that feels
very professional. We have some images
here, and we have the color scheme as
well. But let's flick through. We
immediately notice that this one is not
as wordy. I immediately feel like this
one's less professional though because
of the structure. The other one had like
I don't know, you could tell in each
slide there was like columns. there was
a little bit of like a I don't know
there was a structure to it whereas this
one feels a little bit more abstract. It
feels like one big element. You've got
one big, you know, title thing. And I
think that this one would be a much
better deliverable if I was going to
present in, you know, in a room full of
people. But overall, as we flick
through, this one just feels less
professional. The vibe I get is less
McKenzie and it's more Google Slides or
like Canva. I don't know. There's also
not like a consistent footer or our logo
isn't on every slide. So, you know, this
sort of slide, it just doesn't feel very
structured and as professional. Even the
sources section is way smaller, although
that does link the actual sources. So
anyways, this one was GBT6 Astra and
this one was Fable 5.1. And I will say
in this specific example, I liked Fable
better. So what I'm going to do here is
I'm going to give Fable the win. So I'm
just going to put this down here so we
know Fable won this experiment as far as
just the output. But let's look at the
time and cost. Fable was 37 minutes and
Astra was 23 minutes and Fable was 26
bucks and Astra was 12 bucks. So Astra
was a little less than half the cost as
well as you know 14 minutes faster. So
the question would be if you used Astra
and spent another you know 14 bucks
using Astra to improve V1 would you get
somewhere that you feel better about
than this first version of Fable. So
anyways right now we'll look at the time
and cost at the very end but as far as
the deliverable I liked Fable's output
better here. All right moving on to
experiment number two. We did a sales
letter. So basically I said based on
what you know about our certification
program I didn't give it information. I
told it to you know use my AIOS use my
second brain use any research to put
together a sales landing page. So
writing the copy that's optimized to
convert. So think about our avatar think
about their pain. Think about all this
and I don't want it to sound AI
generated. So I'm not going to read the
entire sales letters. That would be
super boring. Just going to do a quick
skim through and talk about which one I
actually thought was better and why. So
here was the one that Fable 5.1 wrote
out. You can see it is pretty long. This
one was longer. It was about 2,800
words. And if we go over to GBT's
version, if I come down here, it just
output it right in the chat to me. This
was the one that Astra wrote up. And
this one was more like 1,700 words. So,
it was definitely shorter. Now, quick
disclaimer here. I am not an expert
copywriter. I would want, you know, like
John or someone on my team who is really
good at writing copy to tell me which
one they thought is better. I will say
so far what I've been hearing from my
team is that they are liking the GBT
models lately better for writing whereas
in the past Claude always dominated when
it came to writing. But I will say if I
was a prospective you know certification
student and I was reading these I
honestly here would have picked Fable
and the reason is because this is not a
cheap program and Fable had things like
questions people ask. Will this get me
hired? Does everyone who joins get
certified? Am I technical enough? I
already run an agency. What if I miss
live classes? The way it formatted this
makes me feel a little bit more
confident or makes me feel more aware of
what I'm getting myself into. It also
had a section about tuition. It also had
a section about who's teaching, who it's
for, who it's not for, how this actual
program works. Whereas the sales letter
over here with Astra just felt a little
bit more, I don't know, it just felt a
little bit more high level. And I think
with the sales letter, it's supposed to
be detailed enough to answer all the
questions and pain that someone's
thinking about when they're considering
paying for a program. So, I will say in
this specific example, I do think that I
liked Fable 5.1's copy more. So here is
actually what this looked like. Fable
was about four minutes. Astra was about
three minutes. Fable wrote Okay, I was
wrong about Astra. It wasn't 1,700. It
was actually more like 1300. So about
half of the words that Fable wrote. But
Astra came in at $143 whereas Fable came
in at almost four bucks. So here I will
have to say again that I think that
Fable won this challenge as far as just
like a oneshot prompt and the initial
output. All right, so moving on to use
case number three. Now, unfortunately,
guys, I'm going to have pretty much
everything blurred out here because this
is about my taxes, right? And this is
one of those things where you want
something that is very smart to be able
to do this and in a way that you trust.
So, I'm just going to go through high
level the way I feel when I look at
these outputs. This first one was Fable
5.1. And before I get into it, I do want
to say in this example, GBT Astra asked
me like seven questions before it
started, whereas Fable didn't. So, that
alone makes me feel more confident in
Astra's output. But let's look through
here. We go through basically from
January of this year to June of this
year. So Q1 and Q2 of this year. It
pulls all of the numbers. It looks at
federal and state. It looks at things
that I need to read. It goes to the
input and it shows me all of these
different things as far as the
parameters, the notes, the values, the
sources. And Fable gave me like a
decision logic. It said, "Hey, if you
fit into this bucket, do this. If you
fit into this bucket, do this." Whereas
Astra just asked me those questions and
then gave me that recommendation.
Anyways, we have a um P&L. We have some
projections. So for the rest of the
year, what I might be estimating to pay.
We have tax calculations here for the
individual return and all of the
entities that are passed through. We've
got payments. We've got things that are
flagged. And then we have the actual
sources it pulled from. So it's not bad.
It's a really good deliverable like
light years ahead of what used to
happen. But now we have the one from
Astra. We have the actual information as
far as start here. This is what it did.
We have monthly results. We have the tax
forecast. We have Okay, that looks very
good. We have all these payments. We
have inputs and open items. So, these
are other things that I might need to
answer, but this is just way more
tailored. It's easier to read as well.
We have the source checks. We have the
transaction ledger. And this one is
basically every single transaction here.
So, this Oh my gosh, this is probably
thousands and thousands of rows. This is
3739 rows of transactions here. And then
we've got all the sources that it pulled
from. Okay, cool. So, overall, this one
I think that Astro won, like no
question. It was more tailored. It asked
questions. I think with taxes alone, it
gave me that that feeling of confidence
and the structure of the deliverable was
just better to me. Now, Astra did cost
more here and it took longer to run. So,
40 minutes compared to 22 minutes and 22
bucks compared to 13 bucks. So, even
though it's more expensive, we're kind
of putting that aside right now. As far
as the deliverable, I liked Astra here
more. So, right now, we're sitting at
Astra 1 Fable 2. All right. So, this
next one's interesting. I asked it to go
through two of my email accounts and
just look through, you know, potentially
years of emails to help me find
information about subscriptions that I'm
paying for, how much total I've paid
them, you know, um if prices have
increased and things that I need to
cancel, things like that. So, let me
pull up the two outputs. All right, so
here is output number one from Fable
5.1. Now, as we get into the next tabs
on the sheet, I'm sorry, guys, but I am
going to have to blur some of the stuff
out. It's it's financial information.
So, anyways, we have the rundown right
here of the audit. We have the different
emails it looked at. We have the
different types of services,
memberships, programs, retainers,
contractors, insurance, all this type of
stuff. It's looking at the top 10. It's
looking at our different categories, and
it's showing us how to read this sheet.
So, we have all of our active
subscriptions. It's showing me what
email they're associated with. It's
telling me which day of the month I'm
getting build on. It's showing the
current price. It's showing the monthly
equivalent. It's showing me all of the
stats across all of the different
payments that we've been making on some
sort of recurring basis. It's flagging
things and it's ranking them as far as
priority. We can see um the different
actual flag notes. So some of these it
might be unpaid. This one's getting a
price jump. This one's having a seat
creep. This one's having I have two
subscriptions at once. So maybe we need
to figure out why do I have two
different subscriptions on both emails
there. So the point being it's able to
look through so much information and
give you all of these things that are
high priority and you can flag them. You
can check them off. You can, you know,
delegate that out to your team. We have
all charges which actually this sheet
came back completely empty. I'm not sure
why, but this sheet is completely empty.
And then we have contractors and big
payments. So, these are things it looks
like. Anything above
um either a few thousand or if it was a
contractor that was like a onetime
invoice, then it flagged it here as
well. And now, let's go over to the
Astra 6 version. You can see that they
consistently just format Google Sheets a
little bit different. Like, you can kind
of tell Astra likes to make the cells
larger and and wider and taller, whereas
Fable usually keeps them the same. And,
you know, they still do a good job
formatting, but either way, same sort of
thing. At the audit up front, we have
the current recurring baseline of
subscriptions. We have the annualized
baseline tool payments, tool invoices
without confirmation, claude usage,
other bills, um price changes. It's
flagging everything right here. Priority
review right here. You know, there's a
discount ending, there is contract tier
or a contact tier, there is a price
increase, there's a term change, there's
seats and tool overlap. So, it's
flagging all that right away. We then
have all the subscriptions. So, this
shows me a list of every single one. It
gives me the price. It gives me the um
last known bill. Now, this isn't showing
me what date. Oh, there it is. Yeah,
it's showing me every single day of the
month that we have the next one. We have
other bills as well. So, these are kind
of the bigger like bigger contracts um
contractors or or bigger bills. We have
payments. So, this is also like every
single one. And I think this is what
Fable was trying to do on this tab with
all charges, but for some reason just
didn't come through. So, we have this
here. And then we have also other notes
as far as different topics and different
things to sort of be aware of. So, this
is kind of like what it was flagging.
So, overall here, I will say that Astra
gave me a better output. It just, you
know, Fable messed up one sheet
completely and Astro was cheaper here.
So 12 bucks, 12 and a half bucks
compared to about $50, which is insane.
$50 for that output from Fable. Crazy.
It did take 17 minutes whereas Astra
took 30 minutes. But anyways, right now
we are sitting at 2 to2 Astra and Fable.
All right, moving on to number five. We
have meeting analysis. So I asked it to
look through all of my leadership
meetings and my syncs with John and
looking at other meetings that are
relevant to the team. And I wanted it to
understand or I wanted it to tell me
what are the biggest pain points, three
biggest pain points and one of the
highest value automations that we could
build to remove some constraints and
help us scale faster. So Fable gave me
the biggest pain points of me being the
single production and review engine
which is something that I've talked
about 25 of 58 meetings. Certification
delivery does not scale past one cohort.
So we're trying to figure out what that
will look like. The critical constraint
of the business is also a large cost
center. 52 students blah blah blah. And
then we also have demand collapsed and
every fix is blocked by unknown work and
untrusted data. Weekly leads fell blah
blah blah. And yeah, all this makes
sense as far as our three biggest pain
points. And then the one automation it
came up with was an AI customer success
layer for theert one live record per
student built from circle activity
mastery check outputs and attendance.
Students upload case readouts to an
endpoint instead of DMing pat weekly due
dates and reminders so non-submitters go
out through Gmail or beehive. I think
this is something that I've wanted to do
and that we talked about a lot and that
makes a lot of sense based on all these
conversations. And and I also wanted to
note here that Fable 5.1 analyzed 58
meetings and if we go over to Astra,
Astra analyzed 79 meetings. So it did
get the context of 21 more meetings in
here. But anyways, let's take a look.
The first one was that growth depends
too heavily on a few acquisition
channels. Yep, same pain point I think
as Fable pointed out. The second one is
that the customer journey requires too
much personal intervention. This
appeared in undefined AI plus onboarding
call reser during certification and
leadership still has to reconstruct
status and clarify who owns what. Okay,
interesting. So these are different pain
points than Fable 5.1 found. Now as far
as the automation I would prioritize it
came up with the same thing. A customer
success workflow which would check each
student's onboarding status, unanswered
questions, available progress, identify
missteps, prepare follow-up, all makes
sense. Now in this case I think Astra
won again like before I even thought
about the cost which is absolutely
absurd. Astra still won because I liked
its recommendation about the leadership
stuff and ownership. And I think that's
something that you really want to make
sure you have figured out within a team.
But anyways, if you look here, Astra was
5 1/2 bucks and Fable 5.1 here was 46
bucks, which just makes no sense to me.
I'm I'm very very confused on how it
cost that much. I had it look at the
session logs. I also did a SL usage and
this one cost 46 bucks even though the
active agent time was just 6 minutes. So
I'm very confused on where those tokens
went. Like I don't understand why. It
also analyzed less meetings in Astra.
But anyways, that's pretty interesting.
This winner is definitely Astra. So now
we are sitting at 3 to2 Astra to Fable.
All right, so moving on to number six.
This one's super interesting to me. I
gave it this folder which has over 150
GB of resources and recordings from our
AIS live event in July. And I asked them
to make us basically a recap, like an
energetic reel, 60 seconds that shows
like a recap of the event that we can
use to promote the next ones and things
like that. Now, I'm really impressed
with both of these outputs. Let me just
say because with how much information it
had to look through and how it had to
create a story and figure out how to put
everything together with music, I think
they both did really really well. So,
here is Fable 5.1.
>> Hello. Hello, AIS Live. My Let's Let's
get some energy going in here.
>> Oh my god, I'm so excited for this. You
guys are throwing out a fantastic event.
>> Literally like logged off yesterday just
buzzing. I had goosebumps. Let's Let's
get you guys paid.
This was an experience that didn't feel
like a webinar.
It's been a great few days.
Okay, so that was Fable 5.1. Let's take
a look at Astra's version. This has been
so energizing.
Yesterday I did a workshop where I went
all in on every little tool that I use.
Cloud code is my primary driver and then
I built like my entire second
brain/personal agent on top of it.
>> I could go to bed, come back and it'll
still be working, you know, 10 hours
later to try to achieve that goal.
It's great to be here. You guys have
done a a fantastic event. Everything's
been super smooth.
You guys have been such an amazing
audience today.
Now, this one, like I said, is really
tough. I think that they both did
different things well. I think that
Asher did a better job of putting like
live clips in there. I think that Fable
did a better job of kind of like gearing
it up for the next event in October.
There were a few moments where there
were some things that were off. Like
Fable had a few moments where the the
timing and the voices were felt like not
very synced. Astra had one weird moment
where it was showing an a video of Russ,
but it said Devon Karns and it was just
like that was clearly off. But I am
going to give the slight edge here to
Astra. But I will say I'm very very
impressed by both of those outputs. I
thought it was given the vague goal,
they both did a really good job of
exploring and creating a story. But
anyways, this one is going to go to
Astra because you can see this stuff
here. Astra took 30 minutes whereas
Fable took 50 and Astra cost 16 bucks
and Fable cost 26 bucks here. Now, next
we did sizzle reels. I basically gave it
an example of a scissor reel that I
really liked or sort of like a sass I
don't know a motion graphic a motion
design video that I liked and I told it
to analyze what was good about it and I
told it to use that as inspiration and
create us one for AIS. So let me show
you guys these outputs. First one is
Fable 5.1.
Okay, now let me play you Astro's
output. Heat. Heat. N.
Okay, so Astro wins this one. I mean, I
will say that music is a little bit
annoying. The but besides that, it took
screenshots from AIS. Like, it went in
here and it grabs pictures of the actual
courses. Where was the other one? It
took a picture here, which I thought was
just like I love that idea that it's
thinking, okay, why don't I actually go
get real proof and screenshots from the
thing I'm actually building a reel about
and put it in there. I also love this
like these 3D designs. I don't know, it
just felt like it had depth. You can see
the shadows here as it kind of, you
know, zooms in. I thought that this as
far as the energy that it had was much
better and much higher energy than the
first one from Fable 5.1. Now, let's
take a look at the cost and time. This
one was about similar time, but Fable
5.1 was, you know, a little over half.
So, 16 bucks compared to 26 bucks. But
once again, I still think that in this
case, I'm going to take that output from
Astra as the winner. So, moving on to
number eight. This one's a little more
out there as far as I probably wouldn't
really be doing this every day for work,
but I had them build me these games. So,
we have two different games where you're
a pistachio and you're trying to escape
the kitchen. So, I'm just going to go
through these real quick and you're
going to tell me which one you thought
was, you know, sort of like which model.
So, you can see here it's it's uh it's
pretty smooth. I can double jump. I'm
collecting these like serial bits and I
have to hit these checkpoints to get to
different spots in order to get out of
the kitchen. The physics are real. Like
I'm bumping into these things and I can
like, you know, hit the spoon and
everything like that. It's pretty easy,
but you know, I I I missed a cereal, but
I'm able to escape and win the game in
about 43 seconds. Okay, now here is the
other version. This one This one
definitely looks a little bit more I
don't know. It looks a little bit more
premium, doesn't it? Um, this obviously
this wall isn't there, but it's just
because we want to be able to see like
this. But this one feels a bit more
premium, I'd say. It also feels smoother
when I'm actually like controlling this.
It is guiding me very specifically,
though. I don't know. I can double jump,
I think. Oh, no. I can't double jump.
The physics seem to be real still. I can
bump into stuff. If I can move things, I
can fall into there. Um, we've got a hot
stove. Oops. It's interesting though,
they both decided to have like the same
flow as far as you jump up on the drawer
and then you you know, you jump up on
books to start, you're now on the stove,
you're going over to the sink. I mean,
that's how most kitchens are, but still
the the actual flow is pretty similar.
And now we escaped in this one in 46
seconds. So, similar amount of time. I
did get all of the crumbs in this one.
They were designed very similarly, but I
will say I think that as far as like
feeling realistic and you know physics,
I liked this version better and this
version was Astra. Anyways, look at
these stats. They were very, very
similar. So Astra was eight bucks
cheaper, N bucks cheaper, and it also
took about 40 bucks longer. So very
similar stats. Nothing blew anything out
of the water here, but I would say that
I'm giving this one to Astra. Once
again, that one's subjective. Maybe some
of you guys liked Fable 5.1 more, but
what I think is really important is that
you're applying your own taste and
you're finding your own use cases
because some of these use cases, you
guys might be like, "Well, I actually
liked Fable 5.1 here." Cool. Then you
just figured out maybe you use Fable 5.1
for that use case, even though some
other people might use Astra for that
use case. It's all about your own use
cases and your own experiments. Okay, so
moving on to number nine, we have an
actual SAS, like kind of a mini SAS, and
it's an evaluation app. So you should be
able to put in like automations and then
run them against some golden data set
and see the score and understand like
what you need to fix and then you can
rerun them and you can generate reports
and things like that. So you can see
here this is the first version. This is
Fable 5.1. I think that right away this
is a little bit more of an intimidating
interface. It's very very wordy but we
can see all of these tests. We can see
our different automations here on the
left as well. We can add a new one. So
if we wanted to put the name, a
description, and then actually you know
say how how do you actually trigger this
automation? Is it Python or do you hit
an API? And then from there, let's just
put in some information. You would
actually put in the URL or you would put
in the Python script. You would put in
the test cases and then you would write,
you know, how to grade it. So that is
going to be very valuable. And it also
has all of this stored on the back end
because it has to store all of these
actual um runs and it has to store the
code and it has to, you know, show the
improvements and things like that. So
here we can see this support ticket one.
Um I think they ran two tests. You can
see that there's also like a visual
breakdown of what this actually does. So
this is a very deterministic script. We
can see the code. We can see the setup.
We can see the test cases. So, this is
essentially our golden data set. There's
only 12 examples. You probably need more
than that. But this was all generated to
actually test the system, right? And if
I actually go in here and hit run, what
does this do? You put the name, you put
what changed, you put any tags, and you
compare it with a different version if
you want. And then I just go ahead and
start the test. And so, this came back.
You can see, I mean, there were no
changes. So, we still got two out of the
10, or sorry, two out of the 12 didn't
hit, right? It also went super super
fast because I, like I said, this is
super simple. But then you can generate
a report. So if I come in here, we can
see all of the different tests that
we've ran and it would show us like
what's still broke and it would show us
the improvements we make. So this is
something that, you know, I actually do
want to keep building out so we can do
this for, you know, our our students and
basically give them a better way to
evaluate their agents and things like
that when they're building them out
because eval obviously we all know are
super super important and it's also good
to be able to see them visually. So this
was Fable 5.1's version. Let's look at
Astra's version. So I do like the
interface of this one more as from a
design perspective. So, I think that
this one feels I don't know, it just
feels a little bit more premium. It's
also less wordy, so it's less
intimidating right away. I think we have
a test library, so we can see all of
these different versions. We have run
history. We also have reports over here
that we can look at. So, we can see
customer support agent. Um, I like how
this report is structured. Let's see if
we look at this next one. We can see how
it changes over time. This one feels
more branded. Like, this feels like
something I'd rather get in front of
some eyes and get some feedback on
compared to Oops, I just closed out of
the other one. compared to this version.
This one just feels way more like a PC
compared to this I feel like is, you
know, something we can almost get out
there and start testing against. So, if
I come into an automation real quick,
let's say we go to the support ticket
router and I want to go ahead and see it
visually. I like that a lot. We can see
all the previous runs and I can go ahead
and run this eval again and we can see
it running a bit better. We're seeing it
actually go through the test cases. I
like this experience way, way more. And
look at this. Astra came back and cost
half the price of what Fable spent in
order to do this. It did take a little
longer, 2 hours 25 minutes compared to
an hour and 20 minutes, but it just so
much better for less cost. So, in this
case, I'm giving this to Astra once
again. So, Astra is now up, I believe, 7
to2 on Fable. All right, moving on to
number 10. We now have this Herk brain
visual. So, this is a local host where I
can see basically my brain. We see
different clusters over here. Um, this
seems more like YouTube videos. This
seems like things are actually going on
in the business. Oh, wait. We can see
down here claude memory video knowledge
and we can remove things or put them
back in business wiki skills and agents
projects and this is dynamic. It's
really cool because we can see only what
needs attention. We can see show all
labels. We can see 612 notes 2500
connections. We can analyze things. We
can talk to it. We can search for
things. Let's see if I search for um
personal OS personal assistant openclaw.
We can open up the specific things. And
that is a pretty cool visual. So we can
actually start to see in here inside of
the brain. And as we click on different
things, we see all of the connections
that are linking into it. So all the
relationships. So that is a pretty cool
experience. It does feel pretty smooth.
And I can control this. Uh not too well.
Like I feel like I have to click on
something to make that the center, but I
I think that that's pretty cool. So that
was Fable 5.1's version. Let me now open
up Astra's version. Okay. So this one's
a little bit different. Um I can still
click on all of these things. These
nodes are smaller. I don't like how that
feels. I don't like this interface
at all, like nearly as much. I have the
same sort of vibe. I can click on
business strategy or AI and ideas,
videos and content, um people, projects,
book and writing, all knowledge. Um this
interface is more overwhelming for sure.
Like I I definitely like this one more.
I wanted just something simple where I
can see the brain a bit more visually.
And I was honestly expecting Astra to
come in here and kick Fable's butt here,
but I think that I like Fables more. And
now let's look at the cost. Astra took
40 minutes. Fable took 24. Astra and
Fable basically cost the same. Fable was
a little bit cheaper, but I am going to
give this one to Fable. I think that
Fable gave me more of what I was looking
for. You know, once again, kind of a
subjective grading criteria, but I think
Fable won here. So, what does that put
us at now? We're at 7 to3 Astra to
Fable, and we have five more use cases
left. So, Fable could still take the
lead. All right, guys. So, this one is
an HTML explainer doc. What I did is I
gave it my YouTube video, the 25
Grockbot concepts explained. And I told
it to explain it to me simply simply
simply and visually. And I told it to
take screenshots. So, I said basically,
give me a doc that I can read through
and it feels like I actually watched the
entire tutorial. So, we have all these
different parts. We can see the
screenshot to start. This one obviously
is is kind of wordy up front, but that's
okay. We see how the team fits together.
So me, these executives, these
operators, we can see all these
different plugins and computers and
skills. So that's a good little
explanation at first. Now we move into
the concepts. So we're taking
screenshots and it is being analyzed.
This is Fable 5.1 by the way. We can see
the executive bots. We can see the name
and job label. These so far are coming
through well as far as these screenshots
being cropped and annotated, which is
really nice. It's taking a lot of
different screenshots. We have the
buttons here. We have all this. I think
that this is coming out pretty well and
it's showing us what we need to see from
the actual video. Now, I do think this
is pretty wordy. Um, I think that but it
is getting very specific. Like, I do
think I could give this doc to some
people and they would be able to feel
like they actually watched this video.
It's it's cropping things. It's zooming
in. It's annotating. I think that this
is doing a really good job. It's even
showing all of this. Yeah, I mean, this
is doing a really good job here. So,
let's go over to Ash's output. This one
already, it looks a bit better as far as
the HTML. And now let's see if the
screenshots are good as well. So we have
one here. It's pointing at a bot. It is
pointing at the description, the
executives. It's pointing at these
different buttons. I will say Fables was
more detailed for sure. Like this one
was designed better, but Fable's
screenshots were better. Like Fable took
more screenshots and made more
annotations. And so far, I think that
that was a better learning experience.
Even though this one, like I said, looks
a little bit more I don't know. it it
feels prettier or better. But if you
were really thinking about could you
hand this doc to a complete beginner and
have them actually go through and feel
like they're learning, I think that
Fable's going to take this one. But
let's look at the cost. Like I still am
going to give the output to Fable, but
when we look at the cost, Astra was much
cheaper here. So the question is like,
you know, if you used Astra and had it
spend another, you know, 20 bucks or so,
would it be better than Fable's output
right here? And I would argue that yes,
it would be better. So it was way more
efficient here, but it's, you know, its
V1 wasn't as good as Fable's V1 in my
opinion. So Fable's going to take this
one. So now we are at 7 to4 Fable or 7
to4 Astra to Fable. Okay, so moving on
to number 12, we have this sort of like
painting example in Canva, which is a
bit silly, but it does highlight the
browser use and the vision really well
cuz GBT6 Astra had to look at this
picture, open up Canva, understand how
to navigate with the different tools and
things, and build this out, which it
did. And I think that this does look
pretty good, especially when we go over
to Fable real quick and I open up
Fable's output. If I go to the painting
and we open up the browser here, this is
literally what it gave me. And this was
the reference image. I mean, this is
just this is laughable. This is
laughable. I I was expecting Fable 5.1
to do something much better, but it like
I don't know what exactly it tried to
do, but this is obviously just very bad.
So, no question Astro wins this one. And
Astra was also cheaper. So, it's pretty
ridiculous here how much Fable spent and
how long it worked just to give me that
crazy output. So, Astra wins. Okay, so
moving on to the next example number 13.
What I did is I gave Fable and Astra
this doc which said, "Hey, these are
this is a new course. I want you to put
it into the free community as a draft
and I want you to use browser use in
order to do this." So, they basically
opened up school. They went to the
classroom and they put in these draft
courses, Astra AIOS and Fable AIOS and
they put in their different courses. So
they were basically instructed to have
the description, the key points, the key
quotes, and any resources. And they had
to put the video in here. And so this is
Astra's output. I told them to do just
the first five. And this looks really
good. It had to navigate the interface.
It had to basically come in here, make a
new page, it had to put in the video, it
had to put in the text. And it did it
really well and saved everything here as
a draft. Now, if we go to Fable's
output, there are no videos here. This
one arguably might have been structured
better as far as like this looks cool
and these are numbered whereas the other
one with Astra, it wasn't like numbered
as well. Like it just it's longer. But
the big big issue here is that Fable ran
into an issue and for some reason
couldn't upload the video. There was
something issue with having it download
locally and whatnot. You know, I gave
them everything it needed. I gave them
the videos. I gave it the links. This is
something that Ashstra did way better
and I will say I've done this multiple
times in my school and I've used 5.6 six
soul with browser use and just in
general codecs and the GBT models are
significantly better with browser use.
So this one I'm going to give to Astra
and honestly the cost and the time
wasn't too different here you know um
very similar and very similar Astra was
a little bit cheaper and Astra's results
were much much better so this one's
going to go to Astra as well. So we are
now at the place where the score is
Astra has nine and Fable has four. So
Fable can no longer catch up. But let's
look at the last two outputs as well.
Okay, so for number 14, we did a website
and basically what I wanted to happen is
I gave it this URL and I said, "Hey, I
want you to basically help me clone this
website. I like the structure. I like
the feel and I want you to make this for
Perkform, which is the fake, you know,
um, can company." So, this is a really
cool scroll dynamic. I know you guys,
some of you guys hate this sort of site.
That's not the point. The point is,
could Astra and Fable analyze this site
and make one that has the same feel and
the same vibe for perk? So, here is
Fable 5.1's version. And it loads up. We
have this, you know, 3D dynamic element.
Coffee reformed. We have like some, you
know, DNA looking stuff here. We keep
scrolling down. We've got these coffee
beans falling. We've got the can come
back. We've got all of this going on. I
would say that it's doing a decent job
here. It's even got the huge like zoom
out. It's doing a decent job of making
this feel like the other site. You know,
obviously there are some issues here,
but I think it's doing a decent job.
Like for oneshot prompt, although
sometimes I get into these issues with
the scroll. I mean, that's a bit of a
bug, right? when you hit the bottom of
the site, something weird goes on there.
So, there's obviously some bugs, but
it's not terrible for a oneshot. And
now, let's take a look at Astro's
version. We have the big can here, which
is a little bit dynamic. There's
something going on with this text,
right? Like the coffee is out of bounds
for some reason. Keep scrolling down. I
do like this animation. I mean, that's
pretty cool. It's a It's a coffee bean.
There's definitely layers in the back.
And by the way, this one, I didn't tell
it to use any skills. I just said, "Hey,
I want the same vibe. I want you to
analyze the, you know, the original
site, this one right here." and make me
one like this. Right. So, anyways, we're
coming through the little sort of like
DNA thing. Coffee and protein together,
two drinks in one can. I like that
animation. This one overall does feel
smoother than Fables. I do think that as
far as a first pass. I like the way this
one feels. We get stuck at the bottom
and we'd have to scroll all the way back
up to the top. Now, I do think that
Fable did a better job as of actually
just recreating what we saw in the
original site, which was the prompt.
Now, I do get stuck. There's a little
bit of a there's bugs like this. Like, I
get stuck. But as far as recreating
this, Fables felt more similar to this,
I think. So, we will give this one to
Fable. Um, it kind of needs it as well,
but I still think in general, when it
comes to design, you guys have probably
seen throughout this video, and you've
seen my other videos. In general, I do
think I like Astram more for design, but
that was like, hey, show me what you can
do. Take this URL, build me something
crazy in one shot. It was kind of a
weird prompt, right? But in this case, I
still think that Fable won. But here's a
look at the cost and the time for this
example. All right. And this is the last
one. Number 15. We have YouTube 12-month
review and strategy. So, it basically
had to look through the past year of my
YouTube stuff and give me some stats.
So, this is interesting. I mean, these
are big docs. The one on the left is
Fable. It's 25 pages. The one on the
right is Astra. It's 15 pages. So, let's
just slowly scroll through and see
what's happening here. I like how Astra
right away has, you know, this chart on
new viewers and regular viewers. Whereas
over here we have, you know, the year
and numbers. We have a monthly review.
We have total views across the past um
ooh interesting. So actually what they
show me first on the left side is from
January to now. Whereas over here I'm
getting sort of like the actual past 12
months. So those stats are going to be a
little bit different. It's showing me
content type. It's showing me the
monthly scorecard. It's showing what my
best content actually does. It's showing
me some packaging stuff. It's showing me
what to worry about. So it says news
brings the views but does not bring the
subscribers. It's saying um the news
packaging is drifting towards hype. The
audience is saying so it's saying agency
mechanics content has stopped working on
YouTube. That definitely feels to be a
bit true for this audience. Now it's
deep diving into some packaging. So it's
analyzing my my titles over here.
Whereas over here when we have the
packaging um what I would keep and
improve the evidence retention first 30
seconds who you are reaching and how. So
it's looking at the age it's looking at
the gender it's looking at the
geography. It analyzes what the comments
are asking me to do. So then at the end
they kind of like put all this stuff
together and they give me the next 90
days and they give me some things to
look at. Overall, they're very similar.
I do like the way that this was packaged
more by Astra. It just feels a little
bit easier to read and it also feels
more visual. So I'm going to give this
one to Astra as well. And you can see
here though, Astra did spend more and
take longer. So 42 minutes compared to
17 and 27 bucksish compared to 9 bucks.
So Astra wins, but it was longer or
slower and more expensive here. But
anyways guys, that was 15. That was 15
different use cases here that we scored
and looked at the cost and time. Astra
won 10 of them and Fable won five of
them. But let's take a look at the total
numbers here. I had both Astra and Fable
give me these stats to make sure they
were consistent. And you can see the
numbers are exactly the same. Fable was
9 hours 35 minutes and 45 seconds of
total run time here, costing us 513
bucks.36.
And Astro was 11 hours 19 minutes 24
seconds and cost us 326 bucks.98. So in
total Astro was $186
cheaper but took an hour and 43 minutes
longer to run across these 15 different
use cases. Now I will say this was 15
use cases. In general my experience has
been that Astra feels quicker and feels
more efficient. And also it doesn't give
us that 5 hour window in codec and it
doesn't give us that fable limit. You
know we can just use Astra the whole
week. So, I do like that we also get
more inference with Astra in general
because of the codec subscription. So,
right now, I'm heavily leaning towards
Astra for my my day-to-day and my use
cases. But the other thing I want you
guys to keep in mind is that GBT 5.6
Soul is so so good still. It's so
capable and for the majority of my
knowledge work, I could use that just
fine. And that even honestly might be
overkill for the majority of stuff that
I'm doing. So, it's not like you need to
use Astra only for all your use cases.
And it's not like you need to go grab
Fable 5.1 for all your use cases. I'm
still a very firm believer in they both
have different strengths and weaknesses.
They both have value and that's why I
love doing things like this to find out
what are the different use cases and how
do they, you know, behave in different
scenarios. And so yes, I am going to be
using codecs more right now because
that's where it currently is. But this
stuff shifts so fast and I will always
keep both subscriptions or multiple of
both subscriptions so I can keep testing
them out as things change, as my use
cases change. Who knows what might
happen. All right, so that was Codex
versus Cloud Code and it was also Astra
versus Fable and Astra and Fable are the
models there. So we talked about how the
harness cloud code or codeex is
different than the actual model inside.
So that's one thing to be aware of as
far as like the difference between
enthropic and open AAI and whatnot. The
model is different than the harness. But
besides that, I also think it's
important to understand that these tools
are all going to start to sort of merge
into the same standards. At least I
think so. Here's one really good
example. Thoric from cloud code came out
and tweeted and said hey we're adding
support for agents.mmd inside cloud code
which as we know that is what codeex
looks at for sort of like the system
prompts or the instructions and the
point I'm trying to make here is just
that is cloud code changing the harness
a little bit so now everything is being
even more tool agnostic so don't worry
stay flexible and speaking of staying
flexible I want to tell you guys about
some of the mistakes and some of the
lessons that I had learned when I was
trying to be as flexible as possible and
selling automations to tons of different
businesses tons of different clients
because if that's something that you are
motivated to do after watching this
course or maybe you're trying to start
an agency already. Then let me talk
about some of those lessons and the
mindset shift of how you approach
actually helping a business grow with AI
rather than just trying to sell them
some template or some automation that
you tried to copy off a YouTube video.
This is how you can actually provide way
more way more value to clients and that
means that you're going to get bigger
retainers and you're going to get more
referrals and you're going to get better
case studies. It's just going to help
your business in the long run. So
excited to share with you guys what I
learned here. So right now I'm at this
event in Montenegro called Workless AI
and there are a bunch of AI content
creators, AI experts and a bunch of
community members. And on the main day I
closed off the day with this
presentation which I'm about to share
with you guys. So hope you guys enjoy.
Hope you find it insightful. I'll see
you guys in there. This is called Still
Relevant Next Year. And it's actually
kind of funny because last night I kind
of switched up what I was going to talk
about a little bit because yesterday in
the VIP sections and I talked to so many
of you guys and I just kind of had a
feeling that this would resonate a bit
more because whether you are I mean I
think a lot of you guys are building
kind of like an AI consultancy and AI
agency or working with clients. Um but
even if you're not I think that this is
the way that you should be thinking
about using AI within your own business.
And um yeah so let me just although also
um I hope this picture that's
Montenegro, right? Okay. That'd be
awkward if it wasn't. I I wasn't sure.
It was Codeex. Threw it in there. So,
good to know that that's Montenegger.
Okay, cool. So, let me start with a
little story. So, I'm I'm 23 years old
at this point. I just quit my full-time
job. I just closed this deal with a
client and I deliver something and and
he messages me on Slack and he's like,
"Hey, can we get on a call?" And this is
what he says to me as soon as I hop on
the Zoom. He goes, "We are not getting
the value that we paid for." And this
really made me think because,
you know, I started to question like,
did I just make a huge mistake? Am I not
actually able to build these solutions?
Am I not going to turn this into a
business? And so I realized that the
reason that this happened was because,
well, first of all, I made this video
which went viral. It was like a personal
assistant. And so he saw that, lots of
people saw that and they wanted this.
But I made three big mistakes here. And
that's pretty much what I want to talk
about today are these three big
mistakes. So the first one is that what
I built for him, the personal assistant
was not the constraint in his business.
The second one, I guess you guys saw the
third one. The second one is that I
didn't choose a KPI.
And the third one is that I guessed on
the price. So like I said, that's what I
want to talk about today. I had a big
realization here before I started to
scale my business and I was doing
everything in the agency myself all the
way from the lead genen all the way to
the, you know, invoicing, all of that
kind of stuff. I realized that our job
is to be the ones to diagnose and prove.
You know, it's one thing to just be kind
of like you take the ticket, you develop
whatever they're asking for. You kind of
evolve from that and then you start to
be the doctor and you start to diagnose
the pain that they're feeling. But then
you're still not done yet because you
have to prove the value. Because if you
don't prove the value, then how are you
going to win more business? And I've got
another quick story to tell you guys
about in just a sec. But first, I wanted
to start off with if you guys don't know
me, a little bit about my background. My
name is Nate. graduated from the
University of Iowa in 2024 and I was
studying business analytics and
marketing. So don't come from a
technical background although I did work
with data quite a bit. So I've got a
good understanding of data which was
very helpful in automation. So can't lie
about that. Um from there I graduated
and I was working at Goldman Sachs as an
analyst and I was automating a lot of
stuff and what that helped me realize
was that automation is not new at all.
It feels new because the word AI has
been put in front of it and that's what
a lot of business owners are kind of
waking up to. And it's funny because
when I first started running my agency,
I used to joke with my friends and you
know some of my my partners when I
started when I brought on some partners
that we're not even an AI agency. We are
a data infrastructure agency and then
after that we're just a boring
automation agency. And I think that's a
really good realization to have because
that
the whole reframe of diagnosing the
problem is that people might come to you
and they want an AI agent because they
saw a YouTube video that went viral or
because they saw something on LinkedIn,
but your job is to figure out what do
they actually need? Um,
and remember how I said the thing about
you have to prove the value. I was
building a lot of automations at Goldman
and actually you know that's on the next
slide. I'll talk about that in a sec.
Um, sold my agency for so my agency once
we scaled it past $100,000 a month. It
was purely because I was way more
passionate about education. Um, but the
reason we were able to get to $100,000 a
month is because the minimum to work
with us was a $20,000 a month retainer.
And the only reason we were able to do
those retainers is because of this exact
kind of like three-step framework of
working with clients. Um, I've got a
YouTube channel. It's pretty much the
top of funnel. That's where I am doing a
lot of the education. And then my free
community called a automation society is
where we try to get people into and try
to build community. So, real quick, I
wanted to start off with like why did I
bring up the Goldman thing? What did
that teach me? Number one, like I said,
boring is beautiful. Deterministic
automations. They're easier to build.
They are easier to evaluate and they are
less risky ultimately because they're
deterministic. You know the inputs and
you know the outputs. Two is that big
companies I was you know Hostinger is
doing a lot of stuff with AI which is
which is awesome but typically when I've
worked with companies and when I was at
Goldman companies just kind of move
slower. They have a lot of change
management issues and obviously in a or
an institution like Goldman in that type
of vertical there's a lot of regulation.
And then the third thing is that you
need to spotlight your value. So quick
story here. I remember I was building a
lot of automations. Like I said, I built
a few like weekly report things. I built
a few dashboards and I was on a call
with my entire team. So probably 20 25
people. And I was showing them this
automation, you know, on a Zoom call. So
your name is right there under your
face, right? And I get off the call. It
was also my job to send out the meeting
minutes, which obviously we know AI can
do now. But I sent out the meeting
minutes and I got a response from one of
the managers that said, "Good job,
Arthur." I'm like, "Who is Arthur?" my
name is right there and I sent you the
meeting minutes. And that just made me
realize that if you're not explaining to
the business owner, to the stakeholder
what your automation actually did, then
it's hard to get credit for it. So, you
could potentially be in a situation
where you're making the business tens of
thousands of dollars, but they don't
actually know that or acknowledge that
because you didn't prove it. And it's
not bragging, it's just proving what
your systems actually did. So, those are
three big lessons that I had that I
tried to carry with me through my AI
automation agency journey.
Now think about it like this. So truly
the only way for a business to scale is
to remove constraints. And it's very
simple at a high level. Obviously
there's a lot of things that you know a
lot of nuance once you get into the
weeds of that. But that's at the end of
the day if you want a business to scale.
You have to remove constraints.
You might get a lot of people coming to
you like I did that says, "Hey, we need
an AI agent that does X, Y, and Z
because they saw a viral video because
their board is putting pressure on them
to have an AI strategy because their
competitors are posting on LinkedIn
saying, "Look at this AI agent that we
built that's doing all this for us." And
so that makes me feel like what they're
doing is they're actually just buying
relief. They're buying the ability to
say, "Yeah, we work with an AI agency.
Yeah, we have an AI strategy. We have
this agent going to production. We have
blah blah blah." But that's not really
what you're trying to provide. You're
not trying to provide relief. if you're
trying to provide real business value.
So, the whole idea is to reframe. I've
done
probably 300 or more discovery calls and
what I've realized is that they come to
you and they say something, but that's
almost never what they want. And so,
your job is to figure out why did they
book in the call because they booked in
for some reason, right? They had they're
feeling pain or they're feeling
pressure. And so, you're have you have
to figure out what is that actual pain.
You kind of have to take a step back
there. There's pain somewhere and that
is your job. You are paid to solve the
pain. And the more pain you can solve,
the more money that your business will
make.
I think this might have might have died
on me. Okay, so the reason I put this up
there is because think about if you were
to work with an agency that was going to
help you run ads. It's super super
clear. Like you know what is your budget
for ads? $10,000. And you in a direct
correlation because of you ran those
ads, you made $50,000 in sales. That
like the agency doesn't even have to
prove that to you. It's very clear, but
it's not super clear when it comes to
automation. So, you have to make it
clear.
So, those are the three things I want to
talk about, right? Constraints, KPIs
stands for key performance indicator,
and then how do you actually price this
stuff so that you can clearly show this
is how much you paid and this is how
much you're going to make your business
back.
Okay, so starting off with the
constraint,
the only way for a business to scale is
to remove constraints, to directly
attack them.
And at a very high level, your business
is either going to be supply constrained
or demand constrained. Meaning supply
constrainted, too many customers coming
in and you cannot service them. Demand
constrained, you need business. You have
no people coming in. So I really like to
think of this as a pipe.
The water coming into your pipe is
revenue. It's cash flow. And you
obviously want that pipe to be clean, no
leaks, and you want lots of water to go
through. So the top image we see is a
pipe that has a clog in the middle. And
this is probably a supply constrained
business because they're having a lot of
water come through, but the water isn't
making it all the way to the end. Maybe
it's leaking out. It's not coming out
the other end of the pipe. The bottom
one is one where there's no water in the
pipe. And right now there's no clogs.
There probably are. There there always
more clogs. But right now this this
business on the bottom is demand
constrained and they need more water
inside their pipe.
So let me tell you another quick story.
I had a med spa owner that came to me
and she wanted a lead generation AI
agent. She wanted to make more money and
I saw the stat the other day. Um,
couldn't be outdated by now given how
fast the space moves. But the stat was
basically that over 50% of all AI
automations are like lead genen or sales
or marketing automations. And I think
that makes sense because what is the
pain a lot of us are feeling is that we
want to scale our monthly recurring
revenue. And usually the first thing you
think is like oh more leads, more
clients. But in this case, the med spa
owner wanted more leads. And when I
really tried to dig into the pain there
and figure out where the constraint was,
the constraint was she ended up telling
me that they had lots of leads coming in
consistently, but what happened was they
weren't showing up to the appointments.
And then all of the people that had
showed up to an appointment, there was
no follow-up. So the LTV was extremely
low, meaning there was a decent amount
of water coming in the pipe, but it was
just leaking out before it ever made it
to the end. And so we realized together
on this call that it would be much more
valuable to the business to build
reactivation systems, to build follow-up
reminders on their appointments so that
people actually started to show up more.
And that's just a perfect example of the
reframe that you have to do in order to
really diagnose what the true pain is.
And something interesting here is I
think about a slide that says this later
too. There's just a lot of power in
silence. So when I asked her the
question of like why did you book this
call? Like what is truly the pain that
you're feeling here?
I stopped talking. She thought for a
couple seconds, responded, and then I
didn't respond yet because I I had a
feeling that that wasn't true. And when
you have that silent pause, they think
and they feel like they need to talk
more. And I'm not big into like the
sales tactics, right? Like I I don't
have the sales background, but that was
super powerful. I would pause and they
would just keep talking. And your job on
the discovery calls is to talk as much
as least as possible. Your job is to sit
there and listen. And that's how you're
able to diagnose. So that's one quick
example, right? But that happened all
the time. Now, if you guys were here
yesterday on the VIP VIP sessions and I
came around to the table, some of us dug
into this, some of us didn't, but there
are two questions that I love to ask
business owners or even your own
business, right? Like if you're trying
to help automate your own business and
remove constraints, that works super
super well, especially when you pair it
with silence. So, the first one is if a
business is
supply constraint, if you had 10x the
business tomorrow, what would break
first? You ask them that and then you
just be quiet because they'll think
about the flow in chronological order
from start to finish. And the key word
there that I put in all caps is first
because whatever breaks first is the
first clog. Now, whenever you diagnose
and you fix that first clog, there's
going to be another one. There always
is. And that's the beauty of it. And
that's how you get on a retainer because
you just keep solving constraints. You
keep scaling the business. So that's
really good. If there's supply
constraint, if they're demand
constraint, you basically just flip it.
You say, "What would you do to 10x the
business coming in tomorrow?" How do you
get 10x the amount of water into your
pipe tomorrow? So, whatever they're
already doing to get leads or maybe
they're not doing anything to get leads,
building systems to support that
initiative. And
that doesn't sometimes what you'll
realize is as an AI consultant is what
like a lot of us are calling it right
now. Your job is just as much to tell
them, hey, this is the problem that I'm
seeing and we can solve this with no AI.
So, sometimes the problem could be it's
a very service-based business. they're
supply constrained and so the key is to
just hire more people. Now, yeah, maybe
you could come in here and say, you know
what, let's build you some recruiting
agents and some screening agents. That
helps the hiring process. That removes
that constraint. But that's a really
great way to think about it as well is
that an AI consultant or someone that's
AI native, it doesn't mean that you use
AI for everything. It means that you
know just as well when not to use AI
because that perspective is even more
valuable in a world where AI is being
shoved down everyone's throats
and then you just be silent.
Okay. So, moving on to the second one
here. We've got the KPI.
So, the whole idea here is that you
before you accept any payment, you want
to choose one number that you're trying
to move and you're not choosing this
number, you're choosing it with the
stakeholder.
If you think back to that example
earlier where the business owner said to
me, "Hey, we're not getting the value we
paid for." It's because we didn't do
well, all of these things, but this one
very specifically because I had no way
to prove that a personal assistant was
helping his business. He came to me, his
pain was, I feel busy. What is the
solution in my mind? A personal
assistant. When we really dug into it,
the reason he was so busy is because he
was handwriting all his proposals. So,
the better automation there would have
been for me to help him build an AI
agent that would automate the proposals
or at least get them 90% of the way
there. He checks it, he approves it. If
we would have aligned on a number
beforehand, then I know what I'm working
towards. I know the result that I'm
trying to drive for the business.
Because productivity is really
interesting.
Productivity is actually moving the
needle. And you can't move the needle if
you don't know what you're trying to
move it towards. Because a lot of us
feel like you might have had a day where
you sat down on your at your desk all
day, eight hours straight, let's say.
But maybe you watch a lot of YouTube
tutorials. Maybe you played around with
image generation for an hour and you
felt productive because, you know, you
you clock off and you you sat there for
eight hours, but how many of those hours
were you actually doing what you need to
do to move that number forward? And for
us, you know, a lot of us, you know,
it's a business, so there's a lot of
different north stars, but knowing what
you're building towards that quarter or
that day or whatever it is helps you
actually be a lot more productive. And
if your agents know your goals, then
they can help you plan your days better
to be more productive. So, something
that I would like to ask is, okay, let's
say we've scoped it down. We've we
understand the constraint, and I forget
the example I use. Um,
anyways, let's say we we've scoped it
down to a certain automation. Then I
could ask in a perfect world, what does
this look like for your business?
If we push this into production and it's
working perfectly, what do you want to
see? And from there, you try to drill
into one certain metric. So maybe it is
an AI agent that sets appointments.
Maybe they say, "Okay, yeah, I mean,
right now we're getting like five
appointments a week from our manual
setters." In a perfect world, our manual
setters have those 10 hours a week back
to do other things, and we're booking in
like 10 appointments a week. And so now
I know exactly what is a success to
them. So there's that's completely
objective. I can go work towards that
and I can prove that. So if someone says
to me, "Hey, we're not getting the value
we paid for. Look at the scope. This is
what we agreed on. This you said that
you wanted 10 appointments a week from
this automation and I objectively
delivered that to you." I probably would
say a little bit nicer though. Okay. So
that's a trackable and objective metric
because a lot of this stuff is very
subjective. I want a personal AI
assistant so I can feel more productive,
so I feel less busy. There's no way that
I can actually prove that. There's no
way I can prove to the business owner
that he is now less busy because of what
I built. So, they can't be subjective.
So, like I said, you have a baseline
like five weekly appointments. You've
got a target like 12 weekly
appointments. And now you know what
you're working towards. Of course,
you're going to have to leverage some of
their expertise because if you know not
much about the process and you try to
set a baseline target of like, you know,
35 appointments a week, that's very
tough. And now you're not going to be
able to prove that.
But the idea is that each automation is
having something to work towards. And
like I said, if this is not you working
with a client, before you go out and
decide to dedicate some some of your own
internal resources or budget to a
project, you should probably figure out
what is that one metric you want to
move. A lot of times there are, you
know, it it drips into other metrics
too, but if you can choose one, it makes
the decision a lot easier. And then you
can figure out how is that actually
impacting the bottom line of the
business.
And that's how you prove, like I said,
that your automation helped.
Okay, the third piece now is on the
pricing side. Now, this is really
interesting.
I really don't think there's like a
standard universal right way to price.
Everyone's doing it a bit differently.
Even the big firms are changing up their
pricing. I've tried almost everything
that you could think of. I've tried
performance-based. I've tried hourly.
I've tried retainers on hourly. I've
tried value based. I've tried just lots
of stuff.
Um, the way I feel is that you should
not be charging hourly. I think that a
lot of people when they're getting
started, I hear, you know, I keep
getting nos to my price. I hear that
there's imposter syndrome. And so, I
think hourly to start is a really good
way to get your foot in the door and win
some trust or even start free. I think
it's a really good way to start, but I
don't think you should be building a
business around your hourly pricing. And
it's it's really simple. And especially
if you start to think about the way that
AI is supposed to make us do more in
less time. So, it's all about the
incentives. All right, real quick, guys.
I mentioned this at the end of the
presentation, but I attach this
completely free PDF, which is like a
30-page resource on pricing your AI
solutions, which you can access for
completely free inside of my free school
community. The link for that is down in
the description. You just hop in there,
you'll click on all YouTube resources,
and you'll find that pricing masterclass
guide in there. So, if you want it, it's
there. Let's get back to the video.
Let's say you've got two developers on
your team and you're providing services
to businesses. You've got one developer
named Sarah and she's a killer. She gets
something done in 1 hour. And you've got
another developer named Dan. He's good,
but he's a little slower, three hours.
And let's say for the sake of the
example, they produce the exact same
quality of solution. You would then bill
for Sarah's work, your better developer,
you would bill $150 to the client or I
don't know, however you want to, you get
the point, right? $150. And now Dan,
because he took three hours, you get
more money. And those incentives are
completely backwards. Why would you make
more money for moving slower and on a
worse developer? Right? It's all about
incentives. It's all about value based
pricing. That this is where we got to
and this is what I believe at the moment
is the best way to be doing this. And
what that means is yes,
the same automation could be different
amounts of valuable to different
businesses.
So you have to kind of take that into
account at least when you're going very
custom and you're consulting.
This is the way we did it, right? Oops.
A client should understand how they will
receive 10x their investment. That's
kind of the golden rule that I like to
to give, right? Because if you can walk
the stakeholder through the math,
whether that is a business you're trying
to help or whether that's you internally
trying to win a budget because you're
trying to, you know, build AI projects
inhouse,
you need to prove that this investment
of their money will get them a 10x on it
because that makes it a really hard
offer to say no to. So the way that we
would do this is basically take 10% of
the projected annualized value of the
price of the the automation and that's a
gear price. So an example here, let's
say you're building a customer support
agent and the manual rep, the human rep
spends about 10 hours a week responding
to these tickets and this person is paid
40 bucks an hour. So the cost of the
business 40 bucks an hour for customer
support. 40 bucks an hour and the rep is
does this about 10 hours a week. That's
400 bucks a week. And if you annualize
that, that's about $2,100 over the
course of the year, the first year
projected annualized revenue.
And you take 10% of that. Now, 10% 20%,
I play with it a little bit, but let's
just say 10% for the sake of example,
that's $2,80
here. Because what you have to assume,
they don't always,
but you have to assume that they're
going to ask you,
can you please tell me how you got to
that number? Because a lot of people
will come in and they're kind of like
maybe they're shopping around. They're
trying to get a quote. They don't even
know how much to allocate a budget
towards. So if you assume that they're
going to ask you, "How did you get to
that number?" And you can confidently
walk them through the math and then you
just be silent and you don't devalue
your work. I'm kind of jumping ahead. I
know I got some slides here that cover
this, but anyways, you have to figure
out what does the manual process cost
the business. And so in this example,
right, I I was able to understand, okay,
this rep cost the business 40 bucks an
hour. They're not always going to tell
you salary. They're not always going to
tell you the hourly weight rate, but
there's other ways to figure out what
does the manual process cost the
business. It could be opportunity cost.
Maybe they've been having a different
funnel or trip wire that they've wanted
to push out for two quarters, but they
haven't because they are too busy,
right? There's there's other types of
cost besides just like the hourly cost.
Maybe you're building a voice
appointment, uh, a voice agent because
the business misses calls all the time
and every missed call could potentially
be um, a driveway, right? A driveway and
that driveway could win the business
$10,000. So, there's other ways to
figure out what is the cost of the
manual process. You just have to ask
good questions and then be silent and
listen,
like I said.
So, the key thing to remember here is
that cost doesn't justify price.
value justifies price. And
this was kind of tough for me to wrap my
head around at first because the first
thing I thought of as a very new
business owner was I need to protect my
margins here. I need to make sure that
I'm making this much money or this
percent of the deal and I'm keeping that
much to account for taxes to account
for, you know, what I have to pay my
employees to account for our API cost or
our service, whatever it is. I was
thinking about the margins, but I think
that obviously you still have to think
about the margins so you're not running
your business into the ground, but the
cost doesn't justify the price. And a
really good example that I heard from
Jonathan Stark who spoke at our event a
couple weeks ago, he was saying like
let's say you're paying someone to do
your lawn and you pay them a hundred
bucks for the lawn and he's been come,
you know, he's been coming to you for
for years. All of a sudden he buys a new
pickup truck and that's an expense to
his business. So he has higher costs on
his end and then he comes to you and
wants to charge you 200 for the exact
same job for the exact same lawn. That's
not something that people will typically
agree to because the cost doesn't
justify the price. The value justifies
the price.
So, like I said, you have to pretend and
you have to assume that as soon as you
say the price, they're going to come
back to you and ask, "How did you get
that number?" And then you just have to
walk them through the math. Now, what's
really important there is you don't want
to devalue your work. So, let's say
someone comes to you, you scope out the
right constraint, you figure out the
cost of the business, and you give them
a 10% number. Let's say it just comes
out to 15,000. And they were basically
planning 7,000 to be the maximum they
were going to spend on AI this quarter.
You don't want to get into this
negotiation of devaluing your work and
saying, "Ah, you know, this would be
15K, but for you, we'll do it for 7K."
You know, if you're really trying to get
your first client and you can get that,
then I would say do it reps over cash
upfront when you're getting started. But
you don't want to devalue your work.
What I would do in this situation is I
would say, "Okay,
this build, this solution is $15,000
worth of value to the business and you
have a $7,000 budget. Let's just drill
down the functionality a little bit and
treat this as a V1. we'll give you the
$7,000 worth of this automation and then
you know next quarter when you've got
the budget or once this automation's in
production and we're actively earning
you back time and money then we'll look
at the next one because I think if you
if you set the impression right away
that you're willing to bump down your
price as soon as they push back then
they're just going to keep doing that
and you don't want to devalue your work.
So that's pretty much what I wanted to
run through today. Um, obviously those
kind of three main things, there's a lot
more nuance to get into, which if you
guys want to chat more, I'd love to to
chat more.
>> But think about this with your own
business. Um, actually, let's just take
let's just take one volunteer real
quick. Someone that Yeah. Um, is it
Allejo?
>> There we go. Tell us
in your business, you know what you're
driving towards, right?
>> Yeah.
>> At the highest level, are you supply
constrainted or demand constrained?
>> Demand constraint. need more clients.
>> You need more clients. And how are you
currently getting those clients?
>> Uh content on YouTube. Uh it's not quite
converting. I'm doing webinars and out
of 20 people that have assisted webinars
over two months,
>> uh we've gotten zero appointments set.
>> Okay. So,
if you wanted to have 10x the amount of
business tomorrow, what would you have
to do?
>> Uh probably 10x the content.
>> Mhm. 10x the content. uh seems crazy but
the methods that I see today would be
very helpful.
>> Yeah, volume negates luck, right? But
you want to 10x the content without
decreasing the the quality of course. So
in this case,
obviously there's a lot more to dive
into here, but you know the way that
you're kind of you know your top of
funnel. What does it seem like you
should be focusing on automating when
you get home in a couple days or next
week?
Um the problems that I have heard on
sales calls uh turning those into a
video.
>> Okay.
>> Uh that one is huge is I like forget
what we talked about
>> and maybe focus on something in a sales
call but I'm going to miss something
else that they said that is an actual
problem.
>> Totally. And do you know how you could
automate that?
>> Now I do.
>> There we go. Um now something I saw I
remember talking to you about was the
grill me skill, right? Yeah,
>> if you guys don't know the grill me
skill, I mean, it's a very simple
prompt. Essentially, just at the end of
of questions, ask the AI to interview
you relentlessly about this topic
because what that does is it gets all of
the subject matter expertise in your
head into the AIOS that you're building
because once you give it all of that
nuance, it's able to build an automation
out of that so much better because the
way that you would kind of create these
AI agents to to uh, you know,
operationalize that process is different
than someone else might. So obviously
that was a really quick example. Thank
you Allejo. I appreciate the theuh
participation there. But just constantly
be asking yourself like what is the
actual constraint? You know how do we
10x the business? How do we actually
look through the flow of the pipe and
the water and figure out where the clog
is or where the leak is and then just
directly attack that? And so like I said
earlier
when we were working with businesses we
would always start with our foot in the
door with one project on a value based
uh project fee. And from there, we
started to explain to them,
we are seeing all of these other clogs
because once we've removed this
constraint, there's another one. And
that's a good thing because still you're
getting more water through. And that's
how you're able to get on the retainer
because not only did you
find the right constraint, you also
chose a number beforehand so you can
objectively prove to them the automation
helped their business. And then you
price it in a way where it was a
no-brainer for them to say yes. And then
guess what? after you push it into
production, you come back 1 month, 2
months, 3 months later and you show them
that number and now you're able to
justify asking for that retainer and to
just say, "Hey, you know, we can move a
lot quicker if we're not always doing
the scoping and we're not always
figuring out pricing, if we can just
work more and just keep attacking those
constraints." And that's the only way
that the business is truly going to
grow. So, that's pretty much what I want
to talk to you guys about today. I have
a full pricing guide. This is like a 29
30 page doc. Um, kind of just like about
what I talked about today on the
valuebased pricing and some stuff like
that. Um, so go ahead and scan that and
grab that doc. I'm sure we can include
it in the the resources later as well if
you miss it. But yeah, thank you guys so
much. It's been an awesome day and yeah,
let's let's have some dinner.
So, I hope you guys enjoyed the speech
that I gave as well as that free pricing
guide resource. I also wanted to say
that I have a second channel right here
where you can see this was actually the
workless event that I just showed you
guys that speech from. And I have the
second YouTube channel where I kind of
show some more behind the scenes stuff
when I go to AI events or when I do
other cool things in the space and just
showing you like the other side. So I
will link this YouTube channel down in
the description if you want to check it
out. But now before we wrap up this
whole course, let me dive into even more
about how you actually think about
pricing these solutions with valuebased
pricing. So let's hop into the last
video of the course. All right, so I've
sold over a 100 AI automation systems
and I've priced a ton of those wrong.
I've undercharged, I've underscoped, and
I've just thrown out random numbers that
were kind of a guess and I couldn't
explain when someone actually asked me
like, "Hey, where'd you get that number
from?" So, in this video, I'm going to
talk about everything that I know about
pricing AI solutions. I'm going to walk
you through one real build that I sold,
every single number, and by the end of
this video, you'll be able to take any
project, turn the client's own numbers
into a price that you can actually
defend, and then get paid in stages, so
you're never carrying much more than,
you know, 30 days of unpaid work. And if
you don't know who I am, my name is
Nate. I've been teaching hundreds of
thousands of people how to build AI
agents and how to implement them into
businesses as well. And I scaled my
agency to over $100,000 a month, and
then I sold it. With our business, we
got to the point where the minimum to
work with us was a $20,000 a month
retainer. And I'm assuming that sort of
engagement is where a lot of you guys
want to end up getting to. So, let's not
waste any time and let's just jump
straight into today's video. Okay. So,
this example was an appointment setting
agent. The business had employees
manually setting these meetings and this
was about 20 leads a week, each one
taking roughly an hour of a human's
time. And those employees were costing
the business about 40 bucks an hour all
in. So 20 hours a week at $40 an hour is
about $800 bucks a week. And if you
multiply that by 52, which is 52 weeks
in the year, that's $41,600
annualized. And before I said anything
to the client about price, I walked them
through the entire solution. You know,
how the agent would work, what testing
looked like, how it would change their
speed to lead, and their lead quality.
But I also had to ask them a ton of
questions through what we call the
discovery phase. Because some clients
want to talk about price right away, but
the honest answer to them is, you know,
in order for me to give you an accurate
ballpark estimate of what this is going
to cost, I really need to understand
more in depth the complexity of the
system and how it will actually look
once it's fully integrated into your
actual business processes. Then I priced
the build right around 13% of what that
annual number was, which came out to
5,500 bucks. So, the business would
basically be paying $5,500 for a system
that over the course of the year was
going to give them back $41,600,
which comes out to about a 7.5 multiple
on their initial investment. Now,
typically, I like to say the golden rule
is that you need to be able to show the
client that their investment is going to
10x over the course of the year because
that math makes it really hard to say no
to. So, in this specific example, where
I accounted for that extra 2.5x that we
were missing that would put us at 10 was
the baseline. So right now the baseline
was about 20 leads a week. But as the
business earned more time back because
of the system and this whole process
gets more streamlined that baseline of
leads per week would probably start to
increase right it would go to 21 and
then 23 and then 27 and that's where we
are earning them even more money back.
Now obviously something like that is a
projection and you can't just go in
there and say that you can guarantee
that. So be careful about making any
guarantees or trying to tie revenue to
those specific results or anything like
that. But the general idea is that as
the system gets used more, the business
will grow, which in turn utilizes the
system even more. So you create this
really cool like flywheel. And then on
top of the build, we set up a standard
maintenance plan. So this was 400 bucks
a month. And I want to be clear what
that actually is because a lot of people
kind of misinterpret this word
maintenance. So that $400 a month isn't
for me to bolt on new features every
month. It's just me guaranteeing that
the build keeps doing what we agreed
that it would do. Meaning, if something
breaks or an API changes or, you know,
maybe a new model releases or some weird
edge cases show up that need a little
tweak in order to keep the system living
up to the functionality of the scope,
that would be on me and that's covered
by the client's retainer fee. But new
functionality is a completely separate
conversation. So, with maintenance
retainers, I always keep the number
super simple and standard across all
projects. And at this point in my
career, our maintenance package was 400
bucks a month. You just do want to be
careful though because if you're
delivering a system that's, you know,
let's say $30,000. If maintenance on
that solution is going to cost you and
your team more than 400 bucks a month,
meaning you would be like losing money
on giving away that package, then
obviously you can't charge that. But I
think that with well-designed
automations and well-built automations,
it really shouldn't be too timeconuming
for you to maintain them. because once
again there's a big difference between
maintaining and adding minor feature
enhancements and adding you know more
functionality. Now a big mistake that I
made in this specific project was that
once I was in production what I should
have done was gone back and measured how
valuable this thing truly was and I
didn't do that. So I had no after state.
I had no transformation number and what
ended up happening is that cost me on
the next conversation when I tried to
win more business. So make sure you're
capturing the baseline up front which in
this case was you know like 20 leads a
week and the speed to lead time because
that was taking the humans you know time
and then you follow up after a month
after 2 months and after 3 months and
you prove to them that those numbers are
moving in the direction that the
business wants because of your system.
And I know that this might kind of feel
like bragging, but it's not. You know,
because if you don't put a spotlight on
those numbers, even if your automations
really really are helping the business,
the business owner might not actually
feel that and won't acknowledge that.
So, it's really important that you're
the one surfacing that stuff. Okay, so
the obvious question is why not just
bill hourly and be done with it? And I
want to give a quick shout out here. A
pricing guy named Jonathan Stark came
and spoke at AIS Live and he made some
really amazing points on this topic. So,
I'm going to talk about some of the
things that he brought up, but really
the problem with hourly is that it pays
you more to be slow. I mean, picture two
people on your team. You're billing them
the same 150 bucks an hour. Your best
developer and your slowest one. Some new
feature comes in and your best guy
knocks that out in a day. So, you bill
one day, but your slow guy takes 3 days.
So, you bill 3 days. You just made three
times the money off of a worse, slower
employee. And if your best guy gets
faster, then you're going to make less
money off of him. So getting good at the
job actually cut your income. It's all
about incentives. Would you want to hire
someone who was incentivized to work
slower in order to get more money out of
you? Probably not. I wouldn't want to.
But now think about that in, you know,
2026. You get really good with cloud
code or whatever tool you're using and
you can do something in an afternoon
that used to take you a week. And if
your hourly pricing, then that afternoon
because you moved so fast just slashed
your income. So, I'm not saying hourly
is never okay. I think for your first
two or three projects when you've got,
you know, nothing to point at, not a
bunch of proof, then billing hourly is a
safer ask. It's a it's a easier ask for
the business owner and it's a good place
to start. Maybe just like a hundred
bucks an hour. But after that, quit
billing hourly. By the way guys, if you
want to access this completely free
resource, which is like a 27page doc on
pricing your AI services, then you can
grab that, like I said, for completely
free by joining my free school
community. The link for that is down in
the description. All you have to do is
jump in here, click on classroom, go to
all YouTube resources, and then find the
resource in there. I promise you guys,
it's in there. But let's get back to the
video. So, if you're not pricing off
hours, then what are you pricing off of?
Well, there's three things to keep
straight. So, those three words are
cost, value, and price. So your cost is
the floor, the number that you'd walk
away if you know it was below that.
Their value is the ceiling, the most
that this whole thing is even worth to
them in the business. And the price is
any number between the two of those that
you guys can land on. Now on an AI
build, that gap is pretty enormous
because whatever it costs you to build
the thing and harden it, their ceiling
is a higher they now don't need to make.
And just remember this, cost doesn't
justify price. Price justifies cost. And
Jonathan made a really great example of
a landscaper here. So let's imagine a
landscaper mows your lawn every single
week for a h 100red bucks. Then one week
he shows up. He does the same job he's
always done on the same exact lawn he's
always mowed. And now he tells you it's
200 bucks because he bought a fancy new
truck and his costs went up. That's not
how it works. Nobody accepts that. Cost
doesn't justify price. Price justifies
cost. Okay. So the client ceiling is the
number you're actually pricing off. and
you get one conversation to find it. So,
as you're getting to know the business
and getting to know about the
automations that they need, you're
trying to uncover scope just as much as
you're trying to uncover the value to
the business. So, you open by letting
them dump everything. You know, tell me
everything you know about this, what
you've tried in the past, what's worked,
where it keeps getting stuck. And your
job is to just listen, repeat, and poke.
And just run that LRP framework to get
as much information as you can. Take a
ton of notes, and then you pivot. Ask
them about what happens after we're done
with this project. You know, what is the
best case scenario? And what actually
changes for the business once this thing
is successfully up and running? And then
you run three buckets of questions. Why
this? Why now? And why me? So why this
is checking that what they asked for
actually gets them the outcome that they
want. Because a lot of the time it
doesn't. And because they, you know,
walked in asking for an AI agent, but
the real fix might be a really simple
deterministic script and a Slack
notification. Then you ask why now? And
this is about urgency because if a
window is closing or if a competitor is
breathing down their neck, then that's
real money to you. And then why me is
the kind of uncomfortable one, but you
literally ask them, you know, why
wouldn't you just do this internally?
Couldn't you vibe code this? Couldn't
you hand it to an intern? And the reason
you want to do this is because these
questions or that question specifically
surfaces objections that are already in
their head. So, either you can hear it
now while you're on the call with them
and you can answer those objections and
handle them or it's going to kill the
deal later down the line when they're
reading your proposal or talking with
their team. And when they give you a
real answer like, "Yeah, you know, my
nephew probably could build this." You
don't argue. You go, "Yeah, he probably
could get a version of this up and
running." But what I'd want to know is
who's going to watch it at 2 in the
morning when the model updates and you
know, who's going to help you scale this
when you have way more throughput than
you're expecting and when it gets a bit
more complex? And then what you do is
you stop and you just let them answer
because their answer is the actual
reason that they're looking to hire
someone. And if you find that you're in
a situation where they just keep pushing
you for a number, if they keep pushing
for a price before you can ask these
questions and before you can really dive
in, don't blurt one out. And honestly,
if they keep pushing you for a price and
all they want is to get a quote out of
you so they can compare you across a few
different other vendors, then I would
say that's probably a red flag and you
just want to get out of that engagement.
Because the hard truth is some people
are just looking for the cheapest labor.
they're not really looking for a
consultant or partner and that's how you
want to position yourself and there's
unfortunately not much you can do to
change that person's mind besides
telling them hey you know what I bring
to the table is different I bring a
different level of expertise and you
know that's where you really want to
leverage your proof but ultimately some
people know that they could go to Upwork
and get much cheaper labor and that's
just what they're going to do so don't
take it personally okay so the obvious
problem with a lot of this is that a lot
of clients won't just hand you the
numbers like they don't want to tell you
salaries and exact bottom line numbers
and things like that and and they don't
have to. So, start with three questions.
How long does this take you today? How
many people touch it? And what happens
when it goes wrong? These are all sizing
questions. They measure the ceiling, not
the build. Then you keep stacking proxy
questions on top, like you, oh, how many
locations do you have or how many of
these come in on your busiest days? That
kind of stuff. And I know some of you
are on a job marketplace where you have
to put a number in your proposal before
you even get a chance to talk to that
person. And you can still kind of do a
version of this. The job post almost
always tells you things like volume or
headcount or you can figure out some
complexity there, how often the thing
happens. You size it off that and say
your assumption out loud. Something
like, you know, I've priced this
assuming that there's about 200 of these
a month. And you know, if that's off,
let's hop on a 15-minute call and I can
adjust the price and we can rework the
scope a little bit. But that basically
just turns the cold price into a reason
for them to hop on a call and talk to
you. And here's a quick check. If you
can't land on a number, if you feel like
you don't understand the value enough to
accurately give a number, then that's
probably a signal that you're not ready
to write that proposal yet. You need
more information. Okay, so now you've
got that value number from that total
annualized value number, first year
annualized. What I like to do is pick
somewhere between 10% and 20% of that
number as my starting point. So you say
your price, you assume the next sentence
out of their mouth is, can you walk me
through how you got to that price? And
you basically have to answer that
confidently. You have to say, "Okay,
yeah, this is a customer support
automation. It takes a rep an hour a day
manually, and an hour of that rep's time
is about 50 bucks, right? Like that's
how much it's costing the business over
a year. That equals about $12,000 to the
business. So 10% of that $12,000 is
$1,200. So the build is $1,200 bucks. So
conservatively, you will be 10xing your
investment of that $1,200 just in the
first year." And when you go to write
this up, don't just send one price. What
I've always done is tiered packages. So
you can have like a starter, a growth,
and a scale or how whatever you want to
call them. And before you get anywhere
near the options, the top of that
proposal is three short paragraphs. And
none of them are about you or your
pricing. They're about where the
business is right now in their words
with their numbers in it, where they
said they wanted to be and why you're
the person that can help them get to
where they want to be because of your AI
expertise and your systems. So you would
then take the first year value. Let's
for now just call it 100 grand to keep
numbers even. You could say option one
is 10% so $10,000. Option two is 25% so
25,000. And option three is 50% 50
grand. And I'm just kind of throwing out
rough numbers here. But obviously as you
move up those tiers you have to have
different sort of, you know, value. It
still has to make sense. You have to
have more functionality or you have to
have different types of results tied to
it, right? But the middle one is kind of
the one that's designed to win because
the bottom one looks thin, the top one
maybe makes them wse a little bit and
the middle one looks more correct. And
what this does psychologically is really
interesting because if you give them one
number, their decision is hm should we
work with this person? But if you give
them three numbers, their decision is
more around how should we work with this
person? You know, like which one of
these deals should we take? Okay, so one
of the most profitable automations that
I've ever seen was one of the simplest
because all it did was it took a
construction crew's daily phone orders
and converted them into the text format
that the crew already used. That was it.
It was super simple. It only saved like
45 minutes a day, but it helped them
avoid around $12,000 a month in
scheduling errors. And that second
number isn't freed up hours like the
earlier example was with the appointment
setter. It's hard dollars that they were
losing every single month because of
errors, because of the inconsistency of
humans. which is why the saving 45
minutes a day was worth so much more
here. And the reason I'm telling you
guys this is because typically a good
place to start is by thinking about the
hours you're saving. But as you get a
little more comfortable and you have a
little bit more experience behind you,
you start to think about the bottom line
impact of the entire business. If you
think back to the earlier example about
the appointment setting agent, we
basically only attributed the value to
the time we were saving to the time we
were buying back the business. But what
if we would have thought about how much
does a converted appointment actually
make the business? So, all of these um
appointments that we're helping set with
our system, what if each of those closed
sales was worth $5,000? We could have
valued that system way higher. And if we
would have communicated it that way, we
probably could have charged way more for
that automation. So, like I said, as you
get more experience, start to think more
about that. But once again, it's your
job to communicate that value because
the business owner isn't just going to
see that like that immediately. Okay.
Now, I want to talk about underscoping.
This is the number one mistake that I
made when I first got started. And then
what this caused was, you know,
timelines to get pushed and arguing
about milestones, right? So, here's how
I structure this kind of stuff so that
that never happens. Now, this video
specifically isn't about scoping. That's
a different topic entirely, but this is
kind of more about setting up the
milestones in the correct way. So, what
I would do, let's say we have a $9,000
project and we want to split this up
into major milestones. So, let's say we
have one milestone at the halfway point
and one milestone, you know, once this
thing has been pushed into production.
And I like to think about those as far
as like what do we think we could
deliver in 30 days. So each milestone is
30 days apart and that's where you're
going to get paid is essentially every
30 days. Then what you do is you could
split this into three payments if we
have two major milestones. One to get
started, the second one after the first
milestone has been hit and the final one
after the final milestone has been hit.
But this only works if each milestone
itself cannot be argued with. It has to
be so objective. It can't be subjective,
right? Like there can be no ambiguity
there, which we've run into a lot. So,
you know, here's what an objective one
could sound like. At this milestone,
there is an AI system in the business
owner's hands, a PC, a proof of concept
that they can actually talk to. And when
the owner sends it a question, the agent
pulls from the database and responds
within a minute. All of that stuff is
provable and it's very simple to write
down and the client could go prove it
itself. It's not claiming that the
database is perfectly optimized yet.
It's not even saying that all the
answers are perfect or correct. It's
just saying that it works and it pulls
there and it responds and that's
objective. Now, a subjective milestone
maybe could be something that's
obviously easy to argue like, "Oh, the
inbox agent is working as expected."
Okay, what's expected? You and the
client could potentially go back and
forth on that for weeks and you're not
going to get paid and it's just going to
get frustrating. And then what else
could happen is they start to ask for
things that weren't on the original list
because it's so ambiguous and they might
say, you know, can you add this? Can you
add this? That's not, you know, this is
a milestone. I need this functionality.
And so what you want to do there is if
they do start to try to scope creep,
this is actually a great sign because it
means that they're excited and it means
that they're already starting to imagine
working with you more. So the way that I
handle this, I don't say, "Oh, no."
Right? Like I say, yeah, it's a great
idea and I could definitely see how this
would add value to the system. Let's go
ahead and throw this on the backlog for
our version two of the project. And as
you get more ideas, you can just add
more stuff to the backlog because I just
want to make sure that we're hitting the
milestones that we've already set as
quick as possible for you guys so that
we can deliver as much value to the
business as possible. Okay. Now, let's
talk about what you do if they see the
numbers that you've presented your price
and they don't like them and they're
saying, "Oh, you know, this is way more
expensive than I thought it was going to
be. I didn't really have a good gauge.
This is not in our budget." So, what you
want to do is say something like, "Okay,
it sounds like 20 grand isn't in the
budget right now. Why don't we just like
reduce the scope a little bit and start
with a smaller project? And once this is
working and winning you guys back some
time and some more business, then we can
move on to the next piece together cuz
we've kind of already got it scoped out.
And that's how you can avoid teaching
them that your prices move down every
time that they frown and you're also not
devaluing the work that you would be
doing. You're just reducing the scope
and that keeps it pretty fair. And the
last thing that I wanted to address here
was the other costs that typically go
along with these systems which are API
costs or cloud subscriptions and you
know token usage things like that. Now I
have always said client's account
client's card every single time your fee
is for design consulting building
testing. Now the tokens are a utility
bill and utility bills go in the
client's name. I used to start off by
running everything under my own billing
and invoicing them each month and it
just got super messy. I was babysitting
the billing. I had to follow up with
clients. Obviously, I built agents to do
that, but still, it wasn't fun. And it
also left them with no idea what they
were paying for and potentially
misaligned, you know, some trust. And
what else you should do is probably give
them an expected monthly run cost in the
proposal with the volume assumption next
to it. Now, obviously, not a guarantee,
but an estimate of how much this thing
will typically cost per month when it's
fully in production and how ideally the
system starts to get used more and more
over time, like month over month. So the
costs are probably going to scale up a
little bit month over month as well.
Now, one thing that you do want to think
about in your pricing is that there are
typically a decent amount of testing
costs that go into the system. At least
if you're doing it right, you're
spending a lot of money testing before
you push anything into production for a
client. And these testing costs could
genuinely be anywhere from a hundred
bucks to a few thousand based on how
rigorous your evals and your QA process
is, which I think should be pretty
pretty rigorous. So, I would usually
just factor that in to our final price
by just bumping it up by like a,000 or 2
or $3,000 depending on the size of the
automation and how much testing you
think is going to go into it. Obviously,
the more AI that's in there, the more
autonomy, the more testing you're going
to have to do. And the whole thing, the
way I feel about pricing right now is
that even the biggest firms, McKenzie,
Salesforce, everyone's trying to figure
out this AI pricing thing, and no one
has the right golden answer. And I think
that a lot of people might disagree with
some of the things I'm saying here, and
that's okay. But I didn't feel like it
was a great feeling to say, "Hey, you
know, Mr. or Mrs. client, can you please
go ahead and give us this API key and
this one and this one and this one." And
then before we're even giving them any
sort of P or showing them any value,
we're already spending a few hundred of
their dollars just testing the system. I
just don't think that's a very good way
to kick off a partnership. So basically
what I meant by that is in the testing
we paid for everything and then when we
moved everything into production we
swapped out their API keys for you know
compute and whatever else it was that
was costing us. Okay. So if you take one
single thing out of this into your next
discovery or sales call, make it this
one. Before you say any number at all,
get the client to tell you what the
problem is costing them in their own
words. Just have them say it out loud.
And then once that number is on the
table in their language, your price is
just a fraction of a number that they
have already stated. So what you're
selling is the result and the build is
just how it gets delivered. Last thing I
wanted to call out for you all is that I
have a road map, the exact playbook that
I followed to get to $100,000 a month
and exit my agency when I started as a
solo founder. So if you do want to take
that path and sort of like run your own
oneperson agency to start and then look
at scaling up, there's a free road map
down in the description if you want to
check that out. But anyways guys, that
is going to do it for this one. I hope
you enjoyed the video. video. I hope you
learned something new and if you did,
please give it a like. It helps me out a
ton. And as always, I appreciate you
guys making it to the end of the video
and I'll see you on the next one.